<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- generator="bbPress/1.0.2" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Humanities Questions &#38; Answers &#187; Forum: New Media &#38; Games - Recent Topics</title>
		<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/forum/media-games</link>
		<description>Digital Humanities Questions &amp; Answers &#187; Forum: New Media &amp; Games - Recent Topics</description>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2016 03:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<generator>http://bbpress.org/?v=1.0.2</generator>
		<textInput>
			<title><![CDATA[Search]]></title>
			<description><![CDATA[Search all topics from these forums.]]></description>
			<name>q</name>
			<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/search.php</link>
		</textInput>
		<atom:link href="/rss/forum/media-games/topics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
			 
				<title>m.brown4 on "Anyone know any Interdisciplinary STEM/Humanities academic competitions in HE?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/anyone-know-any-interdisciplinary-stemhumanities-academic-competitions-in-he#post-2106</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2013 07:45:40 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>m.brown4</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2106@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I am a mature, Natural Sciences undergraduate student, studying at the University of East Anglia, Norwich, England.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I am writing an article entitled:&#60;br /&#62;
Academic Competitions in Higher Education – Opening a gateway for student initiative, creativity and interdisciplinarity.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;More specifically:&#60;br /&#62;
How academic competitions in HE (International, National or Localised) can allow UNDERGRADUATE students to:&#60;br /&#62;
 - Operate academic skills in a more creative and initiative-based way.&#60;br /&#62;
 - Facilitate the real application of learned material.&#60;br /&#62;
 - Facilitate the application of knowledge to real-world challenges outside of academia. (e.g Engineering competitions, such as the ones listed below).&#60;br /&#62;
 - Facilitate cooperation between academic disciplines.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;For the article I am trying to find as many varied examples as I can, ranging from purely STEM based competitions,( &#60;a href=&#34;http://innovation.wisc.edu/sustainability/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://innovation.wisc.edu/sustainability/&#60;/a&#62; )&#60;br /&#62;
Interdisciplinary examples ( &#60;a href=&#34;http://igem.org/About&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://igem.org/About&#60;/a&#62; ) and Humanities examples ( &#60;a href=&#34;http://openhumanitiesawards.org/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://openhumanitiesawards.org/&#60;/a&#62; ).&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I am also interested in any other forms of extra curricular activities which facilitate undergraduate student initiative, creativity and interdisciplinarity. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Any help, or a point in the direction of someone who might be able to, would be much appreciated. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;All the best&#60;br /&#62;
Michael Brown&#60;br /&#62;
University of East Anglia&#60;br /&#62;
Student Initiative Society UEA &#60;a href=&#34;http://mbrown6.wix.com/sisuea&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://mbrown6.wix.com/sisuea&#60;/a&#62;
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>alangpike on "Big data projects using IMDB?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/big-data-projects-using-imdb#post-2019</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2013 08:42:29 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>alangpike</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2019@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I am in the early stages of my dissertation and, as I explore the possible DH methods that might apply to my work, am wondering if there might be a way for the DH community to take advantage of the mountain of data at IMDB. I have heard from some folks that they have been unfriendly to researchers, but thought it might be worth some serious effort to make some (all!) of their data, reviews, etc. available to film and media studies scholars. The possibilities for DH methods are virtually limitless. For my own work, data visualizations, social network analysis of cast and crew, etc. are all intriguing possibilities. Has anyone out there gotten permission from IMDB to use data crawlers for scholarly research? Has anyone tried to do so and been denied?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Stéfan Sinclair on "Hacking with Micro LCDs"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/hacking-with-micro-lcds#post-790</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2010 10:47:47 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Stéfan Sinclair</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">790@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I saw a very cool art piece that had a micro LCD display (about an inch wide) that I presume was being driven by an &#60;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arduino&#34;&#62;Arduino&#60;/a&#62; or something similar. I did some looking around, but was unable to find a good starting point for a fun little project (i.e. hacking with LCDs for dummies that might include code and suggestions of hardware). Anyone out there have any advice or useful links?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Wally Grotophorst on "Civ 5 Modding?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/civ-5-modding#post-405</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2010 14:26:18 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Wally Grotophorst</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">405@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;&#60;a href=&#34;http://forums.civfanatics.com/showthread.php?t=386910&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://forums.civfanatics.com/showthread.php?t=386910&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;this site covers some of these sorts of questions.  I have to wait till it appears for the Mac.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Bethany Nowviskie on "Any ideas for meaningful, DH-oriented wearable or physical computing?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/any-ideas-for-meaningful-dh-oriented-wearable-or-physical-computing#post-77</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2010 21:44:28 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Bethany Nowviskie</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">77@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I'm interested in wearables and physical computing -- in the sense of tactile, embodied interaction like that made possible by the Lilypad Arduino, a sew-able, programmable microprocessor. My problem is that, conceptually, I can't get past toys and art pieces -- like blinky, light-up merit badges, ambient orbs that respond to the state of my inbox, a tipsyflower made of shape-memory wire &#38;amp; breathalyzer parts, jewelry that whines when you walk north... &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I'd like to design a project that I felt was meaningful in terms of digital humanities theory or research -- something useful within, or reflective about, the field. And I'm just stuck. Any ideas? &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;No experience in soft circuits or arduinos necessary: I've just got a weird kind of writer's block and am looking for inspiration.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
