<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- generator="bbPress/1.0.2" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Humanities Questions &#38; Answers &#187; Topic: Mind-Mapping, Organizing?</title>
		<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/mind-mapping-organizing</link>
		<description>Digital Humanities Questions &amp; Answers &#187; Topic: Mind-Mapping, Organizing?</description>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2016 01:46:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<generator>http://bbpress.org/?v=1.0.2</generator>
		<textInput>
			<title><![CDATA[Search]]></title>
			<description><![CDATA[Search all topics from these forums.]]></description>
			<name>q</name>
			<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/search.php</link>
		</textInput>
		<atom:link href="/rss/topic/mind-mapping-organizing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
			 
				<title>frostdavis on "Mind-Mapping, Organizing?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/mind-mapping-organizing#post-1553</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2012 14:23:38 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>frostdavis</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1553@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;&#60;em&#62;Replying to @&#60;a href='/profile/egitre'&#62;egitre&#60;/a&#62;'s &#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/mind-mapping-organizing#post-977&#34;&#62;post&#60;/a&#62;:&#60;/em&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;You might try the Personal Brain, available here: &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.thebrain.com/products/personalbrain/&#34;&#62;http://www.thebrain.com/products/personalbrain/&#60;/a&#62;&#60;br /&#62;
I haven't used this program in a while, but it looks like they are still updating it.  I'm not sure how much memory it uses, but it is cross-platform and has the functionality you require, i.e., the ability to link to documents on your harddrive into a complex mindmap without moving them.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>egitre on "Mind-Mapping, Organizing?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/mind-mapping-organizing#post-977</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2011 11:46:12 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>egitre</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">977@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I stand corrected.  I can imagine DEVONthink's AI being really helpful in some instances.  Nevertheless, I'm afraid the program still doesn't do what, at base, I need it to (as you intimated).  My sources range in size from 1 to 500 pages, for a start.  &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Anyone have alternative suggestions?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Wally Grotophorst on "Mind-Mapping, Organizing?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/mind-mapping-organizing#post-976</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2011 20:12:18 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Wally Grotophorst</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">976@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;You're right  on one level; that is, DEVONthink doesn't do graphical representations of how one item relates to another.  Yet, it's not right to say it's just a database that relies on tags and organizing folders.   There's an AI (artificial intelligence) capability built into the program as well.  The precise way this happens depends on the view you've set, but do a search...then click on an item in the results set, then look around for an 'upside-down' hat icon (maybe it's something else but that's what it looks like to me)...when you find it, give a click...you'll see &#34;see also&#34; documents that DEVONthink has decided have some relationship to the one you've found.    If your documents are short (e.g., 1000 words or so), this sort of relationship will be quite strong.  If each of your docs is a 50 page treatise, well, probably less useful.  But still, there's more going on here than simple string-match searching.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;If you goal is a program that takes all your data and then builds visual relationships that might alert you to connections you hadn't thought about, well, this probably isn't it.   The DEVONthink thing is more or less...I found this document that seems important, what else is related to this in some way or other?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>egitre on "Mind-Mapping, Organizing?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/mind-mapping-organizing#post-975</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2011 12:30:55 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>egitre</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">975@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Thank you for the suggestion.  I have downloaded and indexed my files.  &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;While it looks like DEVONthink Pro is a really well-designed object-oriented DB, it appears to rely on groups and tags to create relationships.  Am I correct in thinking DEVONthink Pro is, primarily, a sophisticated DB?  &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I was hoping for something that is more visual and fluid, like a mind-map, that would allow me to visualize relationships while working through my various documents and ideas.  That is, I need something with tools to work more optimally at a meta-source level.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Wally Grotophorst on "Mind-Mapping, Organizing?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/mind-mapping-organizing#post-974</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2011 23:39:06 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Wally Grotophorst</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">974@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I seem to figure out a way to recommend DEVONthink Pro for most document organizing projects and I think it offers a possible solution for your question as well. It's Mac only (native cocoa app) and beyond building it's own database it offers the option of indexing documents on your disk without &#34;ingesting&#34; them in the database.  &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I'll suggest you download a trial version, set up a database and then use &#34;index&#34; under the file menu to add (index) the contents of various folders on your disk.  Then run a few searches and explore the AI component within DEVONthink.  &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;&#60;a href=&#34;http://www.devon-technologies.com/products/devonthink/index.html&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://www.devon-technologies.com/products/devonthink/index.html&#60;/a&#62;
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>egitre on "Mind-Mapping, Organizing?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/mind-mapping-organizing#post-970</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2011 15:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>egitre</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">970@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I'm a postdoc fellow, a historian, working on a book manuscript, based on thousands of historical sources in a variety of electronic formats (pdfs, mp4s, images, word docs, etc.).  I have my sources organized logically on my Mac in a hierarchical folder structure.  This method works for the purposes of downloading and storing sources, but not for reorganizing, brainstorming, and writing.  &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Does anyone know of a software package that will leave all my documents where they reside on my hard drive but can link these together in a more permanent, yet still fluid  (non-hierarchical) structure -- kind of like a very complex mind map?  Of course, I could put tags and attach keywords to pull material together.  This method, however, has serious limitations.  So, too, do databases which tend toward hierarchical structures.  &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I have looked at mind mapping software -- the free and cheaper packages -- and all have marked limitations.  I'm working with thousands of PDFs and other sources, which rules out programs designed for smaller projects.  Vue uses a lot of memory even before attaching documents.  Other programs import files; however, my project would measure in the gigabytes if I were forced into going that route.   I want to leave files where they reside on my computer with the capability of reorganizing them visually with links.  Curio does some of this, yet it proved unstable on my system.  A native-Mac program that utilizes its cocoa base, allowing access, for instance, to Quick Look, would be best.  &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I have spent too many hours googling around, trying out various packages on my own, and could really use some assistance.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
