<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- generator="bbPress/1.0.2" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Humanities Questions &#38; Answers &#187; User Favorites: kaia.landon@gmail.com</title>
		<link><a href='/profile/kaialandongmailcom'>kaialandongmailcom</a></link>
		<description>Digital Humanities Questions &amp; Answers &#187; User Favorites: kaia.landon@gmail.com</description>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2013 19:27:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<generator>http://bbpress.org/?v=1.0.2</generator>
		<textInput>
			<title><![CDATA[Search]]></title>
			<description><![CDATA[Search all topics from these forums.]]></description>
			<name>q</name>
			<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/search.php</link>
		</textInput>
		<atom:link href="/rss/profile/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
			 
				<title>Patrick Murray-John on "collaborative software for transcribing digital images of handwritten documents"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/collaborative-software-for-transcribing-digital-images-of-handwritten-documents#post-1997</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2013 14:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Patrick Murray-John</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1997@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;&#60;em&#62;Replying to @Ethan Gruber's &#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/collaborative-software-for-transcribing-digital-images-of-handwritten-documents#post-1994&#34;&#62;post&#60;/a&#62;:&#60;/em&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;It's worth mentioning that Scripto itself is CMS-neutral (See &#60;a href='http://scripto.org/documentation/about/'&#62;this&#60;/a&#62;). Developers can build their own tools to make it talk with whatever CMS they want. So far, they've built the connectors for Omeka, WP, and Drupal, but more would be awesome.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I'm not sure about Scripto to record TEI, though, since the transcriptions are recorded in MediaWiki.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Ben Brumfield on "collaborative software for transcribing digital images of handwritten documents"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/collaborative-software-for-transcribing-digital-images-of-handwritten-documents#post-1996</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2013 02:52:39 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Ben Brumfield</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1996@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;&#60;em&#62;Replying to @Ethan Gruber's &#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/collaborative-software-for-transcribing-digital-images-of-handwritten-documents#post-1994&#34;&#62;post&#60;/a&#62;:&#60;/em&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;These are excellent questions, Ethan.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Regarding image importing, at the moment the only transcription tools I know of supporting any sort of integration with external images are Scripto (Omeka, Wordpress, Drupal), FromThePage (Internet Archive), Islandora TEI Editor (Fedora), the (closed-source) BYU Historic Journals project (ContentDM), and Zooniverse Scribe (via deep-linking to any image on the internet, at a per-page level).  This is, in my opinion, a serious and non-trivial problem with all transcription tools -- just last week I talked with a librarian who really wanted to use T-PEN for medieval manuscript fragments, but was going to use Scripto instead, purely because the images were on their Omeka site.  It seems like rather than using the right tool for the job--and my own FromThePage would be just as inappropriate as Scripto for this use--she was using the tool which integrated with her CMS.  The problem is that it's a lot of effort to integrate tool X with CMS Y, and it's not a problem that scales well across either dimension.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I'm not aware of any transcription tools that do linked data at all.  I know that I've looked into it for FromThePage, but those investigations remain just that -- exciting ideas which do not override improvements to the core tool.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Regarding exports, the XML-(or TEI)-native T-PEN and Bentham Transcription Desk should support export of whatever TEI you use to put into them.  Ditto for MOM-CA-based tools like Itinera Nova, Monasterium, Virtuelles deutsches Urkundennetzwerk as well as the Papyrological Editor.  Mind you &#34;should&#34; is my own term -- I don't know if any of these tools actually feature an 'export' button or API.  FromThePage converts transcripts, subjects, indices, and edit histories into one big HTML file for export, with classes which may allow extraction and conversion.  (I explored TEI export in 2009, but at the time had no background in TEI and abandoned the project -- things will be different soon, however.)  I gather that Scripto exports to the CMS which is its database-of-record, and suspect that CrowdCrafting may well have an export feature as well.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I love your idea of combining annotation and open data -- it seems to come up all the time in conversation these days, but I don't know of any projects which have gotten beyond the idea stage.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Ethan Gruber on "collaborative software for transcribing digital images of handwritten documents"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/collaborative-software-for-transcribing-digital-images-of-handwritten-documents#post-1994</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2013 17:40:20 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Ethan Gruber</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1994@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Sorry, to dredge up an old topic, but are any of the tools listed here capable of importing images from or otherwise interacting with DSpace? FromThePage appears to support some of the annotations that I would like to make about manuscript images, but I want to avoid making duplicates of images, if possible (since various derivatives will already be available in DSpace, should I elect to use it).&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Also, is anyone aware of annotation tools that interact with web services, such as linking manuscripts to resources defined in VIAF or Geonames?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;What sorts of export mechanisms are provided by these annotation tools?  Can I export to TEI?  MODS?  Something else?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I envision using an annotation tool in the back-end to generate TEI or some other robust form of metadata with links to thesauri like VIAF, Geonames, or the Pleiades Gazetteer of Ancient Places in order to import a lot of open data for enhanced context, generate maps, etc.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>elotroalex on "Mapping historic sites - MediaWiki?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/mapping-historic-sites-mediawiki#post-1929</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 18:19:56 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>elotroalex</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1929@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Hi Kaia,&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;As far as I know you won't find a wiki solution to this because wikis are just webpages. In order to do what you are doing, you would need to transition to a database solution. I would recommend an &#60;a href=&#34;http://omeka.org/&#34;&#62;Omeka&#60;/a&#62;/&#60;a href=&#34;http://neatline.org/&#34;&#62;Neatline&#60;/a&#62; combo. You will be able to use 'items' to make the nuanced distinctions you want to make. Omeka/Neatline is of course not the only option available to you. Another solution would be to build your maps separate from your encyclopedic compendium, using links to connect them back and forth. Hope that helps.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Kaia on "Mapping historic sites - MediaWiki?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/mapping-historic-sites-mediawiki#post-1921</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 21:02:41 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Kaia</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1921@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;We're working on a wiki for our local history, and my dream is to come up with a feature to help sort out mapping questions - if some citation says something was one door south of something else (in 1960) it can be quite difficult to unpack what the address (or general location even) actually was. In my ideal world, each business could have its own article, with a field for the address, and the end result could be a map that would show each article with an address. There are, of course, cases where addresses have changed as buildings have been torn down and rebuilt, split into two, combined, etc., but a map view would seem to make some of that matter less.&#60;br /&#62;
How would I go about this? Is it possible, or am I dreaming? The maps extensions for MediaWiki I've look at seem to be geared toward displaying maps on article pages.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Kaia on "Experience with Collective Access?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/experience-with-collective-access#post-1727</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2012 20:10:56 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Kaia</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1727@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;That's one place where Omeka really excels and CA currently falls short. If you've got the time and expertise to script the import, it's possible. There are a variety of ways to export from searches, but I'm not sure how comprehensive they are, or if they're better in the recently released 1.2 (which we haven't upgraded to yet). (My concern at the moment isn't getting data out, it's getting it in!)&#60;br /&#62;
A nice, easy import (like what Omeka has) does not yet exist in CA. It was originally slated for an October 2011 release, which got moved to December 2011. That version was completely unusable by anyone but the software developers. They realized they needed to reconfigure it, and that was slated for 1.2, but has now been pushed back to 1.3 (with a September 2012 release date planned).
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>dot.porter on "Experience with Collective Access?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/experience-with-collective-access#post-1726</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2012 16:08:33 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>dot.porter</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1726@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Thanks Kaia. I read through the documentation for CA and I couldn't find anything about either importing existing metadata or exporting (well, from a search result, but it's not clear how much that would include). Do you know if there is import/export function for the collection metadata?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Kaia on "Experience with Collective Access?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/experience-with-collective-access#post-1724</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 16:24:03 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Kaia</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1724@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;While they do some of the same things, Omeka is really a &#60;strong&#62; content &#60;/strong&#62;management system for online exhibits, while CollectiveAccess is really a &#60;strong&#62;collection&#60;/strong&#62; management system with a front-end that can be used for online exhibits.&#60;br /&#62;
Which might suit you best depends on your needs. If you need a fairly simple way to present photos, documents, etc. online, Omeka may be the solution. If you need a full tracking system for collections (including insurance valuations, location tracking, provenance fields, etc.), that's CollectiveAccess.&#60;br /&#62;
With CA, you can add fields for anything imaginable, and have total control over which of those fields are exposed on the front-end. With Omeka, there is a great selection of fields, but you cannot add your own, and they all default to showing on the front-end. While I suspect you could hack some of them to not display, there aren't built-in controls for that. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Out of the box Omeka is easier to get up and running, and, if you're running on a shared server, more likely to be able to play media. We've got CA running on a shared server and can host video/audio that can be downloaded, but not played through the site, as CA comes with utilities to process those types of file that require settings our host won't allow. (We've therefore also got an Omeka install for some of those. This isn't ideal for us, but there's a chance this will change.)
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>dot.porter on "Experience with Collective Access?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/experience-with-collective-access#post-1723</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 15:11:55 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>dot.porter</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1723@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;A colleague has asked me about Collective Access (&#60;a href=&#34;http://www.collectiveaccess.org/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://www.collectiveaccess.org/&#60;/a&#62;) and I've not heard of it until now. Does anyone here have experience with it? I've looked at a couple of the featured projects and it looks similar to Omeka (it's a digital object content management system plus front-end for searching and display). I'm going to install it and play around to see what it can do and how it's different from Omeka, but I'd appreciate any insight or feedback from people who have used it. Thanks!
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>dot.porter on "collaborative software for transcribing digital images of handwritten documents"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/collaborative-software-for-transcribing-digital-images-of-handwritten-documents#post-788</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 00:50:51 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>dot.porter</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">788@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;TILE by itself wouldn't really help with this, but it's designed to be incorporated into other systems (VRE, for example) - and we're hopeful that once it's released this year it will actually be used in that way. And this may sound naive, but what about just using a wiki? Could you format the pages so that the images are on the left and you can transcribe on the right, or something? Otherwise, I'd second T-Pen and Transcribe Bentham (the advantage of TB being that it's actually going to be available soon).
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>MelissaTerras on "collaborative software for transcribing digital images of handwritten documents"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/collaborative-software-for-transcribing-digital-images-of-handwritten-documents#post-731</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2010 10:16:11 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>MelissaTerras</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">731@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Hi folks&#60;br /&#62;
You should also look at what we are doing over at Transcribe Bentham - we will be making the code public for that soon, for other people to use.  &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.transcribe-bentham.da.ulcc.ac.uk/td/Transcribe_Bentham&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://www.transcribe-bentham.da.ulcc.ac.uk/td/Transcribe_Bentham&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;The tile project (&#60;a href=&#34;http://mith.info/tile/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://mith.info/tile/&#60;/a&#62;) will also provide &#34;a new web-based, modular, collaborative image markup tool for both manual and semi-automated linking between encoded text and image of text, and image annotation&#34;.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Bethany Nowviskie on "collaborative software for transcribing digital images of handwritten documents"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/collaborative-software-for-transcribing-digital-images-of-handwritten-documents#post-726</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2010 09:46:59 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Bethany Nowviskie</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">726@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;&#60;em&#62;Replying to @Kaia's &#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/collaborative-software-for-transcribing-digital-images-of-handwritten-documents#post-725&#34;&#62;post&#60;/a&#62;:&#60;/em&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Kaia, there seems to be &#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/software-for-audio-transcription&#34;&#62;a separate thread&#60;/a&#62; about this right now.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Kaia on "collaborative software for transcribing digital images of handwritten documents"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/collaborative-software-for-transcribing-digital-images-of-handwritten-documents#post-725</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2010 03:06:21 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Kaia</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">725@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;So, does anyone know of something similar, but for audio files? It seems like the pile of oral histories to transcribe never gets any smaller. . .
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Ben Brumfield on "collaborative software for transcribing digital images of handwritten documents"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/collaborative-software-for-transcribing-digital-images-of-handwritten-documents#post-724</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2010 22:51:48 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Ben Brumfield</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">724@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;(Thanks, Alex!)&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;According to comments made recently on &#60;a href=&#34;http://manuscripttranscription.blogspot.com/2009/07/wikisource-for-manuscript-transcription.html&#34;&#62;my review of the MediaWiki ProofreadPage extension&#60;/a&#62; for manuscript transcription, it looks like the Hebrew and German language Wikisource instances have launched some projects transcribing manuscript material.  ProofreadPage is certainly worth looking at -- especially if your scanned images are already in djvu format.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Can you tell us a bit more about the kind of materials you're looking to transcribe?  Are they structured (e.g. muster rolls, census forms) or free-form (e.g. letters, diaries)?  How paleographically complex are they?  Do you hope to produce annotated editions, simple (flat) transcriptions, or just indexes of people and places mentioned within the documents?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>elotroalex on "collaborative software for transcribing digital images of handwritten documents"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/collaborative-software-for-transcribing-digital-images-of-handwritten-documents#post-719</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2010 01:58:07 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>elotroalex</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">719@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;You might also want to check out Ben Brumfield's (above) Collaborative Manuscript Transcription blog: &#60;a href=&#34;http://manuscripttranscription.blogspot.com/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://manuscripttranscription.blogspot.com/&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;You will find all kinds of goodies there.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
