<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- generator="bbPress/1.0.2" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Humanities Questions &#38; Answers &#187; Tag: pdf - Recent Topics</title>
		<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/tags/pdf</link>
		<description>Digital Humanities Questions &amp; Answers &#187; Tag: pdf - Recent Topics</description>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2013 07:41:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<generator>http://bbpress.org/?v=1.0.2</generator>
		<textInput>
			<title><![CDATA[Search]]></title>
			<description><![CDATA[Search all topics from these forums.]]></description>
			<name>q</name>
			<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/search.php</link>
		</textInput>
		<atom:link href="/rss/tags/pdf/topics" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
			 
				<title>Gogol71 on "I&#039;d like to create a personal database for a collection of letters"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/id-like-to-create-a-personal-database-for-a-collection-of-letters#post-2010</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2013 13:34:36 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Gogol71</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2010@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;What's the best software to create a personal database of letters in manuscript? I've downloaded the pictures in pdf format from a commercial database, so I haven't got the right to publish them and can't use open source software, I guess.&#60;br /&#62;
Many thanks for your help.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>olaf on "How create a real (with page numbers) index of journal&#039;s entire run, from PDFs?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-create-a-real-with-page-numbers-index-of-journals-entire-run-from-pdfs#post-1904</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2013 17:57:10 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>olaf</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1904@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I need to index all back issues of &#60;em&#62;&#60;a href=&#34;http://mamluk.uchicago.edu&#34;&#62;Mamluk Studies Review&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/em&#62; (open access, now digital only but formerly print) but have not had much luck finding ideas about how to go about it.&#60;br /&#62;
Searching the Web for info about indexing PDFs leads largely to results about indexing them on a computer for improved searches, or to indexing services.&#60;br /&#62;
I hope to find software (or scripts or something!) that can &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;ul&#62;
&#60;li&#62;read PDF files&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;understand the idea of page numbers&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;understand that each page in a pdf is a distinct entity&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;handle Unicode and diacritics (and, ideally, Arabic script)&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;see phrases or hyphenated words that break across pages as single items&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;/ul&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I don't expect anything to happen automatically: I know I (or better yet an unwary grad student) will have to actually go through and mark words and phrases to be included in the index.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Bonus points if it can be taught to ignore certain strings when alphabetizing. For example, since 'al-' is Arabic for 'the', it doesn't affect alphabetization (so al-Nasir Muhammad goes in the N section).&#60;br /&#62;
Similarly, there needs to be a way to instruct it that ā and a are the same for purposes of alphabetization, as are ṣ and s, etc.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Super bonus points if it can recognize (or learn to recognize) variations on a word or phrase in terms of spelling (often inconsistent when transliteration is involved), word order or intervening words.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;What I have: 23 issues of the journal as whole-book pdfs, as well as individual pdfs of all articles. Unfortunately, the first half dozen or so were created without Unicode, using proprietary fonts with non-standard encodings. Messy, but I can work around it somehow. I also have InDesign files (various versions) for about half the issues. This will all be done in Windows (32-bit XP and 64-bit 7). I always have the latest version of Acrobat (not reader, the full program).&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;The resulting index will be posted on the Web, probably both as a PDF and in some more dynamic and usable format(s). &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Any ideas for ways to streamline this would be appreciated. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Thanks!&#60;br /&#62;
Olaf
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Moacir P. de Sá Pereira on "iAnnotate vs. GoodReader?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/iannotate-vs-goodreader#post-853</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2010 17:16:19 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Moacir P. de Sá Pereira</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">853@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;It's Christmas at my household, which means that I can finally ask this question. I have been using GoodReader on my phone, and I generally like the wide array of means by which one can get to files, the reading experience in general, and the annotation seems a bit clunky, but good enough.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;My friend refuses to believe that there is a program for reading scholarly journals, chapters of books, things one has scanned, etc. that is better than iAnnotate.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;How do you all feel? Has anyone tried both? I can't really say money is the issue (since I decided that I apparently *need* FIFA11 on my iPad right after springing for GoodReader), but I would like to avoid getting heavily into the groove on one program or the other on the device and then switching up after succumbing to pressure from my DH peers.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>inactinique on "Is there a free (open) sofware to annotate PDFs, that can be used with zotero?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/is-there-a-free-open-sofware-to-annotate-pdfs-that-can-be-used-with-zotero#post-220</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2010 15:24:16 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>inactinique</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">220@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;To annotate PDFs in zotero, I am using a software (freeware), PDF X-Change Viewer, wich allow PDF-annotation. But it is not free/open-source. I can't use Pliny, because it's not zotero compliant. I'm using Windows XP and Ubuntu.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
