<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- generator="bbPress/1.0.2" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Humanities Questions &#38; Answers &#187; Tag: meta - Recent Topics</title>
		<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/tags/meta</link>
		<description>Digital Humanities Questions &amp; Answers &#187; Tag: meta - Recent Topics</description>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2018 16:56:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<generator>http://bbpress.org/?v=1.0.2</generator>
		<textInput>
			<title><![CDATA[Search]]></title>
			<description><![CDATA[Search all topics from these forums.]]></description>
			<name>q</name>
			<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/search.php</link>
		</textInput>
		<atom:link href="/rss/tags/meta/topics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
			 
				<title>Josh on "What other types of questions can we be asking here?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/what-other-types-of-questions-can-we-be-asking-here#post-2024</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 21:03:05 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Josh</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2024@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I would like to interrupt our regularly scheduled questioning here at DH Answers and get a little meta. DH Answers is a fantastic resource, but it tends to be very tool and tech centric, and I wonder it isn't time to find ways of facilitating other types of non-totally-unrelated discussion here. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Recently, some really great discussions have been happening on Twitter and sites like &#60;a href=&#34;http://dhpoco.org/&#34;&#62;DH Poco&#60;/a&#62; that have arisen in response to more social, political, and cultural questions, events, prompts, and provocations in relation to DH. I feel that some of these questions—of gender, labor, disciplinarity, and others—might be even more illuminating when embedded within other, more dominant, discourses, like those around available tools, technologies, and methodologies. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I also think that, due to issues of scope and scale on Twitter and the epic-scrolling and searching that needs to happen to stay up-to-date on the latest of 150+ blog post comments, we might need to seek out a better mechanism for supporting these important discussions. I don't mean to say these discussions shouldn't be happening anywhere and everywhere—of course they should!—but I also think that the way DH Answers was originally set up makes folks less likely to bring these types of discussion here. (Or maybe it's something else entirely? Discuss!)&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;For instance, a quick look at the categories one has to choose from when posting a question (this one is filed under &#34;About DHAnswers&#34; which may or may not makes sense) reveals how much we are privileging technical questions about tools and technologies, and while there's certainly nothing wrong with that (the tools and tech, not so much the privileging) it unfortunately, I'd argue, suggestively narrows the conversation considerably. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;&#34;1 Year Ago&#34; Matthew Kirschenbaum asked the DH Answers community, &#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/should-dhers-accept-militarydefense-funding#post-1239&#34;&#62;&#34;Should DHers accept military/defense funding?&#34;&#60;/a&#62; which he tagged with, among other things, &#34;ethics&#34; (not a single &#34;Popular Tag&#34; explicitly deals with any of these &#34;other&#34; issues). It was also filed under the category &#34;Project Management &#38;amp; DH Profession,&#34; which seems to be the catch-all for questions that don't fit strict the limitations of the tech-centric discourse. I think the question Matthew raises, due to everything from recent events (see: PRISM) to the history of humanists working in military research, makes this a very pertinent and important question worth exploring, especially in this particular digital space. And while before and after that post there have been several of a more political or ethical nature, there have not been many, and that seems, at the very least, worthy of concern and some discussion.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;So, LONG STORY SHORT, I'd like to see what others think about this by asking the following questions (along with all of those implicitly and explicitly raised above): (1) Can and should DH Answers be a place for social, cultural, political, etc. discussion (as it seems it at times has been)? (2) What types of categories can we add that would make folks more comfortable feeling such questions are welcome? (3) How can we continue to further integrate discussions happening in other venues—Twitter, DH Poco, personal blogs, MLA Commons, etc.—with DH Answers?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Bethany Nowviskie on "How can we improve the DHanswers site?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-can-we-improve-the-dhanswers-site#post-192</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2010 13:06:15 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Bethany Nowviskie</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">192@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Now that we've launched (and a big thanks to our collaborators and to all of the people who volunteered to beta test and pre-populate the site!), we're keen to hear your ideas for improving DHanswers.  We have some plans for further Twitter integration and email notifications at the category level, but need to hear your good ideas.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;So here's an open thread. What can we do to make DHanswers as useful and joyful a community-based tool as possible?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>hopegreenberg on "Who supports DH at your institution? An impromptu survey."</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/who-supports-dh-at-your-institution-an-impromptu-survey#post-953</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2011 19:21:57 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>hopegreenberg</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">953@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;In the wake of increasing visibility of the term &#34;digital humanities&#34; in national and discipline-specific press, we might expect that faculty in humanities departments will be intrigued and will want to explore the possibilities of getting involved in DH work. Beyond the online resources, what are the local &#34;on the ground&#34; resources? Some possibilities might be people in the department already working on DH projects, or institution-wide faculty development organizations (Centers for Excellence in Teaching or for Teaching and Learning, etc.), or IT groups that support academic work. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;The questions, then, are: to whom at your institution will propsective DH practitioners turn for information and help? What kind of help is available?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;(I'f you prefer anonymity I'll also compile all answers I get, names removed, which are sent to me at &#60;a href=&#34;mailto:hope.greenberg@uvm.edu&#34;&#62;hope.greenberg@uvm.edu&#60;/a&#62;)
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Bethany Nowviskie on "How can I find answers, get my questions answered, &#38; help DHanswers grow?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-can-i-find-info-thats-already-been-discussed-help-dhanswers-grow#post-492</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2010 19:35:21 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Bethany Nowviskie</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">492@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Gee, I'm wondering if one of our intrepid &#60;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/DHanswers&#34;&#62;@DHanswers&#60;/a&#62; admins can enlighten us all on good ways to find information on this site.  How can we all best use &#60;em&#62;and contribute to good management of&#60;/em&#62; the knowledge in this growing, community-built knowledge-base?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;If only someone doing, say, a post-doc in Information Management could offer some advice...
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Eric Johnson on "Has anybody written a history of the digital humanities?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/has-anybody-written-a-history-of-the-digital-humanities#post-558</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2010 21:15:26 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Eric Johnson</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">558@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I've often found myself wondering if anybody has written a book-length narrative history telling the story of humanities computing/digital humanities from the early days of humanities computing until now (or some approximation thereof), addressing major milestone DH projects, related efforts, and some of the big themes of the field as they've evolved--or haven't--over time?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I suspect that some histories may have been done that address particular disciplines (e.g. digital history), but have they been tied together and examined as a whole?  I see that the question has been addressed in conference presentations, such as those by &#60;a href=&#34;http://infomotions.com/blog/tag/digital-humanities/&#34;&#62;Joe Raben&#60;/a&#62; or &#60;a href=&#34;http://infomotions.com/blog/2010/05/cyberinfrastructure-days-at-the-university-of-notre-dame/&#34;&#62;Stéfan Sinclair&#60;/a&#62;, and appears in Chapter 1 of Schreibman et al.'s &#34;&#60;a href=&#34;http://www.digitalhumanities.org/companion/&#34;&#62;A Companion to Digital Humanities&#60;/a&#62;,&#34; but I wondered if anything longer has been published.  I may well have just sailed right past it.  Seems like it would make a great oral history project, too.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Nicholas Pavkovic on "What is Digital Humanities?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/what-is-digital-humanities#post-289</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 03:06:23 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Nicholas Pavkovic</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">289@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Sorry to be so green, and I apologize if this issue has already been addressed somewhere the forums. If a definition is elusive, a list of example projects would be helpful.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Thanks!
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Bethany Nowviskie on "So, what is this Q&#38;A forum, and what can I do here?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/so-what-is-this-qa-forum-and-what-can-i-do-here#post-47</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2010 00:17:17 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Bethany Nowviskie</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">47@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;[Welcome to the only canned, pro-forma question in DHanswers!]&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Gee, I'm wondering if you can tell me a little more about this site.  What's it for?  What kind of questions should I be asking?  Any tips and tricks?  And who is here to help me?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
