<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- generator="bbPress/1.0.2" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Humanities Questions &#38; Answers &#187; Tag: teaching - Recent Topics</title>
		<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/tags/teaching</link>
		<description>Digital Humanities Questions &amp; Answers &#187; Tag: teaching - Recent Topics</description>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 06:55:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<generator>http://bbpress.org/?v=1.0.2</generator>
		<textInput>
			<title><![CDATA[Search]]></title>
			<description><![CDATA[Search all topics from these forums.]]></description>
			<name>q</name>
			<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/search.php</link>
		</textInput>
		<atom:link href="/rss/tags/teaching/topics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
			 
				<title>Kaarina on "Examples of online teaching modules or lesson plans?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/examples-of-online-teaching-modules-or-lesson-plans#post-2384</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 15:57:09 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Kaarina</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2384@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Hello!&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I am helping to develop teaching modules around a collection of digitized texts and artefacts, so that non-expert instructors and teachers can integrate these texts into their courses. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Can anyone think of examples of strong teaching modules/guides/plans that are freely available online?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Thanks!
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>LeahPowell on "How did you learn to code?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-did-you-learn-to-code#post-2368</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 10:52:28 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>LeahPowell</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2368@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I'm a PhD in English student, and I'm interested in (but very new to) DH. I will start working with TEI soon through a digital archive project I'm working on, so there's that. What other avenues should I explore in my quest to learn coding for the sake of DH research?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>rachaelsullivan on "What texts would you use in a &#34;Literature of Information Overload&#34; course?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/what-texts-would-you-use-in-a-literature-of-information-overload-course#post-1945</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 16:55:43 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>rachaelsullivan</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1945@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;This fall, I'm teaching a course called &#34;Literature of Information Overload.&#34; It's a 200-level undergraduate course in English. Students will mostly be sophomore English majors, I'd imagine.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I need help with selecting texts for this course! Below is a draft of the course description and a list of texts I've started (obviously I won't include all this on the syllabus, but I just wanted to give a sense of what I'm thinking). I'm looking for fiction, non-fiction, films -- you name it. Even if I don't use something in the syllabus, I'd like to compile a longer list of &#34;recommended reading and resources&#34; to post on the course website. &#60;strong&#62;I'm open to all ideas/suggestions.&#60;/strong&#62;&#60;br /&#62;
- - - -&#60;br /&#62;
&#60;em&#62;Everybody gets so much information all day long that they lose their common sense. They listen so much that they forget to be natural. This is a nice story.&#60;br /&#62;
&#60;a href=&#34;http://www.writing.upenn.edu/~afilreis/88/stein-atom-bomb.html&#34;&#62;Gertrude Stein, 1946&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/em&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Information overload is a contemporary cultural concern with a rich past. This course will cover a broad sampling of texts from different time periods to consider how our current confrontation/struggle with digital technologies both &#60;em&#62;is&#60;/em&#62; and &#60;em&#62;is not&#60;/em&#62; new. We will pay attention to the various forms that information overload takes: a pathological condition, a burden on attention and social bonds, a renaissance of knowledge access and production, and even a non-issue. Most importantly for our purposes, the texts we read and view will help us to ask how our understanding of knowledge, literature, and even ourselves evolves alongside technological innovations.  Through studying texts that comment on, represent, and/or actually produce the feeling of overload in readers, we will encounter questions like:&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;ul&#62;
&#60;li&#62;How do people experience and describe information overload (or a sense of &#34;too much&#34;) across cultures and chapters of technological development? In what ways is the contemporary predicament of information management similar to and different from struggles of the past?&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;How does information overload contribute to distraction and changing modes of attention, and why is this relevant to today's readers of literature? &#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;What are the differences between information and literature? What is at stake in efforts to make a distinction?&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;If we accept the story of how humans are becoming increasingly dependent on their reference tools and technological devices, what new types of machine-human hybrids emerge? What reasons might we find for accepting or resisting this cyborg vision?&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;/ul&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Through engaging with these questions and the texts (some alphabetic and others visual) on the syllabus, we will learn how information overload functions as a subject matter, a form or structuring device, and an affect generated by the work itself. This final affective quality of information overload (the feeling of having &#60;em&#62;too much&#60;/em&#62; to know and organize) is a familiar frenemy of college students, so I hope that you will draw on your personal experiences to enlighten our discussions and inform your writing.&#60;br /&#62;
- - - -&#60;br /&#62;
&#60;strong&#62;ideas for literary texts&#60;/strong&#62;&#60;br /&#62;
Jonathan Swift, &#34;The Battle of the Books&#34; (1704)&#60;br /&#62;
Walt Whitman, &#34;Song of Myself&#34; (1855)&#60;br /&#62;
Gertrude Stein, selections from &#60;em&#62;Tender Buttons&#60;/em&#62; and/or &#34;Composition as Explanation&#34;&#60;br /&#62;
Jorge Luis Borges, &#34;The Library of Babel&#34; (1941)&#60;br /&#62;
Thomas Pynchon, &#34;Entropy&#34; (1960)&#60;br /&#62;
Franz Kafka, &#34;The Burrow&#34; (1971)&#60;br /&#62;
Michael Joyce, &#60;em&#62;Was: annales nomadique: a novel of internet&#60;/em&#62; (2007)&#60;br /&#62;
Something YHCHI&#60;br /&#62;
Nick Montfort &#38;amp; Stephanie Strickland, &#60;em&#62;Sea and Spar Between&#60;/em&#62; (2010)&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;&#60;strong&#62;ideas for critical/theoretical texts&#60;/strong&#62;&#60;br /&#62;
Alex Wright, selections from &#60;em&#62;Glut: Mastering Information Through the Ages&#60;/em&#62; (2007) Specifically the introduction and chapters on &#34;The Ice Age Information Explosion&#34; and &#34;The Age of Alphabets&#34;&#60;br /&#62;
Tom Standage, selections from &#60;em&#62;The Victorian Internet&#60;/em&#62; (2007)&#60;br /&#62;
Vannevar Bush, &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/1945/07/as-we-may-think/303881/&#34;&#62;&#34;As We May Think&#34;&#60;/a&#62; (1945)&#60;br /&#62;
Neil Postman, &#60;a href=&#34;http://w2.eff.org/Net_culture/Criticisms/informing_ourselves_to_death.paper&#34;&#62;&#34;Informing Ourselves to Death&#34;&#60;/a&#62; (1990)&#60;br /&#62;
Philip Elmer-Dewitt, &#60;em&#62;Time&#60;/em&#62; magazine article: &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.time.com/time/magazine/article/0,9171,978216,00.html&#34;&#62;&#34;Take A Trip into the Future on the Electronic Superhighway&#34;&#60;/a&#62; (1993)&#60;br /&#62;
Clay Shirky, &#60;a href=&#34;http://boingboing.net/2010/01/31/clay-shirky-on-infor.html&#34;&#62;&#34;It's Not Information Overload. It's Filter Failure&#34;&#60;/a&#62; (2008)&#60;br /&#62;
Ann Blair, &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.boston.com/bostonglobe/ideas/articles/2010/11/28/information_overload_the_early_years/&#34;&#62;&#34;Information overload, the early years&#34;&#60;/a&#62; (2010)  or a selection from &#60;em&#62;Too Much to Know: Managing Scholarly Information before the Modern Age&#60;/em&#62; (2010)&#60;br /&#62;
Nick Carr, &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2008/07/is-google-making-us-stupid/306868/&#34;&#62;&#34;Is Google Making Us Stupid?&#34;&#60;/a&#62; (2008)&#60;br /&#62;
Cathy Davidson, introduction and chapter 6 (&#34;The Changing Workplace&#34;) from &#60;em&#62;Now You See It&#60;/em&#62; (2011)&#60;br /&#62;
Elizabeth Gruber Garvey, selections from &#60;em&#62;Writing with Scissors: American Scrapbooks from the Civil War to the Harlem Renaissance&#60;/em&#62; (2012)
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>scottkleinman on "Undergraduate DH Training, Transferable Skills, and Employment Prospects"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/undergraduate-dh-training-transferable-skills-and-employment-prospects#post-1962</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2013 16:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>scottkleinman</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1962@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;This isn't really a specific question, but more of a conversation starter. I've been looking around for a well-articulated statement of the transferable skills students acquire in studying digital humanities, above and beyond, and in combination with traditional humanities skills. As we try to transfer DH research culture to the undergraduate classroom, it seems to me increasingly important to make a case that studying DH provides skills that are in demand by employers--and that give graduates a leg up in the job market--but one especially geared towards undergraduate, the majority of whom are not going to pursue graduate school. I think many of us treat the advantages as self-evident: coding skills, data analysis, project management, to name a few types of knowledge not emphasised in the traditional humanities. These are all skills in demand. But the undergraduate DH student is not likely to be competitive with one in computer scientist for a software engineering job. Is there a special niche for the humanities students with a DH background?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Thoughts or resources are greatly appreciated.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>sbarnwell on "Any graduate level DH programs in the works?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/any-graduate-level-dh-programs-in-the-works#post-1796</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 12:45:56 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>sbarnwell</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1796@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I'm working with a group at UNC-Chapel Hill on DH-related educational initiatives and we're pulling together an environmental scan of graduate level digital humanities programs--PhD, MA, certificates. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Past posts on DH Q&#38;amp;A have been great at pointing me toward established programs, but now I'm wondering if there are other graduate level programs in the works? &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I'd also be interested in hearing about programs that allow humanities PhD students to substitute tech skills, research methodologies, etc. for foreign languages requirements as well as PhD programs that incorporate DH training in other ways---perhaps as a minor field, etc. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Cheers,&#60;br /&#62;
Stephanie
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Inna Kizhner on "DH projects with strong visual/non-linear components"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/dh-projects-with-strong-visualnon-linear-components#post-1740</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2012 01:40:34 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Inna Kizhner</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1740@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;This autumn I will be teaching an Introduction to DH to a group of masters students with some background in museum informatics. They are non-English speaking students and there is little motivation for them to read academic papers in English (we are based in Siberia). This might mean that examples of scholarly argumentation and DH scholarship should be taken from visualised/non-linear projects, such as GIS, museum web sites with developed browsing opportunities, timelines, etc. I would be appreciative if somebody could refer me to such projects and/or for recommendations or best practices of teaching an academic course without relying too much on reading assignments. It would be even interesting to build a syllabus based on visualisations and non-linear narratives. This would turn our weakness into an opportunity.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>mariazoey on "Recommended course of study for New Media/DH teaching career?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/recommended-course-of-study-for-new-mediadh-teaching-career#post-1554</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2012 17:44:46 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>mariazoey</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1554@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I have been completing hours for an AA to transfer for an English undergrad degree. Recently it has come to my attention that teaching university English is a field mostly closed to new blood, due to the number of highly-qualified individuals already there. I'm considering switching to a career path in teaching Digital Humanities or New Media instead, but feel a little lost as to knowing what would be a fruitful undergrad degree versus one that's actually worthless in the face of a teaching career. What degrees are useful? Which schools are good? Are there any in the Kansas City area?? Thanks a bunch.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Roger Whitson on "Resources/Strategies for teaching coding or programming to grad students?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/resourcesstrategies-for-teaching-coding-or-programming-to-grad-students#post-1521</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2012 12:30:32 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Roger Whitson</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1521@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Hi, does anyone know of any resources for teaching a short unit of a larger DH course on programming for graduate students? I'd like students to have basic skills in HTML/CSS/Python - but maybe that's asking too much. Any strategies?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Stéfan Sinclair on "Most comprehensive and current list of DH programs?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/most-comprehensive-and-current-list-of-dh-programs#post-1395</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 09:50:06 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Stéfan Sinclair</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1395@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;It seems to me that maintaining a comprehensive and current list of DH programs should be a high priority for the DH community, especially for outreach to students considering grad and undergrad studies. There's a great summary of &#60;a href=&#34;http://commons.gc.cuny.edu/wiki/index.php/DH_Syllabi&#34;&#62;DH syllabi&#60;/a&#62; and a more expansive &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.zotero.org/groups/digital_humanities_education&#34;&#62;Zotero group&#60;/a&#62;, but I'm not sure there's a reliable resource for DH programs (of course, how to define a DH program is a big issue here).&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;The ALLC's list of &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.allc.org/education/seminars-courses&#34;&#62;programs&#60;/a&#62; is very useful. Are there others that are current and fairly complete that you'd recommend?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Where would it make the most sense for such a list to be maintained?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>jmcclurken on "What is one topic or source you&#039;d use in a History of the Information Age class?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/what-is-one-topic-or-source-youd-use-in-a-history-of-the-information-age-class#post-1323</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2011 09:17:10 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>jmcclurken</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1323@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;This fall I'm teaching a History of the Information Age, an undergraduate seminar.  &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Here's the course description:  &#34;This readings seminar will explore the history of new media and the digital age.  We will begin with an investigation of the various definitions of the Information Age, then move into a discussion of the historical &#38;amp; technological foundations of information production, computing devices, and communication and networking tools.  We will explore the social and cultural history of information production and consumption from newspapers to the Internet, from analog computational machines to handheld computers.  The course will generally be based in the history of the US, but, given the transfer of technology and the increasing ability of these technologies to transcend geographic regions, it will logically range more widely as appropriate.&#34;  &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I'm creating a broad syllabus for the class with a few key readings and a big bibliography of primary and secondary texts, images, videos, films, etc.   The students in the class will select as a group the topics and readings we explore in more detail over the course of the semester.  I'm looking to expand the bibliography of potential sources that I've currently compiled at &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.zotero.org/groups/infoage/items&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://www.zotero.org/groups/infoage/items&#60;/a&#62;.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;[We will also, as a class, create a digital timeline of events, people, trends, ideas, concepts, linking to individual projects by students expanding on their particular areas of interest.  Any suggestions people have about small and large assignments (oral histories, infographics, short essay topics, mini-biographies, etc.) would also be welcome.]
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>briancroxall on "What should I read and what software should I use to do textual studies well?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/what-should-i-read-and-what-software-should-i-use-to-do-textual-studies-well#post-1311</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2011 15:58:22 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>briancroxall</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1311@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I'm super excited to be &#34;Introduction to Digital Humanities&#34; this fall. As I've been turning over the course in my mind, I've known that I've wanted to do one or more projects with the students, probably using our special collections, which tend to be quite strong in particular swaths of literature. This week I sat down with &#60;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/#!/LizChaseMARBL&#34;&#62;Liz Chase&#60;/a&#62;, one of our special collections librarians, and brainstormed. We came up with a great project involving &#60;a href=&#34;http://findingaids.library.emory.edu/documents/duffy834/?keywords=duffy&#34;&#62;our holdings of Carol Ann Duffy's notebooks&#60;/a&#62;. In short, we want to do some comparisons between how she writes in her 1999 volume, &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Worlds-Wife-Carol-Ann-Duffy/dp/057119995X/briacrox-20&#34;&#62;The World's Wife&#60;/a&#62;, and her previous volumes. We're interested in thematic material, vocabulary she uses, poetic styles, and so forth. But as I've been working to design the project, I've come to realize that the students' work (to say nothing of my teaching) will be improved by the inclusion of some readings on textual scholarship along these lines. &#60;strong&#62;But I don't know this field at all.&#60;/strong&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;What's more, I've been trying to think about what sort of software we might most profitably use to help push our analysis after creating a dataset of the texts. I'm guessing we'll want to represent word counts, word clouds, line structures, and more. My first thought is &#60;a href=&#34;http://seasr.org/&#34;&#62;SEASR&#60;/a&#62;, but I'm not familiar with the tool and I'm not sure if it's overkill or underkill or totally off the mark. I can always use &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.wordle.net/&#34;&#62;Wordle&#60;/a&#62;, but I would like to have more options. And perhaps if I really knew this field of scholarship then it would be easier for me to know which tools I should be using.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;What I really need, then, is a suggestion of books or articles that I should read so that our class proceeds thoughtfully on the project with an understanding of what's been done in the past. Any tool suggestions would be welcome as well.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>hopegreenberg on "Design a digital history curriculum: what would you include?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/design-a-digital-history-curriculum-what-would-you-include#post-814</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2010 11:04:59 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>hopegreenberg</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">814@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;There are now a number of universities offering courses in digital history. When you look at individual syllabi, however, there is quite a variety in approaches or topics covered. If you were given the task of designing a curriculum or a series of courses to be taught alongside more traditional history courses, what would you include? &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Let's say it's a series of 4 courses, one per semester over 2 years, that begins with first year students (undergraduate freshmen) with a goal of producing digitally &#34;nimble&#34; history students or even digital historians (feel free to define both of those!). How would you balance theory, general information literacy skills, projects, programming, etc? What would be the &#34;must include&#34; pieces and which would be the ideal? What mix of lecture-based, active learning/project based, discussion/seminar, online/face-to-face/hybrid or other configuration would you build?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>elotroalex on "What&#039;s the best open source e-Portfolio tool for teaching?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/whats-the-best-open-source-e-portfolio-tool-for-teaching#post-644</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2010 15:37:34 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>elotroalex</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">644@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;And as corollary, how does it compare to a Wordpress install or a CMS?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>MelissaTerras on "What are the essential DH books on your class reading list?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/what-are-the-essential-dh-books-on-your-class-reading-list#post-114</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2010 07:43:13 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>MelissaTerras</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">114@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Hi Everyone,&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I'm just wondering what the essential books you tell your students are on your course reading lists. It may be useful to compile a list of those used (and point out to others ones that they have missed?) I'm aware that a lot has been published over the last few years - what am I missing? Thanks. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Here are my essentials:&#60;br /&#62;
-Set Text: &#34;A Companion to Digital Humanities&#34;. Schreibman, S., Siemens, R., Unsworth, J. (Eds). Blackwell Companions to Literature and Culture. Paperback Edition, 2007. Available freely online at &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.digitalhumanities.org/companion/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://www.digitalhumanities.org/companion/&#60;/a&#62;&#60;br /&#62;
-Set Text: &#34;A Companion to Digital Literary Studies&#34;. Schreibman, S., and Siemens, R., (Eds). Blackwell Companions to Literature and Culture. 2008. Available freely online at &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.digitalhumanities.org/companionDLS/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://www.digitalhumanities.org/companionDLS/&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;-Susan Hockey. (2000). Electronic Texts in the Humanities: Principles and Practice. Oxford: Oxford University Press.&#60;br /&#62;
-Deegan, M. and Tanner, S. (2006) “Digital Preservation”. London, Library Association Publishing.&#60;br /&#62;
-Deegan, M. and Tanner, S. (2001) “Digital Futures: strategies for the Information Age”. London, Library Association Publishing.&#60;br /&#62;
-Hughes, L. (2004). “Digitizing Collections, Strategic Issues for the Information Manager”. London, Facet.&#60;br /&#62;
-Kenney, A. and Reiger, O. (2000) &#34;Moving Theory Into Practice, Digital Imaging for Libraries and Archives&#34;. RLG.&#60;br /&#62;
- Macdonald, L.W. (2006). “Digital Heritage: applying digital imaging to cultural heritage”. Elsevier&#60;br /&#62;
-Naughton, J. (2000) “A Brief History of the Future: Origins of the Internet”. Pheonix.&#60;br /&#62;
-Cameron and Kenderdine (2007), “Theorizing Digital Cultural Heritage: A Critical Discourse”. MIT Press.&#60;br /&#62;
-Greengrass, M. and Hughes, L. (2008).”The virtual representation of the past”. Ashgate&#60;br /&#62;
-Matthew G Kirschenbaum (2008) “Mechanisms: New Media and the Forensic Imagination”,  MIT Press. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Thanks,&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Melissa
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Alice Stratton on "Methods/ideas for teaching hypertext theory"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/methodsideas-for-teaching-hypertext-theory#post-549</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2010 23:18:30 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Alice Stratton</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">549@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I'm currently working on a hypertext introductory program for advertising students.  I'm trying to steer clear of vertical transmission mode of teaching in favour of a more practise-focused, self-directed approach. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;So far I've found the teaching notes of Adrian Miles (&#60;a href=&#34;http://vogmae.net.au/research/thinking/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://vogmae.net.au/research/thinking/&#60;/a&#62;) and &#34;The Future of Learning&#34; (&#60;a href=&#34;http://startl.org/about/the-future-of-learning/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://startl.org/about/the-future-of-learning/&#60;/a&#62;) to be really useful.  &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Does anyone have any recommended texts, thoughts, exercises or tips on how to go about this?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Thanks guys!
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
