<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- generator="bbPress/1.0.2" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Humanities Questions &#38; Answers &#187; Tag: XSLT - Recent Topics</title>
		<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/tags/xslt</link>
		<description>Digital Humanities Questions &amp; Answers &#187; Tag: XSLT - Recent Topics</description>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2013 14:28:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<generator>http://bbpress.org/?v=1.0.2</generator>
		<textInput>
			<title><![CDATA[Search]]></title>
			<description><![CDATA[Search all topics from these forums.]]></description>
			<name>q</name>
			<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/search.php</link>
		</textInput>
		<atom:link href="/rss/tags/xslt/topics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
			 
				<title>Karin Dalziel on "Best way to create COinS or other metadata from TEI using XSLT?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/best-way-to-create-coins-or-other-metadata-from-tei-using-xslt#post-134</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2010 16:31:50 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Karin Dalziel</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">134@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I feel way behind in this area. I have successfully used XSLT to insert in Dublin Core metadata into the header of an HTML page, but I would like to support multiple resources, etc. From looking around, it seems the best format to use is COinS, but the format is a bit more, er, obtuse than dublin core. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Has anyone done this? care to share some sample XSLT? Am I going about this all wrong?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;(Also, I debated whether this should go in metadata or programming. Feel free to chime in on that as well)
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Hayim on "Getting started with XSLT document() ?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/getting-started-with-document#post-1019</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2011 19:20:57 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Hayim</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1019@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I am hoping someone can send me to a good tutorial or working model.&#60;br /&#62;
I am a &#60;strong&#62;rank neophyte&#60;/strong&#62; trying working on a project that will present multiple witnesses to strongly aligned texts, each in a separate xml (TEI) file and each &#38;lt;ab&#38;gt; has a unique xml:id. The alignment is to a central xml file, which links out to the unique IDs.&#60;br /&#62;
For demo purposes, I'd like to be able to use XSLT to pull the corresponding texts from the several files into a single html file. Any advice on how best to get started?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Raskolnikov on "HELP! I need advice on which approach to take with a text encoding project..."</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/help-i-need-advice-on-which-approach-to-take-with-a-text-encoding-project#post-1011</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2011 16:49:53 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Raskolnikov</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1011@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Hi there,&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I desperately need advice at the moment, and really hope some people here can provide some suggestions.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I have a fairly extensive data set in the forms of letters (from the 16th century) which have been encoded in XML.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;My job is to create something which aids content analysis of the letters.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;- This could be a GUI written in Java, which (via SAX or DOM) allows the user to extract certain features from the letters, compare them side by side rather than have to laboriously flick between letters on a computer system.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;- Or it could be an elaborate XML project, where XSLT, HTML hyperlinks, and possibly some type of query language such as XQuery or more likely XPath would be used.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;- Or it could be XML documents displayed in IE and using a JavaScript window/console to select, extract, manipulate, compare different letters.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Does anyone have an opinion or a suggestion on which of the three would be the best option to take?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Thank you very much in advance
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Vika Zafrin on "XSL: sorting based on user input"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/xsl-sorting-based-on-user-input#post-942</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2011 23:56:58 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Vika Zafrin</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">942@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;You know how sometimes you offer to build someone a proof of concept that should take about half an hour, and then it takes days?  I did that.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I have a fairly simple bibliography. I'd like to present it as a web page, and give the user three choices: this list should be sortable by author, year of publication, and title. This choice can be presented as the page is loading (so, to re-sort, one must reload) or as buttons or hyperlinks.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;The stylesheet itself took no time; it's the choice I'm stumped on.  I suspect this can be done fairly trivially with a combination of XSL and JavaScript, but find JavaScript impenetrable.  Been trying off and on for a few days to extrapolate from what I'm finding online, to no avail.  Perhaps you can help, with or without JavaScript?  &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;&#60;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/805081&#34;&#62;Here's the XSL I've got so far&#60;/a&#62;, with some assistance from StackOverflow folk.  Suggestions on how to modify it for choice?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;To summarize: I'd like to use the &#60;code&#62;xsl:sort&#60;/code&#62; with the first three parameters (&#60;code&#62;pSortNameAuth&#60;/code&#62;, &#60;code&#62;pSortNameYear&#60;/code&#62;, &#60;code&#62;pSortNameTitle&#60;/code&#62;) interchangeably, based on user input.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Andrew Jewell on "XSL-FO advice needed"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/xsl-fo-advice-needed#post-216</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2010 15:06:57 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Andrew Jewell</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">216@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I am experimenting with generating well-designed PDF documents from my TEI P5 files, and I could use a little advice if others have worked with XSL-FO in a DH context:&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;1.  I have been using Oxygen and the FOP processor that is packaged with it, but apparently FOP doesn't support certain XSL-FO elements (like &#38;lt;fo:float&#38;gt;).  Have other used alternative processors?  Do they cost?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;2.  Though I have found Dave Pawson's book on XSL-FO useful, and I have consulted with the W3C site on the topic, I have struggled to find other resources to help me when these resources fail (particularly online ones).  Any advice?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Thanks for your help.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Andy Jewell
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Karin Dalziel on "Alternatives to Cocoon?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/alternatives-to-cocoon#post-97</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2010 18:53:14 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Karin Dalziel</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">97@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I have used Cocoon to publish  TEI encoded XML files processed with XSLT (using Saxon), but I have never tried any other method of processing/publishing files. What alternatives are there? For many sites we generally use only a very small subsets of the features in cocoon - some basic redirecting and post processing.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
