<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- generator="bbPress/1.0.2" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Humanities Questions &#38; Answers &#187; Tag: text - Recent Topics</title>
		<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/tags/text</link>
		<description>Digital Humanities Questions &amp; Answers &#187; Tag: text - Recent Topics</description>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 03:55:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<generator>http://bbpress.org/?v=1.0.2</generator>
		<textInput>
			<title><![CDATA[Search]]></title>
			<description><![CDATA[Search all topics from these forums.]]></description>
			<name>q</name>
			<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/search.php</link>
		</textInput>
		<atom:link href="/rss/tags/text/topics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
			 
				<title>johnlaudun on "Methods to process a plain text collection into a bimodal graph..."</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/methods-to-process-a-plain-text-collection-into-a-bimodal-graph#post-1984</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2013 12:24:20 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>johnlaudun</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1984@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I am starting a new project wherein I want to take a closer look at narratives both in terms of topics as well as in terms of morphologies. For the moment, I have narrowed my initial exploration to two collections of treasure legends, one drawn from oral sources (and transcribed by folklorists) and one drawn from materials found on on-line forums. Both collections are, purposefully as I take baby steps here, small: each is only sixteen texts. The texts range in size from 153 to 1025 words for the oral collection and 155-3081 words for the web collection. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I am looking to create a bimodal graph for each of the collections which represents the relationship between the words used in each text, such that I can examine the relationship either between texts, based on words in common, or between words, based on texts in common.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;What I need, I think, is a Python script or some other kind of code/application which will work through each collection of plain text files and generate a CSV or network file of some kind that will let me then work in Gephi or Sci2. I would especially like it if the script would allow me to feed in a stopword list of my choosing.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>cforster on "How to Handle Soft Hyphens in OCR&#039;d PDF?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-to-handle-soft-hyphens-in-ocrd-pdf#post-180</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2010 08:37:23 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>cforster</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">180@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I am using ABBYY Finereader 10.0 to OCR some material I've scanned. I would like to export the result as a PDF with the text &#34;under&#34; the image. Everything seems to be going well, &#60;em&#62;except&#60;/em&#62; the way that soft-hyphens (Finereader calls them &#34;optional hyphens&#34;) are handled in the PDF output. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;While the OCR successfully recognizes most end-of-line hyphens as soft hyphens, when the result is exported to PDF, the word remains split in half and therefore will not appear in search results. For example, if the word &#34;digital&#34; appeared at the end of a line, hyphenated as &#34;digi-tal,&#34; Finereader recognizes the hyphen as a soft hyphen. But if I export to PDF and search for the term &#34;digital&#34; it will not be found (but &#34;digi-&#34; and &#34;tal&#34; would).&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Any thoughts on how to handle this? I could just manually rejoin these words, but that seems absurd. After futzing about for quite awhile, though, I've been unable to find a better solution.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>briancroxall on "What should I read and what software should I use to do textual studies well?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/what-should-i-read-and-what-software-should-i-use-to-do-textual-studies-well#post-1311</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2011 15:58:22 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>briancroxall</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1311@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I'm super excited to be &#34;Introduction to Digital Humanities&#34; this fall. As I've been turning over the course in my mind, I've known that I've wanted to do one or more projects with the students, probably using our special collections, which tend to be quite strong in particular swaths of literature. This week I sat down with &#60;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/#!/LizChaseMARBL&#34;&#62;Liz Chase&#60;/a&#62;, one of our special collections librarians, and brainstormed. We came up with a great project involving &#60;a href=&#34;http://findingaids.library.emory.edu/documents/duffy834/?keywords=duffy&#34;&#62;our holdings of Carol Ann Duffy's notebooks&#60;/a&#62;. In short, we want to do some comparisons between how she writes in her 1999 volume, &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Worlds-Wife-Carol-Ann-Duffy/dp/057119995X/briacrox-20&#34;&#62;The World's Wife&#60;/a&#62;, and her previous volumes. We're interested in thematic material, vocabulary she uses, poetic styles, and so forth. But as I've been working to design the project, I've come to realize that the students' work (to say nothing of my teaching) will be improved by the inclusion of some readings on textual scholarship along these lines. &#60;strong&#62;But I don't know this field at all.&#60;/strong&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;What's more, I've been trying to think about what sort of software we might most profitably use to help push our analysis after creating a dataset of the texts. I'm guessing we'll want to represent word counts, word clouds, line structures, and more. My first thought is &#60;a href=&#34;http://seasr.org/&#34;&#62;SEASR&#60;/a&#62;, but I'm not familiar with the tool and I'm not sure if it's overkill or underkill or totally off the mark. I can always use &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.wordle.net/&#34;&#62;Wordle&#60;/a&#62;, but I would like to have more options. And perhaps if I really knew this field of scholarship then it would be easier for me to know which tools I should be using.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;What I really need, then, is a suggestion of books or articles that I should read so that our class proceeds thoughtfully on the project with an understanding of what's been done in the past. Any tool suggestions would be welcome as well.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Moacir P. de Sá Pereira on "Tips for getting digital versions of texts without scanning or OCR?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/tips-for-getting-digital-versions-of-texts-without-scanning-or-ocr#post-243</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2010 19:46:52 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Moacir P. de Sá Pereira</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">243@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Hi. Half of my question was already answered in &#34;&#60;a href='/topic/when-your-texts-arent-digital-yet#post-106'&#62;When your texts aren't digital (yet),&#60;/a&#62;&#34; but I was wondering if anyone here has any record of success getting digital versions of books without scanning. -- Has anyone, say, written to a publisher and asked for their inhouse pdfs?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I somehow doubt a publishing house (unless it's something like, maybe, Library of America?) would distribute these digital files, but if someone has had success in the past, I'd like to know precisely what stream of words in a letter made the publisher cave.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Thanks,
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>PhDeviate on "When your texts aren&#039;t digital (yet)"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/when-your-texts-arent-digital-yet#post-105</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2010 18:16:54 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>PhDeviate</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">105@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I work in contemporary literature, so almost everything I study is under copyright. Many things I study are available in attenuated digital formats like google books, or kindle editions, but those sorts of formats are not available for doing even a simple text manipulation or visualization, like, say slamming it into Wordle. Other that pushing for available full-access digital editions, what tools are there out there for those times when you find yourself confronted with something that is irredeemably paper?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
