<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- generator="bbPress/1.0.2" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Humanities Questions &#38; Answers &#187; Topic: Best DH Tools For Best Access in Haiti</title>
		<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/best-dh-tools-for-best-access-in-haiti</link>
		<description>Digital Humanities Questions &amp; Answers &#187; Topic: Best DH Tools For Best Access in Haiti</description>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2013 22:12:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<generator>http://bbpress.org/?v=1.0.2</generator>
		<textInput>
			<title><![CDATA[Search]]></title>
			<description><![CDATA[Search all topics from these forums.]]></description>
			<name>q</name>
			<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/search.php</link>
		</textInput>
		<atom:link href="/rss/topic/best-dh-tools-for-best-access-in-haiti" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
			 
				<title>rania on "Best DH Tools For Best Access in Haiti"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/best-dh-tools-for-best-access-in-haiti#post-1121</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2011 08:52:36 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>rania</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1121@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;The post is written in very a good manner and it entails many useful information for me. I am happy to find your distinguished way of writing the post. Now you make it easy for me to understand and implement the concept. Thank you for the post.&#60;br /&#62;
curt&#60;br /&#62;
&#60;a href=&#34;http://www.nicetick.com/nike-vintage-cortez-black-canvas-delicate-images-of-wu-shu.html&#34;&#62;Nike Vintage Cortez&#60;/a&#62;
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Cathyd on "Best DH Tools For Best Access in Haiti"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/best-dh-tools-for-best-access-in-haiti#post-304</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 19:52:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Cathyd</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">304@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;&#60;em&#62;Replying to @laurientaylor@gmail.com's &#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/best-dh-tools-for-best-access-in-haiti#post-300&#34;&#62;post&#60;/a&#62;:&#60;/em&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;&#60;em&#62;Replying to @laurientaylor@gmail.com's &#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/best-dh-tools-for-best-access-in-haiti#post-300&#34;&#62;post&#60;/a&#62;:&#60;/em&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Thank you.  I'll pass your reply on to Laurent Dubois one of the co-directors of our Haiti Lab who asked the question.  I love the specifics and your commitments.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>laurie taylor on "Best DH Tools For Best Access in Haiti"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/best-dh-tools-for-best-access-in-haiti#post-300</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 17:02:14 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>laurie taylor</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">300@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;The model of the Digital Library of the Caribbean (dLOC, &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.dloc.com&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://www.dloc.com&#60;/a&#62;) might be helpful. dLOC is a cooperative digital library for resources from and about the Caribbean and circum-Caribbean and provides access to digitized versions of Caribbean cultural, historical and research materials from archives, libraries, and private collections. Partners include the Archives Nationale d'Haïti, Bibliothèque Nationale d'Haïti, and Bibliothèque Haïtienne des Pères du Saint-Esprit. The dLOC group continually works with issues of access and we'd love to work with you on a Haiti-specific project (you might already know Brooke Wooldridge, the dLOC Coordinator, since she visited Duke fairly recently).&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I'd also strongly agree that questions on the digital divide and access are key to all digital humanities work. The questions are fundamental to concerns on developing support for digital accessibility and machine/system interoperability, as well as for how to do humanities work with changes from digital technologies, which requires a non-reductive approach.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Cathyd on "Best DH Tools For Best Access in Haiti"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/best-dh-tools-for-best-access-in-haiti#post-283</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2010 19:52:09 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Cathyd</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">283@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;A colleague from our Haiti Lab at the Franklin Humanities Institute asked my advice about the best ways to create a library of low res books that students in Haiti can access easily--thumb drives with low resolution pdf's, tagging low data &#34;canonical&#34; texts and archives (literary, historical) from internet cafes, excellent translations between English and Haitian Kreyol, etc.   This is the beginning of a conversation, obviously, but I'm so thrilled for DHAnswers (and delighted you posted this on the HASTAC site) that I thought I'd get this local conversation going for my colleagues by putting it out to our community and collecting and passing on responses. I know that questions of digital divide and digital access are not as key to all work in the Digital Humanities but I also know that many in our community have thought deeply about how we translate work in ways that make it accessible.   Thanks for any ideas, leads, sources, experts, anything anyone wants to contribute to this vital conversation.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
