<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- generator="bbPress/1.0.2" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Humanities Questions &#38; Answers &#187; Topic: Must your tools/projects, esp. in Omeka, meet specific accessibility standards?</title>
		<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/must-your-toolsprojects-esp-in-omeka-meet-specific-accessibility-standards</link>
		<description>Digital Humanities Questions &amp; Answers &#187; Topic: Must your tools/projects, esp. in Omeka, meet specific accessibility standards?</description>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2016 14:10:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<generator>http://bbpress.org/?v=1.0.2</generator>
		<textInput>
			<title><![CDATA[Search]]></title>
			<description><![CDATA[Search all topics from these forums.]]></description>
			<name>q</name>
			<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/search.php</link>
		</textInput>
		<atom:link href="/rss/topic/must-your-toolsprojects-esp-in-omeka-meet-specific-accessibility-standards/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
			 
				<title>hopegreenberg on "Must your tools/projects, esp. in Omeka, meet specific accessibility standards?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/must-your-toolsprojects-esp-in-omeka-meet-specific-accessibility-standards#post-2325</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2015 21:08:12 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>hopegreenberg</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2325@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;&#60;em&#62;Replying to @&#60;a href='/profile/hopegreenberg'&#62;hopegreenberg&#60;/a&#62;'s &#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/must-your-toolsprojects-esp-in-omeka-meet-specific-accessibility-standards#post-2323&#34;&#62;post&#60;/a&#62;:&#60;/em&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Thanks - I'm hoping that's the case too.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Patrick Murray-John on "Must your tools/projects, esp. in Omeka, meet specific accessibility standards?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/must-your-toolsprojects-esp-in-omeka-meet-specific-accessibility-standards#post-2324</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2015 19:27:26 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Patrick Murray-John</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2324@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;There will be more info coming via the Omeka forums, and/or some direct contact as we plan how to publicize the information.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;It was just a few months ago that we got our first request for a VPAT from an institution. The guided a lot of what went into Omeka 2.3, and we're likely to publish the results of that evaluation soon -- just not sure where and how yet in our strategy.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I can say that student-produced work is unlikely to be an issue. The real issue is the themes that are used. That is, Omeka, like other CMSs, happily lets people enter data, then the themes to the lion's share of the work for accessibility. Admittedly, that can cause issues if there is a custom theme that doesn't address accessibility. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;My suspicion, though, is that a VPAT assessment is more likely to be a tool for folks to know what to expect and what not, and what an institution's accessibility office might need to address to make sure content is available to all. That is, I suspect it is more informational that prescriptive for institutions, and that over the long term that information should inform future work.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;That's my guess, though, so definitely want to hear additional info.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>hopegreenberg on "Must your tools/projects, esp. in Omeka, meet specific accessibility standards?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/must-your-toolsprojects-esp-in-omeka-meet-specific-accessibility-standards#post-2323</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2015 14:21:51 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>hopegreenberg</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2323@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I've posted this directly to the Omeka Forum (Feature Requests) but think it may have future impact for many types of DH projects/tools so hope folsk will weigh in:&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Our department (Center for Teaching and Learning) at U of Vermont has a small Omeka space that contains exhibits built by students as part of class projects. (Feel free to take a look: &#60;a href=&#34;http://badger.uvm.edu/omeka/)&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://badger.uvm.edu/omeka/)&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;The university is planning a campus-wide accessibility review of the current use of technology, web-based tools, and public program information related to learning and instruction and campus communications, programs, and information.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;The accessibility review will include examining web-based tools that we support by using the “Voluntary Product Accessibility Template” - the rubric that the federal government uses to ensure that new software products are accessible and will meet the WCAG 2.0 AA standard:&#60;br /&#62;
&#60;a href=&#34;http://www.state.gov/m/irm/impact/126343.htm&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://www.state.gov/m/irm/impact/126343.htm&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;While the planning is still in progress for how the review will be done, the question of our Omeka site has come up, especially since it is built by students and so needs to be accessible both to viewers and builders.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I've searched the Omeka Forums for accessibility information and have found some information about improvements in 2.3 but would like to know if anyone can point me to a more comprehensive list of accessibility features or if the VPAT template linked above has been considered as a guide to future accessibility features.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I would hate to our growing Omeka exhibits get shut down. These are wonderful opportunities for students to create exhibits and collections based on historic documents and objects. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;- Hope
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
