<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- generator="bbPress/1.0.2" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Humanities Questions &#38; Answers &#187; Topic: How to gain DH experience without institutional support</title>
		<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-to-gain-dh-experience-without-institutional-support</link>
		<description>Digital Humanities Questions &amp; Answers &#187; Topic: How to gain DH experience without institutional support</description>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2016 10:16:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<generator>http://bbpress.org/?v=1.0.2</generator>
		<textInput>
			<title><![CDATA[Search]]></title>
			<description><![CDATA[Search all topics from these forums.]]></description>
			<name>q</name>
			<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/search.php</link>
		</textInput>
		<atom:link href="/rss/topic/how-to-gain-dh-experience-without-institutional-support/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
			 
				<title>Jennifer Vinopal on "How to gain DH experience without institutional support"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-to-gain-dh-experience-without-institutional-support#post-2186</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2014 17:47:50 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Jennifer Vinopal</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2186@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Hi. I'm late in responding. You can join the NYCDH community and connect with people that way. &#60;a href=&#34;http://nycdh.org/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://nycdh.org/&#60;/a&#62;&#60;br /&#62;
If you do join, make sure to also then join the NYCDH Announcements group so you can get and send announcement to everyone in the community.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>lmullen on "How to gain DH experience without institutional support"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-to-gain-dh-experience-without-institutional-support#post-2154</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2014 12:02:32 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>lmullen</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2154@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I'll add a second to Patrick's ideas about making data available. Putting the data out there marks you as the owner, both in a copyright sense but more importantly in a scholarly sense. It announces that that particular topic is one that you are working on.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;But it doesn't make that announcement in a &#34;keep your hands off&#34; sort of way. Putting something valuable (i.e., your data) out there means that potential collaborators have a reason to collaborate you. At least my own experience with making data available is that it gives other scholars something to use, and therefore a reason to contribute their own data back to the project.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Along those lines, you might consider making a simple web page for your project. If you are using GitHub anyway, then &#60;a href=&#34;http://pages.github.com/&#34;&#62;GitHub pages&#60;/a&#62; might be worth checking out. A simple web page might not be a digital project itself, but it can go a long way towards finding people to work with.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;What this all adds up to is that if you're in a place without institutional support and without existing connections to DH scholars, you may as well start working on your project and making it public, which can be your means of entrance into the DH community and DH collaboration. Trevor Owens &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.trevorowens.org/2011/07/the-digital-humanities-as-the-diy-humanities/&#34;&#62;writes&#60;/a&#62; that &#34;There is a version of whatever it is that you want to do that you can do right now with only an investment of your time and energy.&#34; Trevor's whole post might be of interest to you.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>trmarvin on "How to gain DH experience without institutional support"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-to-gain-dh-experience-without-institutional-support#post-2153</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 10:40:07 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>trmarvin</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2153@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Patrick, many thanks, I appreciate your advice on this. You've convinced me to go ahead and put the data out there! Once I input it that is, which will take a while. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Great idea about the panel - no knowing anyone very well in the DH community and having little experience thus far I'm not sure where to start, but I'll try.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Patrick Murray-John on "How to gain DH experience without institutional support"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-to-gain-dh-experience-without-institutional-support#post-2152</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2014 15:28:58 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Patrick Murray-John</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2152@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Bonus idea! I suspect that this conversation would be very interesting to many people in similar circumstances. Maybe it's worth a panel discussion at whatever yearly big conference your field has? It's not hard for me to imagine this flying well at AHA or MLA, for example.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Patrick Murray-John on "How to gain DH experience without institutional support"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-to-gain-dh-experience-without-institutional-support#post-2151</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2014 15:14:17 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Patrick Murray-John</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2151@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;&#60;em&#62;Replying to @&#60;a href='/profile/trmarvin'&#62;trmarvin&#60;/a&#62;'s &#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-to-gain-dh-experience-without-institutional-support#post-2150&#34;&#62;post&#60;/a&#62;:&#60;/em&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;That is one of the sticky wickets! No matter what, it would be a bold move, and as such an implicit positioning of yourself in the market. That could obviously go either way, but since there are wide parts of DH that are all about challenging traditional publishing model, it would serve to stake out a place among DHers, and possibly establish DH cred. But yeah, I understand/remember how bold a move that would be!&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;To the details of authorship, I'll skip the copyrightability question of data by assuming it falls into the category of data that reflects significant creative work (as opposed to, say, the phone book). So, your copyright would already be implicitly there by publishing it (I think...we're moving into 'I am not a lawyer' territory!). To make it more solid, researching what license to apply to it would be the next step. &#60;a href=&#34;http://wiki.creativecommons.org/Data_and_CC_licenses&#34;&#62;Creative Commons's page about data&#60;/a&#62; might be a start.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;That wouldn't prevent someone from downloading the data, but presumably you have a head start on working with it for your research questions. If someone were to abuse the license, you'd still have to react to that, but you'd have the tools in place. But, I tend to be optimistic about scholarly integrity in general, and figure that if someone else does publish some results based on your data, they'll include the citation (maybe even reach out for a collaboration, as DH folks tend to do!). Ideally in that situation, they'll produce results/arguments that don't nullify yours. That actually seems likely to me, given the very different directions, methodologies, etc. that can be used on some data.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;So, it is tricky and a little risky. But, if the mission is to have CV lines that say &#34;Digital Humanist&#34;, doing the research to decide on a license and posting the data up would put you deep in some of the important conversations going on in DH, just by adding a CV line that's a link to the dataset. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Hope that helps
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>trmarvin on "How to gain DH experience without institutional support"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-to-gain-dh-experience-without-institutional-support#post-2150</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2014 11:31:52 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>trmarvin</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2150@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;&#60;em&#62;Replying to @Patrick Murray-John's &#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-to-gain-dh-experience-without-institutional-support#post-2149&#34;&#62;post&#60;/a&#62;:&#60;/em&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Patrick, great suggestion re: Github. If I was in a TT (or other secure) position I would do this in a heartbeat. But the reality is I am on the market and this is data I painstakingly collected over several years of research. How do I maintain authorship of it? What do you recommend in this situation?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Patrick Murray-John on "How to gain DH experience without institutional support"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-to-gain-dh-experience-without-institutional-support#post-2149</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2014 16:57:53 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Patrick Murray-John</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2149@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I think the most interesting part is in this phrase from your question: &#34;how do I obtain CV-level involvement (for lack of a better term) in DH projects&#34;.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;What is &#34;CV-level&#34; in DH is a huge, open question, one that DH struggles with all over. It hits on what is accepted as scholarship?, what counts toward tenure? alt-ac careers, and many other questions!&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;So, CV-level? depends on the CV, and what jobs you are applying for. Last time I was job hunting, I had a couple different CVs for different position types. One listed unconferences that I'd attended, and (if applicable) what sessions I'd led. That was in a section under &#34;Conferences&#34;. I think I also had an &#34;Ongoing Projects&#34; or &#34;Development&#34; or some-such thing, where I gave short descriptions and links to stuff I was building or had built.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;That works (depending on the CV/job interaction), but doesn't get to the &#34;plugging away on your own&#34; aspect. I'm all behind the idea of sending an email out, and looking for local DH/hacker communities. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Going that route, I'd also suggest posting your dataset on GitHub, and using whatever networks you can to invite playing and working with that data. If there's a (DH) hackathon you can find in your area that invites data submissions (like &#60;a href=&#34;http://glamhack.com/submitted-challenges/&#34;&#62;GLAMHackPhilly&#60;/a&#62; did recently), that's a great place to make contacts, build up the project, and list the hackathon attendance and submission on your DH-oriented CV -- those non-standard CV lines, and your boldness in using them, will likely be recognized by DHers.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>trmarvin on "How to gain DH experience without institutional support"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-to-gain-dh-experience-without-institutional-support#post-2148</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2014 10:41:37 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>trmarvin</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2148@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Getting to conferences is not a problem as I am traveling to present anyway, and I have been to a number of informative and interesting workshops, etc. What I don't know is how to get from the audience side of DH panels to the maker side. Stéfan, at what stage would you recommend posting on DHCommons? I feel like I need to at least have a prototype up, but right now I'm stuck on figuring out a schema for data entry (let alone entering the data).&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I'm in the NYC metro area (though I'm not in NYC all that frequently) and welcome any connections - thanks for the suggestion. I work in Jewish studies, specifically medieval intellectual history. acrymble - true. Working on it, nothing yet.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>acrymble on "How to gain DH experience without institutional support"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-to-gain-dh-experience-without-institutional-support#post-2147</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2014 13:26:09 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>acrymble</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2147@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;&#60;em&#62;Replying to @&#60;a href='/profile/trmarvin'&#62;trmarvin&#60;/a&#62;'s &#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-to-gain-dh-experience-without-institutional-support#post-2145&#34;&#62;post&#60;/a&#62;:&#60;/em&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;The way I'd go about this is to send someone an email out of the blue and say you want to collaborate with them on a study using your data and their methodology. Be open about the fact that you think what they do is cool but you don't know how to do it (though you're keen to learn). You'll learn so much by working with someone.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;If they say no, who cares?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Stéfan Sinclair on "How to gain DH experience without institutional support"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-to-gain-dh-experience-without-institutional-support#post-2146</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2014 12:34:37 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Stéfan Sinclair</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2146@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;That is indeed a bit of tricky situation, not least because some of the usual strategies for building momentum and community around a project (like travelling to do conference presentations) may not be viable options. If you haven't encountered it already, you may want to poke around &#60;a href=&#34;http://dhcommons.org/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://dhcommons.org/&#60;/a&#62; and even add your own profile and project.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Beyond that, several cities and regions have thriving DH communities that cut across institutions and sectors (that's certainly the case here in Montreal, but I'm thinking also of great initiatives like &#60;a href=&#34;http://dhmakerbus.com/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://dhmakerbus.com/&#60;/a&#62; in London, ON). If you're comfortable letting us know your general geographical location, there may be some connections folks here could help establish.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>trmarvin on "How to gain DH experience without institutional support"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-to-gain-dh-experience-without-institutional-support#post-2145</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2014 11:16:30 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>trmarvin</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2145@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Hello, I'm a freshly minted, traditionally trained humanities Ph.D. interested in DH. I come from a specialized research institution without a DH center, etc. My interest in DH methodologies stems from a data set I collected incidentally while doing my dissertation research, which, I think, could be productively manipulated and, pending results, expanded. I have a decent set of self-taught beginner tech skills and enjoy picking up more when I have the time. I'm aware of the great resources and advice out there for people in my situation, but my question is more specific: without institutional backing, how do I obtain CV-level involvement (for lack of a better term) in DH projects that would allow me to collaborate, learn, and work on a deeper level than just plugging away alone in my (very little) spare time on the server space I purchased out-of-pocket?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Any advice is greatly appreciated.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
