<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- generator="bbPress/1.0.2" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Humanities Questions &#38; Answers &#187; Tag: textual studies - Recent Topics</title>
		<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/tags/textual-studies</link>
		<description>Digital Humanities Questions &amp; Answers &#187; Tag: textual studies - Recent Topics</description>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 05:12:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<generator>http://bbpress.org/?v=1.0.2</generator>
		<textInput>
			<title><![CDATA[Search]]></title>
			<description><![CDATA[Search all topics from these forums.]]></description>
			<name>q</name>
			<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/search.php</link>
		</textInput>
		<atom:link href="/rss/tags/textual-studies/topics" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
			 
				<title>Henry Cowles on "How to find traces of a text (e.g. article) in a more recent one (e.g. chapter)?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-to-find-traces-of-a-text-eg-article-in-a-more-recent-one-eg-chapter#post-1425</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 13:06:26 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Henry Cowles</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1425@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I want to do two different sorts of text comparison, though I suspect the answer for one will apply for the other. Ideally, I'll find a web-based or freeware solution to one or both of the following:&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;1. I want to see how much of an early text (a published article, in this case) was lifted and republished in a later one (a book chapter). Being able to find verbatim reuse of paragraphs, sentences, or even strings of words (&#38;gt;5 or so) would be very useful. Both texts have already been identified (i.e. I don't need to search across texts to find candidates for comparison - though that would be nice for the future!), and the ultimate goal is to highlight, in the more recent text, those portions that came from the earlier one. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;A side interest (which seems like it would follow from the above) would be to find moments were specific words, examples, or references were swapped out for others. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;2. Expanding on the former, I'd like to be able to take the entire set of texts by a given author published before a certain date and find, as before, portions lifted and republished in a text published on that date (a large book, known to have been cobbled together from previous work, for which the MS is unknown and so finding provenance of various passages has proven laborious). Corpus size is obviously larger here, and representing/listing the relevant portions of lifted text is more complicated because they would each be tagged, ideally, as belonging to specific prior texts. Generating a list of passages from the recent text that listed (a) their location in the new text, (b) the earlier text in which they appeared, and (c) their location in the earlier text would be ideal.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Any idea?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Note #1: All the relevant texts are pre-1923 and available in relatively-clean text files (or can be turned into them).&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Note #2: I poked around before posting – the closest thread I found is &#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/best-way-to-display-and-compare-multiple-editions-of-a-songbook-on-the-web#post-1224http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/best-way-to-display-and-compare-multiple-editions-of-a-songbook-on-the-web#post-1224&#34;&#62;this&#60;/a&#62;, though the focus there is music notation.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>neuman on "Please recommend collation software?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/please-recommend-collation-software#post-1557</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2012 17:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>neuman</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1557@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;For a friend who is studying the manuscripts of John Selden, can anyone recommend collation software?  I see that Collate is still in use, and &#60;a href=&#34;http://juxtasoftware.org&#34;&#62;Juxta&#60;/a&#62; looks promising.  Learning of related projects that use the tool and share techniques would also be helpful.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>briancroxall on "What should I read and what software should I use to do textual studies well?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/what-should-i-read-and-what-software-should-i-use-to-do-textual-studies-well#post-1311</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2011 15:58:22 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>briancroxall</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1311@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I'm super excited to be &#34;Introduction to Digital Humanities&#34; this fall. As I've been turning over the course in my mind, I've known that I've wanted to do one or more projects with the students, probably using our special collections, which tend to be quite strong in particular swaths of literature. This week I sat down with &#60;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/#!/LizChaseMARBL&#34;&#62;Liz Chase&#60;/a&#62;, one of our special collections librarians, and brainstormed. We came up with a great project involving &#60;a href=&#34;http://findingaids.library.emory.edu/documents/duffy834/?keywords=duffy&#34;&#62;our holdings of Carol Ann Duffy's notebooks&#60;/a&#62;. In short, we want to do some comparisons between how she writes in her 1999 volume, &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Worlds-Wife-Carol-Ann-Duffy/dp/057119995X/briacrox-20&#34;&#62;The World's Wife&#60;/a&#62;, and her previous volumes. We're interested in thematic material, vocabulary she uses, poetic styles, and so forth. But as I've been working to design the project, I've come to realize that the students' work (to say nothing of my teaching) will be improved by the inclusion of some readings on textual scholarship along these lines. &#60;strong&#62;But I don't know this field at all.&#60;/strong&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;What's more, I've been trying to think about what sort of software we might most profitably use to help push our analysis after creating a dataset of the texts. I'm guessing we'll want to represent word counts, word clouds, line structures, and more. My first thought is &#60;a href=&#34;http://seasr.org/&#34;&#62;SEASR&#60;/a&#62;, but I'm not familiar with the tool and I'm not sure if it's overkill or underkill or totally off the mark. I can always use &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.wordle.net/&#34;&#62;Wordle&#60;/a&#62;, but I would like to have more options. And perhaps if I really knew this field of scholarship then it would be easier for me to know which tools I should be using.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;What I really need, then, is a suggestion of books or articles that I should read so that our class proceeds thoughtfully on the project with an understanding of what's been done in the past. Any tool suggestions would be welcome as well.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
