<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- generator="bbPress/1.0.2" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Humanities Questions &#38; Answers &#187; Tag: copyright - Recent Posts</title>
		<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/tags/copyright</link>
		<description>Digital Humanities Questions &amp; Answers &#187; Tag: copyright - Recent Posts</description>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 06:12:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<generator>http://bbpress.org/?v=1.0.2</generator>
		<textInput>
			<title><![CDATA[Search]]></title>
			<description><![CDATA[Search all topics from these forums.]]></description>
			<name>q</name>
			<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/search.php</link>
		</textInput>
		<atom:link href="/rss/tags/copyright/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
			 
				<title>rebeccaonion on "Need Sounding Board for Copyright/IP Questions"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/need-sounding-board-for-copyrightip-questions#post-1403</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2011 12:06:28 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>rebeccaonion</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1403@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Hey, thanks, everybody (especially Patrick, who is now officially the fairy godfather for this project, having also helped me on the technical side over at Omeka). I will dig through all of this. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;The question of how far down the copyright rabbit hole to take the students in a good one. I was planning on selecting their images myself this semester, given that we're already spending a lot of time in my class on &#34;extra&#34; instruction that's not teaching them the content on the syllabus. (I taught them Zotero, made them use databases for their research, and am requiring them to write these weird-to-them archive entries instead of traditional papers, which is already a tall order for some of them - there are a lot of freshmen in the class - as well as a tall order for me, as an early-career instructor.) I might make this part of the assignment next semester, however. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I may also include on the site a written statement that summarizes my rationale for claiming fair use for the images that I use (I mean, if I pick any that are questionable, which seems inevitable). I'm not sure how much protection that will provide, but I thought I'd seen something similar elsewhere. If anybody has good examples of this, or feedback re: whether this is a good idea, I'd love to hear it.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Dorothea Salo on "Need Sounding Board for Copyright/IP Questions"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/need-sounding-board-for-copyrightip-questions#post-1402</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2011 11:57:31 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Dorothea Salo</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1402@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Rebecca, you might try asking either your campus legal office (I've dealt with campus legal at two-three different institutions, and they've always been fantastic) or at your campus library (which may have a copyright expert internally).&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Is the Omeka project live on the web, or on a private server? The answer may impact the strength of a fair-use analysis. (IANAL, TINLA.)
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>unsworth on "Need Sounding Board for Copyright/IP Questions"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/need-sounding-board-for-copyrightip-questions#post-1401</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2011 11:34:50 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>unsworth</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1401@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Stanford University Libraries and Academic Information Resources (SULAIR) has a great collection of resources on this subject: &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;&#60;a href=&#34;http://fairuse.stanford.edu/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://fairuse.stanford.edu/&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;So does the library at the University of Maryland, more specifically aimed at instructors: &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;&#60;a href=&#34;http://www.umuc.edu/library/libhow/copyright.cfm&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://www.umuc.edu/library/libhow/copyright.cfm&#60;/a&#62;
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Micah Vandegrift on "Need Sounding Board for Copyright/IP Questions"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/need-sounding-board-for-copyrightip-questions#post-1400</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2011 11:34:15 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Micah Vandegrift</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1400@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Here's another one from the &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.copyright.com/Services/copyrightoncampus/basics/fairuse_list.html&#34;&#62;Copyright Clearance Center&#60;/a&#62;. This seems like a great opportunity to teach the students about copyrights in an educational setting and fair use. Also, depending how deep you want to go down this rabbit hole, you could introduce them to Creative Commons; here's &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.sitepoint.com/30-creative-commons-sources&#34;&#62;30+ places to find CC licensed media&#38;gt;&#60;/a&#62;. Also, I'm assuming the students are probably using Google Images to dig up their results - you can filter search results by images with CC Licenses - Google &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/support/websearch/bin/answer.py?&#38;amp;&#38;amp;answer=29508&#34;&#62;outlines it here&#60;/a&#62;. (*hoping I did my HTML right)
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Patrick Murray-John on "Need Sounding Board for Copyright/IP Questions"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/need-sounding-board-for-copyrightip-questions#post-1399</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2011 11:11:38 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Patrick Murray-John</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1399@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Hi,&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;The Center for Social Media has a couple different Fair Use guides, including one tailored to &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.centerforsocialmedia.org/fair-use/related-materials/codes/code-best-practices-fair-use-online-video&#34;&#62;Code of Best Practices in Fair Use for Online Video&#60;/a&#62; that might be helpful.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;&#60;a href=&#34;http://www.law.duke.edu/cspd/comics/&#34;&#62;Bound By Law&#60;/a&#62; from the Center for the Study of the Public Domain is also great reading on the topic, but is aimed more toward documentary producers.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>rebeccaonion on "Need Sounding Board for Copyright/IP Questions"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/need-sounding-board-for-copyrightip-questions#post-1398</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2011 11:03:51 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>rebeccaonion</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1398@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Hi everyone,&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I'm working on an Omeka project with a class, and am concerned about the kinds of images we might be able to include with our item records. The class is about popular culture and childhood, and the students are nominating for inclusion (&#38;amp; writing item records about) objects that were significant to their own experiences with pop cult as kids; this results in an archive full of items like Jersey Shore and Harry Potter which are very much still in copyright. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I know this isn't the right forum for specific questions about copyright, but is there someplace I could turn to get some feedback about this project? I've often wondered whether there might be some entity out there that would offer pro bono advice to people working in education who are worried about committing inadvertent copyright violations.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Thanks.&#60;br /&#62;
Rebecca
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Dorothea Salo on "best practices for sharing TEI code and public/private data dictionaries"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/best-practices-for-sharing-tei-code-and-publicprivate-data-dictionaries#post-1307</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2011 11:13:38 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Dorothea Salo</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1307@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Why would anyone bother to do that, given that your project would already be there, dated and documented? What exactly could they hope to gain?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Paige Morgan on "best practices for sharing TEI code and public/private data dictionaries"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/best-practices-for-sharing-tei-code-and-publicprivate-data-dictionaries#post-1295</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2011 00:32:38 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Paige Morgan</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1295@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Thanks, Patrick. I've been a bit intimidated by Github, but I'll look into it further, and see whether it might serve.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Conal, that's a useful question, thank you. I realize that what I'm concerned about losing is the basic concept as much as anything, and once that's out in public, well, it's out -- someone could use it, and the metadata, to build a version of the project  -- but that doesn't automatically provide them with massive amounts of data. (Whether they could build a program that would automatically retrieve it might be another story.) But the more that I work to publicly establish the project (and the more traditional, less strictly DH critical background behind it), the more recognizable it is as my work.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;This has given me good things to think about -- thanks again, to both of you.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Conal Tuohy on "best practices for sharing TEI code and public/private data dictionaries"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/best-practices-for-sharing-tei-code-and-publicprivate-data-dictionaries#post-1294</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2011 20:16:23 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Conal Tuohy</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1294@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;&#60;em&#62;Replying to @paigecm@uw.edu's &#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/best-practices-for-sharing-tei-code-and-publicprivate-data-dictionaries#post-1292&#34;&#62;post&#60;/a&#62;:&#60;/em&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;It depends what parts of your work you consider your 'IP' and what exactly you stand to lose from describing your methods in public. In other words, what scenarios do you you envisage that you would suffer a loss, and what would you ha ve lost?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Patrick Murray-John on "best practices for sharing TEI code and public/private data dictionaries"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/best-practices-for-sharing-tei-code-and-publicprivate-data-dictionaries#post-1293</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2011 20:11:43 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Patrick Murray-John</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1293@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;One option, though it is a bit techy, might be to use github ( &#60;a href=&#34;https://github.com&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;https://github.com&#60;/a&#62; ). It's mostly thought of as a code repository and versioning system, but it's also hard to ignore what they learned from Flickr about being social and sharing (Their tag-line is &#34;Social Coding&#34;).&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;So, even though it would mean a learning curve of using git and github, it would offer ways to share code -- for a fee you can restrict access, but that'd mean others also having a github account to be able to see it, and you managing that access.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;But it would let you share some things, restrict access to others, and it has a built-in issue system where people could provide feedback.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;It'd also be really nice, I personally think, to see see more extensions of TEI up there. That's solid coding, and could live in a different git repository from the marked up text. With a paid account that'd let you put different permissions on different content.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;This idea isn't really a &#34;best practice&#34; since it isn't tested and assessed. Maybe it's a &#34;radical practice&#34;, which might be more fun.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;HTH&#60;br /&#62;
Patrick
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Paige Morgan on "best practices for sharing TEI code and public/private data dictionaries"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/best-practices-for-sharing-tei-code-and-publicprivate-data-dictionaries#post-1292</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2011 19:18:32 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Paige Morgan</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1292@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I'm working on a long-term database project involving literature and economics, in which I'm gathering price data from a wide range of 18th and 19th century English texts.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;On my project website, I have an editorial statement and FAQ designed to provide context for the project both for people who are familiar with lit./econ. studies, and less so. I don't want to give away my IP, so most of the project itself is walled off. But I'm at the stage where I'm going to be looking for interested collaborators, and so I'd like to put as much on display as possible while protecting my work. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;With that in mind, I'm trying to make a decision about whether to share a sample entry with full TEI markup. It's important, I think, that I show how my work uses the current TEI guidelines; especially because in a couple of areas, I'm extending them to meet the needs of my data. That brings me to the data dictionary, and the question of whether to make it visible, so that people can see my rationale for the choices I've made.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I could password protect some parts of the site, and maintain a certain amount of control over who can access it that way, but that doesn't provide a lot of security, and to be truthful, I'd prefer to have the site open, so that someone who found it could explore without having to contact me first.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I looked back through previous posts, and though I found acknowledgments that code is often kept out of the public eye, I didn't find any clear statements regarding the fine balance between making code public as a way of illustrating that you know what you're doing; and sharing too much.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Anyone have any recommendations? And thanks, very much, in advance.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Ben Brumfield on "Who follows best practices re: restrictions on digitized public domain works?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/who-follows-best-practices-re-restrictions-on-digitized-public-domain-works#post-760</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2010 17:35:33 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Ben Brumfield</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">760@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;&#60;em&#62;Replying to @Bethany Nowviskie's &#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/who-follows-best-practices-re-restrictions-on-digitized-public-domain-works#post-759&#34;&#62;post&#60;/a&#62;:&#60;/em&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Thanks, Bethany!  One really important thing I should mention is that despite my frustration determining policy, I &#60;em&#62;was&#60;/em&#62; able to do what I wanted with the material, and that that use (high-quality scans of 800+ pages) was something I never would have been legally able to do with a Footnote.com or such.  I consider the money well spent, and appreciate the flexibility during my dialog with the digitization service.  UVa's service was a welcome contrast with the Clements Library at University of Michigan, whose &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.clements.umich.edu/Hours.html&#34;&#62;policies and fees&#60;/a&#62; were so forbidding that I didn't even bother inquiring.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Bethany Nowviskie on "Who follows best practices re: restrictions on digitized public domain works?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/who-follows-best-practices-re-restrictions-on-digitized-public-domain-works#post-759</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2010 17:15:31 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Bethany Nowviskie</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">759@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;&#60;em&#62;Replying to @Ben Brumfield's &#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/who-follows-best-practices-re-restrictions-on-digitized-public-domain-works#post-755&#34;&#62;post&#60;/a&#62;:&#60;/em&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Ben, (putting on my work hat) I just want to thank you for laying out the ambiguities and contradictions you found in our policies. I'm sharing your post with folks at UVa connected to our Digitization Services, Special Collections, and Collections Steering groups.  I know that work is already well underway to create more helpful, clear, and (I think) liberating access and use guidelines for digital content, but I'm sure your experience can still help inform those conversations.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;And Dorothea, wow -- thanks for that citation!
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Dorothea Salo on "Who follows best practices re: restrictions on digitized public domain works?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/who-follows-best-practices-re-restrictions-on-digitized-public-domain-works#post-758</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2010 16:55:26 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Dorothea Salo</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">758@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Thanks for the clarification, Ben. Much appreciated.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;This might be an opportune moment to point out Eschenfelder and Caswell's &#60;em&#62;First Monday&#60;/em&#62; article &#60;a href=&#34;http://firstmonday.org/htbin/cgiwrap/bin/ojs/index.php/fm/article/view/3060/2640&#34;&#62;Digital Cultural Collections in an Age of Reuse and Remixes&#60;/a&#62;.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Ben Brumfield on "Who follows best practices re: restrictions on digitized public domain works?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/who-follows-best-practices-re-restrictions-on-digitized-public-domain-works#post-755</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2010 13:50:27 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Ben Brumfield</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">755@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Dorothea, I'm pretty sure that James is referring to British law, which &#60;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bridgeman_Art_Library_v._Corel_Corp.#Relevance_to_U.K._law&#34;&#62;seems to be diverging from Bridgeman v. Corel&#60;/a&#62;. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I've had a couple of experiences recently scrutinizing US-based digitized public-domain documents from different organizations.  While I can't really say what might constitute best-practices, I certainly have opinions one what I liked and disliked about each of them:&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Footnote.com includes this statement in its &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.footnote.com/termsandconditions/&#34;&#62;Terms of Use&#60;/a&#62;:&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;blockquote&#62;&#60;p&#62;Footnote.com does not claim a copyright to images already in the public domain that it has then converted into a digital format. However, through agreements we have obtained, and may continue to obtain, certain images or documents that are protected by copyrights or that, even if in the public domain, are subject to restrictions on reuse. Unless such specific restrictions apply, we encourage Members to reproduce public domain images from the Website for their own personal use. By agreeing to these Terms of Service, however, you agree to limit your reuse and republication of such public domain images to small portions of the Footnote collection. For purposes of this paragraph, a &#34;small portion&#34; means a limit of no more than 200 images per year. If you republish public domain images, you agree to credit Footnote.com as the source of the digital image, unless additional specific restrictions apply. If you wish to republish more than a small portion of the Footnote.com collection, you agree to obtain prior written permission from us.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;/blockquote&#62;
&#60;p&#62;While I might wish that the terms for republication were more generous, there are some very specific things that they're doing right:&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;ol&#62;
&#60;li&#62;No &#60;a href=&#34;http://ragesoss.com/blog/2009/01/30/libraries-and-copyfraud/&#34;&#62;copyfraud&#60;/a&#62; -- they explicitly deny possessing copyright over PD documents.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;The attribution clause is clear-cut.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;There's a bail-out clause in the &#34;prior written permission&#34; section.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;Best of all, they provide a &#60;em&#62;specific number-per-year&#60;/em&#62; to let the user know whether their republication will comply with the agreement or not.  As a result, I was able to figure out whether &#60;a href=&#34;http://beta.fromthepage.com/display/read_work?ol=c_work_list_work&#38;amp;work_id=12&#34;&#62;republishing a Civil War-era letter&#60;/a&#62; was allowed, with no ambiguity.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;/ol&#62;
&#60;p&#62;My other recent experience was in paying the University of Virginia library to scan a 19th-century manuscript in their special collections.  Since I was planning to put the diary images online for transcription and since I was paying $300 out of my own pocket for the scanning work, I really wanted to make sure that I wouldn't be bound by any agreements not to re-publish the images.  &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;This was a more frustrating experience, I'm afraid.  The library posts a number of its policies online, but they're hard to reconcile with each other.  The &#60;a href=&#34;http://www2.lib.virginia.edu/digitalcuration/use_of_materials.html&#34;&#62;Digitization Services &#34;Use of Materials&#34; policy&#60;/a&#62; states: &#34;Reproductions of materials obtained from Digitization Services (or from its web site) may be made without prior permission only for use in the research, teaching, or private study of the recipient of the reproduction. Reproductions ... may not be further reproduced without permission.  The recipient agrees ... to secure permission in advance from Digitization Services to publish or broadcast any item, in whole or in part, from its collections.&#34;  Is putting the scans online for transcription private study or publishing?  The statement also directs users to the &#60;a href=&#34;http://www2.lib.virginia.edu/small/using/use_of_materials_policy.html&#34;&#62;Special Collections &#34;Use of Materials Policy&#34;&#60;/a&#62; which says &#34;It is not necessary to seek the Library’s permission as the owner of the physical work to publish or otherwise distribute portions of texts or individual images (up to 20 from any given work or collection) for educational or scholarly purposes.&#34;  Other use policies mention a fee of $100 per image for commercial use&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;All of that seemed a bit high-handed, given that 1) the manuscript was in the public domain as an unpublished work whose author died in 1882, 2) I'm paying to have the thing scanned, and 3) I'm doing so in collaboration with members of the author's family who are already irate about the document being &#34;locked away in a library&#34; in the first place.  However, the &#60;a href=&#34;https://tracksys.lib.virginia.edu/request&#34;&#62;Digitization Services request form&#60;/a&#62; included a bail-out clause: &#34;I understand and agree to the above copyright statement and will only use the digitized resources as I indicate in my online request.&#34;  I was able to describe exactly how I intended to use the images, and happily the further steps in the web form even allowed me to select &#34;publishing on the web&#34; as an option for use.  As a result, I was able to continue with the project feeling that the library had agreed to my planned use (rather than me having to agree to its restrictions), and have been delighted by the scans.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;These are just a couple of experiences from the perspective of an amateur local history researcher.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
