<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- generator="bbPress/1.0.2" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Humanities Questions &#38; Answers &#187; Tag: wiki - Recent Posts</title>
		<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/tags/wiki</link>
		<description>Digital Humanities Questions &amp; Answers &#187; Tag: wiki - Recent Posts</description>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 10:28:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<generator>http://bbpress.org/?v=1.0.2</generator>
		<textInput>
			<title><![CDATA[Search]]></title>
			<description><![CDATA[Search all topics from these forums.]]></description>
			<name>q</name>
			<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/search.php</link>
		</textInput>
		<atom:link href="/rss/tags/wiki" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
			 
				<title>Arno Bosse on "Best DH project-management system?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/best-dh-project-management-system#post-2336</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 05:04:20 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Arno Bosse</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2336@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Returning to this since there are now a lot (and when I say &#34;a lot&#34;... &#60;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Comparison_of_project_management_software)&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Comparison_of_project_management_software)&#60;/a&#62; of web-based options for project management out there.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I've started testing Active Collab (&#60;a href=&#34;https://www.activecollab.com/features.html&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;https://www.activecollab.com/features.html&#60;/a&#62;) and would be grateful for feedback from anyone else who has used this. I'd also love to hear about first hand experience with other alternatives now that 4 years have passed since the question was first posted.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>elotroalex on "Mapping historic sites - MediaWiki?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/mapping-historic-sites-mediawiki#post-1929</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 14:19:56 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>elotroalex</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1929@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Hi Kaia,&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;As far as I know you won't find a wiki solution to this because wikis are just webpages. In order to do what you are doing, you would need to transition to a database solution. I would recommend an &#60;a href=&#34;http://omeka.org/&#34;&#62;Omeka&#60;/a&#62;/&#60;a href=&#34;http://neatline.org/&#34;&#62;Neatline&#60;/a&#62; combo. You will be able to use 'items' to make the nuanced distinctions you want to make. Omeka/Neatline is of course not the only option available to you. Another solution would be to build your maps separate from your encyclopedic compendium, using links to connect them back and forth. Hope that helps.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Kaia on "Mapping historic sites - MediaWiki?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/mapping-historic-sites-mediawiki#post-1921</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 17:02:41 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Kaia</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1921@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;We're working on a wiki for our local history, and my dream is to come up with a feature to help sort out mapping questions - if some citation says something was one door south of something else (in 1960) it can be quite difficult to unpack what the address (or general location even) actually was. In my ideal world, each business could have its own article, with a field for the address, and the end result could be a map that would show each article with an address. There are, of course, cases where addresses have changed as buildings have been torn down and rebuilt, split into two, combined, etc., but a map view would seem to make some of that matter less.&#60;br /&#62;
How would I go about this? Is it possible, or am I dreaming? The maps extensions for MediaWiki I've look at seem to be geared toward displaying maps on article pages.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Wally Grotophorst on "Microsoft access on sharepoint to create database ultimately destined 4 website?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/microsoft-access-on-sharepoint-to-create-database-ultimately-destined-4-website#post-1414</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2011 15:57:05 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Wally Grotophorst</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1414@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;If you're willing to spend between $79-$99 you'll find that Navicat for MySQL makes it trivial to import an Excel spreadsheet or CSV into a MySQL databse.  As an added bonus, it's a great tool for working with the data as well: exporting, reporting, querying, etc.  $79 for Mac and Linux, $99 for Windows.  &#60;a href=&#34;http://navicat.com&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://navicat.com&#60;/a&#62;
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>georginalgreen@gmail.com on "Microsoft access on sharepoint to create database ultimately destined 4 website?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/microsoft-access-on-sharepoint-to-create-database-ultimately-destined-4-website#post-1411</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2011 16:45:54 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>georginalgreen@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1411@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Thanks everyone! The relational nature of the database is key to the research -we are trying to uncover complex, unforeseen patterns of membership, publication, etc. I am looking into MySql and ways to remotely access the MySql server or perhaps enter data offline to be synced once network access is available.&#60;br /&#62;
Thanks for your input it reassured me that I might be right to doubt the access / sharepoint solution. I'll look into all your suggestions and let you know how we get on.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Stéfan Sinclair on "Microsoft access on sharepoint to create database ultimately destined 4 website?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/microsoft-access-on-sharepoint-to-create-database-ultimately-destined-4-website#post-1409</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2011 20:11:46 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Stéfan Sinclair</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1409@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Depending on the complexity of your database you might want to consider using Google Spreadsheets with &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/google-d-s/forms/&#34;&#62;Google Forms&#60;/a&#62;. You wouldn't have the possibility of establishing relationships between tables, but you could do field validation and constraints (through pull-down menus, etc.).&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I suspect ultimately you'll need to build a custom web-based interface for the database anyway, and that could be query Spreadsheets through the API or you can migrate all the data into something like MySQL or SQLite. The real strength of Google Forms would be a free, collaborative platform for data entry.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Alternatively, you might want to try something like &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.zoho.com/creator/create-online-database.html&#34;&#62;Zoho&#60;/a&#62; (I haven't tried it for databases).
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>georginalgreen@gmail.com on "Microsoft access on sharepoint to create database ultimately destined 4 website?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/microsoft-access-on-sharepoint-to-create-database-ultimately-destined-4-website#post-1408</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2011 15:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>georginalgreen@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1408@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;&#60;em&#62;Replying to @Patrick Murray-John's &#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/microsoft-access-on-sharepoint-to-create-database-ultimately-destined-4-website#post-1407&#34;&#62;post&#60;/a&#62;:&#60;/em&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Hello,&#60;br /&#62;
Thanks for the suggestions so far. I will look into them. Sharepoint was a suggestion as it is being used by another (pretty different) project at the uni. My concerns are the same as yours!&#60;br /&#62;
There would be a lot of manual entry -taken from a lot of handwritten sources, for example. I think we are committed to a conventional relational database, but I will look into the wiki idea. I was thinking of using MySql via a GUI (none of us are up to it without a GUI for inserts). I am uncertain how to access the database from a variety of locations.  I also think we maybe should have data collection databases which we then merge somehow into a master database ultimately.&#60;br /&#62;
What do you think? Any tips appreciated.&#60;br /&#62;
Thank you!
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Patrick Murray-John on "Microsoft access on sharepoint to create database ultimately destined 4 website?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/microsoft-access-on-sharepoint-to-create-database-ultimately-destined-4-website#post-1407</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2011 10:50:46 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Patrick Murray-John</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1407@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;One specific question I have (after agreeing that Sharepoint doesn't sound like the ticket) is how the information would be coming in from the various archives? That is, are you looking at a lot of manual entry, or importing via OAI-PMH, or some other mechanism. My hunch is that that will be very big factor in what tool or platform will work best, perhaps even more important than the factors of displaying and sharing the information once it has been populated.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Arno Bosse on "Microsoft access on sharepoint to create database ultimately destined 4 website?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/microsoft-access-on-sharepoint-to-create-database-ultimately-destined-4-website#post-1406</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2011 04:12:02 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Arno Bosse</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1406@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I concur that Access is not a good choice. At Chicago my group former Humanities Computing group hosted a similar sounding project developed by the university library: Libraries and Archives in South Asia (LASA): &#60;a href=&#34;https://coral.uchicago.edu:8443/display/lasa/Home&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;https://coral.uchicago.edu:8443/display/lasa/Home&#60;/a&#62; &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;As you can see LASA is built around a wiki. It is a database, certainly, but a database whose content is exposed in a format that allows others to (optionally) contribute their own data, easily share results, search through the contents by keywords or browse it by facets, subscribe to an RSS feed of recent changes and so on. As you can see, by putting the content in a wiki you get a lot of very useful, user directed features 'for free'. The LASA wiki is built on Atlassian Confluence (&#60;a href=&#34;http://www.atlassian.com/software/confluence/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://www.atlassian.com/software/confluence/&#60;/a&#62;) which is a commercial wiki. I feel Confluence is by far the most feature rich and easiest to use wiki solution available today but it's not free (or even cheap..) and setting it up requires a fair amount of hardware resources.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;My advice is still to build your resource as a wiki but to do this with a free and technically less demanding solution such as Dokuwiki (&#60;a href=&#34;http://www.dokuwiki.org/dokuwiki)&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://www.dokuwiki.org/dokuwiki)&#60;/a&#62;. I personally don't recommend MediaWiki (even though it is far better known) since to me, at least, it is cryptic and unfriendly to use, difficult to extend and maintain and hasn't (to my knowledge) seen any significant updates in some time. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;One potentially significant downside of a wiki-as-a-database approach to your task is that just as a wiki excels in helping you organize and share relatively unstructured data you will have a harder time of it than with a traditional database in exporting this data into a structured context afterwards. So, for example, while it should not be too difficult to move from eg. DokuWiki to another wiki, much more manual intervention will likely be required to move your content from DokuWiki to say another database. Without more background on your specific task and audience I can't properly say more to this but my gut instinct is that this won't actually matter.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Dorothea Salo on "Microsoft access on sharepoint to create database ultimately destined 4 website?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/microsoft-access-on-sharepoint-to-create-database-ultimately-destined-4-website#post-1405</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2011 18:19:48 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Dorothea Salo</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1405@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Almost certainly not. Access is well-known for falling over dead given any significant load (either via size of database or number of simultaneous accesses), and it doesn't play nicely with non-Microsoft technology (such as what runs most of the Web).&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;What were you thinking Sharepoint/Access would do for you? Perhaps the DH hivemind can suggest a stabler, opener alternative.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>georginalgreen@gmail.com on "Microsoft access on sharepoint to create database ultimately destined 4 website?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/microsoft-access-on-sharepoint-to-create-database-ultimately-destined-4-website#post-1404</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2011 13:04:21 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>georginalgreen@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1404@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;We are at the very start of a project which will populate a relational database with information from archives across the world. There will be three people working on the database and ultimately we want it to be openly available and searchable as an online research tool. Would Microsoft access on sharepoint be a good way of facilitating the collaborative research?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>larrycebula@gmail.com on "Best DH project-management system?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/best-dh-project-management-system#post-471</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2010 14:42:52 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>larrycebula@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">471@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Wow--I had no idea there were so many alternatives. And I am surprised not to see Google Groups or Windows Live groups listed. Why not those? They are simple, familiar, and fairly powerful.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Miriam Posner on "Best DH project-management system?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/best-dh-project-management-system#post-466</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 21:08:50 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Miriam Posner</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">466@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;&#60;em&#62;Replying to @Stéfan Sinclair's &#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/best-dh-project-management-system#post-432&#34;&#62;post&#60;/a&#62;:&#60;/em&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I hear you about face-to-face meetings, I really do, but I'm getting to the point (and I know this is near-universal) where I just can't keep track of all the stuff I and others are supposed to be doing, in my head or on a spreadsheet. And I'd really like other people to have a way of keeping track of their own responsibilities without relying on me to nag them. Plus, we can't keep switching among Gmail, Outlook, Dropbox, Google Docs, various text-editor to-do lists, Remember the Milk, and all the janky spreadsheets I've cobbled together. It's getting unmanageable and we've had a few near-missed deadlines and dropped balls, just because we can't get our stories or documents straight.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Integrating Basecamp, Trac, and Subversion sounds promising -- I noticed that's &#60;a href=&#34;http://blog.projectlocker.com/articles/2008/04/03/basecamp-integration-is-here&#34;&#62;a possibility&#60;/a&#62;.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Wayne Graham on "Best DH project-management system?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/best-dh-project-management-system#post-463</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 19:35:43 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Wayne Graham</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">463@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;&#60;em&#62;Replying to @&#60;a href='/profile/jason'&#62;Jason&#60;/a&#62; Boyd's &#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/best-dh-project-management-system#post-460&#34;&#62;post&#60;/a&#62;:&#60;/em&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;One technique I've employed in the past in smaller projects has been a simple whiteboard on wheels. Everybody could see what tasks needed to be completed, and it was redrawn on a weekly basis (with tasks crossed off as we went). This also had the nice side effect of people not interrupting the developers. As a general tip, make sure you provide developers with lots of uninterrupted time to do their work. Nothing kills productivity like being interrupted for a meeting in the middle of working through a complex piece of code. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;There's more, but I'll post on your other question as to not cross streams here...
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Jason Boyd on "Best DH project-management system?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/best-dh-project-management-system#post-460</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 16:10:39 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Jason Boyd</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">460@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;&#60;em&#62;Replying to @Stéfan Sinclair's &#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/best-dh-project-management-system#post-432&#34;&#62;post&#60;/a&#62;:&#60;/em&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;In the case where the project team works in close proximity together, and a collaborative project workflow management tool would be a distraction, how does the project manager manage? The one downside to face-to-face communication is it can easily lead to a highly informal communication environment where effective reporting and documentation of workflow and the management of that reporting and documentation can be a real problem for the project manager. To ask the original question somewhat differently, 'What are the best tools/techniques to help a DH project manager do his or her job?'
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
