<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- generator="bbPress/1.0.2" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Humanities Questions &#38; Answers &#187; Tag: analysis - Recent Topics</title>
		<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/tags/analysis</link>
		<description>Digital Humanities Questions &amp; Answers &#187; Tag: analysis - Recent Topics</description>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2016 09:17:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<generator>http://bbpress.org/?v=1.0.2</generator>
		<textInput>
			<title><![CDATA[Search]]></title>
			<description><![CDATA[Search all topics from these forums.]]></description>
			<name>q</name>
			<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/search.php</link>
		</textInput>
		<atom:link href="/rss/tags/analysis/topics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
			 
				<title>MelissaTerras on "Computational analysis of perspective in Paintings/art?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/computational-analysis-of-perspective-in-paintingsart#post-1269</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 09:31:17 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>MelissaTerras</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1269@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Hi folks. I wondered if anyone had come across any research that uses computational methods to look at perspective in art, such as in renaissance oil paintings, or foreshortening in sculpture, etc. I am sure there is a method to do this, but not sure if anyone has applied it to a corpus of paintings to understand the artist's use of perspective better. If you have any pointers at all I'd be glad to hear about them.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Thanks! &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Melissa
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>materialculture on "How to analyze &#38; record CIELAB or Munsell notations of colors in digital images?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-to-analyze-record-cielab-or-munsell-notations-of-colors-in-digital-images#post-1482</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2011 18:28:26 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>materialculture</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1482@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I know photo editing software can analyze color and display CIELAB and Munsell color identification notations for selected image areas.  Is there a tool (preferably open source) that will analyze and identify the colors in a digital image, and create an output file recording those colors in CIELAB or Munsell notation?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>briancroxall on "What should I read and what software should I use to do textual studies well?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/what-should-i-read-and-what-software-should-i-use-to-do-textual-studies-well#post-1311</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2011 15:58:22 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>briancroxall</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1311@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I'm super excited to be &#34;Introduction to Digital Humanities&#34; this fall. As I've been turning over the course in my mind, I've known that I've wanted to do one or more projects with the students, probably using our special collections, which tend to be quite strong in particular swaths of literature. This week I sat down with &#60;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/#!/LizChaseMARBL&#34;&#62;Liz Chase&#60;/a&#62;, one of our special collections librarians, and brainstormed. We came up with a great project involving &#60;a href=&#34;http://findingaids.library.emory.edu/documents/duffy834/?keywords=duffy&#34;&#62;our holdings of Carol Ann Duffy's notebooks&#60;/a&#62;. In short, we want to do some comparisons between how she writes in her 1999 volume, &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Worlds-Wife-Carol-Ann-Duffy/dp/057119995X/briacrox-20&#34;&#62;The World's Wife&#60;/a&#62;, and her previous volumes. We're interested in thematic material, vocabulary she uses, poetic styles, and so forth. But as I've been working to design the project, I've come to realize that the students' work (to say nothing of my teaching) will be improved by the inclusion of some readings on textual scholarship along these lines. &#60;strong&#62;But I don't know this field at all.&#60;/strong&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;What's more, I've been trying to think about what sort of software we might most profitably use to help push our analysis after creating a dataset of the texts. I'm guessing we'll want to represent word counts, word clouds, line structures, and more. My first thought is &#60;a href=&#34;http://seasr.org/&#34;&#62;SEASR&#60;/a&#62;, but I'm not familiar with the tool and I'm not sure if it's overkill or underkill or totally off the mark. I can always use &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.wordle.net/&#34;&#62;Wordle&#60;/a&#62;, but I would like to have more options. And perhaps if I really knew this field of scholarship then it would be easier for me to know which tools I should be using.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;What I really need, then, is a suggestion of books or articles that I should read so that our class proceeds thoughtfully on the project with an understanding of what's been done in the past. Any tool suggestions would be welcome as well.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Miriam Posner on "Drupal modules for displaying data"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/drupal-modules-for-displaying-data#post-636</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2010 12:54:34 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Miriam Posner</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">636@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;So I know someone (I swear, it's not me) who has collected a bunch of data from a bunch of survey respondents in a bunch of formats: PDF, Word docs, spreadsheets. Some of it is quantitative, some of it is narrative. There's about 150 pages of it. So kind of not a best-case scenario.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;What he'd like to do is display this (anonymized) data on a website for the benefit of the community from which it was collected. He's already obtained consent. He'd like to be able to display the data by anonymized &#34;person&#34; (i.e., by profile), but also allow for the possibility of some rudimentary analysis or visualization (e.g., how many of these respondents are female? how many are both female and of this ethnicity?)&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;My hunch is that he's best off using Drupal + CCK + Views. I have warned him that he has a lot of data-entry and a steep learning curve ahead of him. Important caveat: he does not know any programming languages. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;So my questions are these:&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;• Do you agree that Drupal is his best option?&#60;br /&#62;
• If Drupal is the way to go, are there modules that make sense for collecting, displaying, and visualizing this kind of information?&#60;br /&#62;
• Can you recommend particularly good books or other resources for this use of Drupal?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Thank you, as always.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Eric Johnson on "Has anybody written a history of the digital humanities?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/has-anybody-written-a-history-of-the-digital-humanities#post-558</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2010 17:15:26 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Eric Johnson</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">558@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I've often found myself wondering if anybody has written a book-length narrative history telling the story of humanities computing/digital humanities from the early days of humanities computing until now (or some approximation thereof), addressing major milestone DH projects, related efforts, and some of the big themes of the field as they've evolved--or haven't--over time?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I suspect that some histories may have been done that address particular disciplines (e.g. digital history), but have they been tied together and examined as a whole?  I see that the question has been addressed in conference presentations, such as those by &#60;a href=&#34;http://infomotions.com/blog/tag/digital-humanities/&#34;&#62;Joe Raben&#60;/a&#62; or &#60;a href=&#34;http://infomotions.com/blog/2010/05/cyberinfrastructure-days-at-the-university-of-notre-dame/&#34;&#62;Stéfan Sinclair&#60;/a&#62;, and appears in Chapter 1 of Schreibman et al.'s &#34;&#60;a href=&#34;http://www.digitalhumanities.org/companion/&#34;&#62;A Companion to Digital Humanities&#60;/a&#62;,&#34; but I wondered if anything longer has been published.  I may well have just sailed right past it.  Seems like it would make a great oral history project, too.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
