<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- generator="bbPress/1.0.2" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Humanities Questions &#38; Answers &#187; Tag: databases - Recent Topics</title>
		<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/tags/databases</link>
		<description>Digital Humanities Questions &amp; Answers &#187; Tag: databases - Recent Topics</description>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 05:12:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<generator>http://bbpress.org/?v=1.0.2</generator>
		<textInput>
			<title><![CDATA[Search]]></title>
			<description><![CDATA[Search all topics from these forums.]]></description>
			<name>q</name>
			<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/search.php</link>
		</textInput>
		<atom:link href="/rss/tags/databases/topics" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
			 
				<title>Miriam Posner on "What are people using to manage large collections of images?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/what-are-people-using-to-manage-large-collections-of-images#post-2307</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 19:05:22 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Miriam Posner</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2307@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I'm curious to know what software humanities scholars are using to wrangle large collections of images. I often encounter scholars who struggle to manage large image collections — it's not at all unusual to find people managing collections of historical images with iPhoto — and wondered if there are databases that make sense for visual collections. I'm especially interested in programs that:&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;ul&#62;
&#60;li&#62;work out of the box and have a GUI (sorry)&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;are designed for individuals, not enterprises&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;allow a scholar to quickly apprehend many images at once&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;allow one to add metadata (like place and date) — something beyond tags would be nice — and construct queries&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;make sense for people who have a lot of digital surrogates of primary sources (which is to say, systems that are optimized to retrieve the EXIF data from a photo of an archival document won't make a whole lot of sense)&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;/ul&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I know about Picasa, LightRoom, and ImagePlot. I don't think an enterprise-level system like ContenDM or the like makes sense for individual scholars. Omeka, of course, is nice, but it's a bit unwieldy if you're just trying to manage a collection. What am I missing?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>jennriley on "How do you want full text provided to you for analysis?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-do-you-want-full-text-provided-to-you-for-analysis#post-1893</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2013 21:02:25 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>jennriley</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1893@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;We're in the early planning stages of an initiative that will make available full text for some of our special collections library's manuscript holdings. We'll definitely provide a search interface, but we'd also like to allow the full text of these resources to be downloaded for researchers to use in text mining and whatever other applications suit their fancy. As a researcher doing this kind of work, what's the most useful way for us to make this full text available to you? One big download? Something else? Are there examples out there of sites that do this particularly well that we should model our capabilities after?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Thanks for your input!&#60;br /&#62;
Jenn
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>boybot16@gmail.com on "Have you used MongoDB for DH project?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/have-you-used-mongodb-for-dh-project#post-1850</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2013 11:19:42 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>boybot16@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1850@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;We have a DH project that's currently uses MySQL for the database, and it works very well.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;There has been much recent talk about NoSQL databases, particularly MongoDB, promising flexibility and scalability. We're considering re-writing the backend. Is anyone in the DH community seriously using MongoDB?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;If you have used MongoDB for a DH project, what has been your experience with it? Biggest joy? Gotchas to look out for? Is conversion worth it for libraries and archives open source projects?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>georginalgreen@gmail.com on "Microsoft access on sharepoint to create database ultimately destined 4 website?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/microsoft-access-on-sharepoint-to-create-database-ultimately-destined-4-website#post-1404</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2011 13:04:21 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>georginalgreen@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1404@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;We are at the very start of a project which will populate a relational database with information from archives across the world. There will be three people working on the database and ultimately we want it to be openly available and searchable as an online research tool. Would Microsoft access on sharepoint be a good way of facilitating the collaborative research?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
