<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- generator="bbPress/1.0.2" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Humanities Questions &#38; Answers &#187; Tag: open source - Recent Topics</title>
		<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/tags/open-source</link>
		<description>Digital Humanities Questions &amp; Answers &#187; Tag: open source - Recent Topics</description>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 06:43:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<generator>http://bbpress.org/?v=1.0.2</generator>
		<textInput>
			<title><![CDATA[Search]]></title>
			<description><![CDATA[Search all topics from these forums.]]></description>
			<name>q</name>
			<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/search.php</link>
		</textInput>
		<atom:link href="/rss/tags/open-source/topics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
			 
				<title>dot.porter on "Virtual Lightbox? (or, what are some good image comparison tools?)"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/virtual-lightbox-or-what-are-some-good-image-comparison-tools#post-2002</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2013 09:01:16 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>dot.porter</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2002@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I'm looking for a server-side tool I can use to compare some images. I'm familiar with the Virtual Lightbox at MITH (&#60;a href=&#34;http://mith.umd.edu/lightbox/)&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://mith.umd.edu/lightbox/)&#60;/a&#62;, but according to the site it hasn't been touched since 2004 and I'm wondering if there is anything newer that does the same kind of thing.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Stéfan Sinclair on "Licenses and IP Agreements for DH Projects"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/licenses-and-ip-agreements-for-dh-projects#post-1956</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 15:31:03 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Stéfan Sinclair</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1956@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I'm wondering if any of you folks would be willing to share custom (software or content) licenses as well as IP agreements for your DH projects. I'm especially interested in what licenses people are using for code and why, as well as IP agreements that are used with research assistants, staff and other researchers. I'll post a few examples that we've used in a separate message below, but I'd be grateful to hear what others have been doing and why (as applicable).
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>DigitalHumanitiesScholar on "Accessibility, open access etc - Recommended articles and papers?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/accessibility-open-access-etc-recommended-articles-and-papers#post-1937</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 08:36:52 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>DigitalHumanitiesScholar</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1937@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I am looking for any recommendations regarding literature (freely available online) about accessibility (re written work, art and so on), Open Access and related topics (scholarship, journals etc).&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Thanks!
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>dh.donoralibrary@gmail.com on "User-friendly, open-source/free latent semantic indexing?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/any-user-friendly-open-sourcefree-lsi-software-for-public-library-use#post-1469</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 17:32:39 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>dh.donoralibrary@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1469@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I would like to use LSI (latent semantic indexing) to provide access within the public library to a local history collection which I have been scanning (usually newspaper pages or clippings; using the Paper Port software which came with our Brother all-in-one scan/fax/copy machine).&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;While I've read the &#34;right tool(s)for an archive of newspaper columns&#34; post, I do not have copyright clearance for the scanned material, nor do I seek to put it online, as most of the suggested tools seem to do. DevonThink seems to be out, as we're strictly Windows(including a few 7's)-- no Macs.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;We're also perpetually broke (who isn't?), and unlikely to spend anything on this project, including renting IT help--have none in-house. Although I'm motivated to do the text cleanup of the scanned corpus, I'm not too tech-savvy, nor am I a mathematician. (I have a bad case of English-major-brain; it gets all fuzzy somewhere around the word &#34;vector&#34;). I still hope we can transcend our limitations and those of keyword indexing. Any help?  Any suggestions? Thanks! DH
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Jennifer Sano-Franchini on "Suggestions for open source frameworks for web development?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/suggestions-for-open-source-protocols-for-web-development#post-981</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2011 14:54:34 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Jennifer Sano-Franchini</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">981@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I'm looking for a fairly user-friendly open source protocol for developing a web-based project that basically combines organized, user-contributed links (kind of like an online bibliography) with tagging capabilities and discussion boards. It would be great if I could develop something easy for users to navigate, as the site would be geared toward college-level writing students and instructors.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Right now I'm looking at Drupal and BuddyPress, and I'm also thinking to use APIs, possibly from delicious, Mendeley, and I'm interested in looking into OpenCalais for pulling metadata from the linked sources. But, I'm really new to all of this and I'm wondering if anyone else has any other suggestions of tools that I might look into using--?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>tanyaclement on "Are there essential reads on the open source movement and humanities research?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/are-there-essential-reads-on-the-open-source-movement-and-humanities-research#post-844</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2010 11:35:32 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>tanyaclement</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">844@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I'm looking for articles or books on the affect or use or impact of the open source movement in software development on research in the humanities.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Bethany Nowviskie on "Experience to share on DH data curation, FOSS/OA advocacy?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/experience-to-share-on-dh-data-curation-fossoa-advocacy#post-785</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2010 15:55:05 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Bethany Nowviskie</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">785@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;In December 2010, the Outreach Committee of the ACH (Association for Computers and the Humanities) will draft open letters to the funders of digital humanities projects, advocating for the establishment of data curation or management plans and open source / open access guidelines for grant-funded DH.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;We will share drafts of the letters for public comment before circulating them to funders.  In the meantime, we're hoping you'll help inform the process by sharing your ideas and examples below -- positive or negative -- of the relationship of digital humanities projects to open source, open access, and data curation or management. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;We've also set up a Google Doc which can be edited anonymously: &#60;a href=&#34;http://is.gd/i6DNw&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://is.gd/i6DNw&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;What should we be sure to address in these letters?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Many thanks on behalf of the ACH Outreach Committee,&#60;br /&#62;
Bethany Nowviskie
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Jeremy Boggs on "Recommentations for open-source GIS software?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/recommentations-for-open-source-gis-software#post-75</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2010 15:48:57 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Jeremy Boggs</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">75@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I've been using ArcGIS for a project, but am interesting in running some open-source alternative. I use a Mac, but am interested in recommendations for open-source GIS software for any platform? Anyone have suggestions?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
