<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- generator="bbPress/1.0.2" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Humanities Questions &#38; Answers &#187; Topic: 3D Printers</title>
		<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/3d-printers</link>
		<description>Digital Humanities Questions &amp; Answers &#187; Topic: 3D Printers</description>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2015 10:45:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<generator>http://bbpress.org/?v=1.0.2</generator>
		<textInput>
			<title><![CDATA[Search]]></title>
			<description><![CDATA[Search all topics from these forums.]]></description>
			<name>q</name>
			<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/search.php</link>
		</textInput>
		<atom:link href="/rss/topic/3d-printers" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
			 
				<title>Jentery Sayers on "3D Printers"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/3d-printers#post-2008</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2013 19:12:13 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Jentery Sayers</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2008@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I just want to echo what Devon wrote --- so clearly and accurately --- three days ago (tho I will confess I haven't used the Ultimaker). And I agree: the Make Mag roundup is a fantastic reference. I was quite surprised by it, in the best possible way.  &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;At the MLab, we've been using The Replicator Dual. Consensus seems to be that the Replicator 2 is a better bet, especially because of the shift from ABS to PLA. Also, on the Dual, the heated build plate is not ideal. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;You might also want to consider modelling, prototyping, and editing software. We've been using a combination of 123D Catch, Mudbox, SketchUp, netfabb, and MeshLab. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Hope this helps!
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Devon Elliott on "3D Printers"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/3d-printers#post-2007</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2013 17:11:34 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Devon Elliott</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2007@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I've recently been using the Makerbot Replicator 2 quite a bit, and haven't had any problems with it. The high quality setting results in nice prints, and their latest MakerWare software is easy-to-use. If you're looking for a printer that prints well, out-of-the-box with little in the way of calibration and maintenance, I recommend it. What calibration it does require is done on-board, via a small LCD screen and simple push-button interface. You don't need the machine tethered to computer, as it prints easily off an SD card. It only prints in PLA -- so if you were hoping to print in ABS, you'll want to look at a different machine with a heated build platform. I like printing in PLA more than with ABS for a number of reasons. I thin the Makerbot is the easiest to get into printing things -- the machine works with only a minor calibration (levelling the build platform) and the software is hassle-free. The print quality is also among the best I've seen among a variety of machines &#38;gt;$3000.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;The Ultimaker is another one I've seen very good quality prints come from, and it's also quite fast at printing. Documentation is a bit less for it, and you can get it as a kit to assemble. For the best quality prints (at least in the example I saw), extra pieces had to first be printed on the printer, and then added to the machine to tighten some parts up. The results were outstanding, though -- very high quality prints. &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.ultimaker.com/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://www.ultimaker.com/&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;We've liked using 3D printer kits. In the past, we used Makerbot kits that always went together well, were well-documented, and printed fine. Makerbot seems to have moved on fromt he kit business, though, so for kits, we've been building Printrbots. We've been using the Printrbot Jr., a small printer that only works with PLA, and is about $400. The print-quality is decent, particularly at that price point. They're releasing an even smaller kit for $299, and they have larger models as well. The Printrbot Jr. also folds up flat, so it's easier to pack up and take places. &#60;a href=&#34;http://printrbot.com/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://printrbot.com/&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Make Magazine published a roundup of 3D printers within the past year. It offers a good comparison of various models of printers, and also includes some tips on using them and some helpful workflows for both printing and imaging things. &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.makershed.com/Ultimate_3D_Printer_Buyer_s_Guide_p/mkbk4.htm&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://www.makershed.com/Ultimate_3D_Printer_Buyer_s_Guide_p/mkbk4.htm&#60;/a&#62;
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Stéfan Sinclair on "3D Printers"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/3d-printers#post-2006</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2013 19:49:51 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Stéfan Sinclair</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2006@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Thanks to &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.poweredbyosteons.org/&#34;&#62;Kristina Killgrove&#60;/a&#62; for &#60;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/DrKillgrove/status/335089915438190592&#34;&#62;answering on Twitter&#60;/a&#62; to @&#60;a href='/profile/ethanwatrall'&#62;ethanwatrall&#60;/a&#62;'s echo of my question about 3D printing, pointing to these posts: &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.poweredbyosteons.org/search/label/3D%20Printing&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://www.poweredbyosteons.org/search/label/3D%20Printing&#60;/a&#62;
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Stéfan Sinclair on "3D Printers"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/3d-printers#post-2001</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2013 15:39:52 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Stéfan Sinclair</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2001@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;3D printing is evolving at a breakneck speed with decent machines becoming available at affordable prices. I'd be very grateful for any recommendations from people who have shopped for or deployed 3D printers recently in the context of DH. I wish I could say more about the planned usage, but I guess it's best to say that it's meant to be versatile. I'm imagining something in the $2-10k range though that could changed based on desirable features. My current point of reference is something like a &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.makerbot.com/&#34;&#62;MakerBot&#60;/a&#62;. Thanks in advance!
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
