<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- generator="bbPress/1.0.2" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Humanities Questions &#38; Answers &#187; Tag: publishing - Recent Posts</title>
		<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/tags/publishing</link>
		<description>Digital Humanities Questions &amp; Answers &#187; Tag: publishing - Recent Posts</description>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 07:41:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<generator>http://bbpress.org/?v=1.0.2</generator>
		<textInput>
			<title><![CDATA[Search]]></title>
			<description><![CDATA[Search all topics from these forums.]]></description>
			<name>q</name>
			<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/search.php</link>
		</textInput>
		<atom:link href="/rss/tags/publishing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
			 
				<title>kevin.s.hawkins on "What exists as an open platform for editorial management?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/what-exists-as-an-open-platform-for-editorial-management#post-1990</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2013 19:37:44 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>kevin.s.hawkins</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1990@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;In fact, when configuring a journal in OJS, there's an option to say that the OJS is used only for submissions and editorial management but not for actually publishing the journal.  This prevents the &#34;current issue&#34; and &#34;archives&#34; links from appearing in the interface, confusing readers.  See &#60;a href=&#34;http://journal.tei-c.org/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://journal.tei-c.org/&#60;/a&#62; for an example of an OJS instance that is used for managing submissions but not for actually publishing issues.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Here is a list of things that at one point or another struck me as covering editorial management.  Many are not open-source, but I'll let you sort through for anything of interest:&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;ul&#62;
&#60;li&#62;&#60;a href=&#34;http://www.bepress.com/edikit.html&#34;&#62;EdiKit&#60;/a&#62; (being rebranded as &#34;Digital Commons Publishing&#34;)&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;&#60;a href=&#34;http://highwire.org/publishers/benchpress.dtl&#34;&#62;Bench&#38;gt;Press&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;&#60;a href=&#34;http://www.epress.ac.uk/&#34;&#62;epress&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;&#60;a href=&#34;http://www.editorialmanager.com/homepage/home.htm&#34;&#62;Editorial Manager and Preprint Manager&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;&#60;a href=&#34;http://www.subs-espere.org/&#34;&#62;Espere&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;&#60;a href=&#34;http://library.queensu.ca/webir/planning/e-journal_publishing_support.htm&#34;&#62;http://library.queensu.ca/webir/planning/e-journal_publishing_support.htm&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;&#60;a href=&#34;https://jscholarship.library.jhu.edu/handle/1774.2/32737?show=full&#34;&#62;A Survey and Evaluation of Open-Source Electronic Publishing Systems&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;&#60;a href=&#34;http://www.ejpress.com/&#34;&#62;eJournal Press&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;&#60;a href=&#34;http://scholarone.com/&#34;&#62;ScholarOne&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;&#60;a href=&#34;http://www.editorialmanager.com/homepage/home.htm&#34;&#62;Aries Editorial Manager&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;/ul&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>johnlaudun on "What exists as an open platform for editorial management?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/what-exists-as-an-open-platform-for-editorial-management#post-1983</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2013 15:48:51 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>johnlaudun</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1983@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I don't know about the two WordPress solutions -- though I have been really, really impressed with all the things that can be done, and done well, with WordPress in general -- but I'd like to echo the Open Journal software and its cousins (Open Conference et al.). I've been on the reviewing side of the setup, as well as someone who reads a number of open access journals published using the OJS setup, and I have to say it is very close to painless. Easy to use. Nice outputs.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Dorothea Salo on "What exists as an open platform for editorial management?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/what-exists-as-an-open-platform-for-editorial-management#post-1982</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 21:31:25 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Dorothea Salo</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1982@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;For WordPress, look into the Atahualpa and Montezuma themes, both of which are specialized for publishing workflows. (Read &#60;a href=&#34;http://blogs.cetis.ac.uk/philb/2012/03/13/cetis-publications-now-on-wordpress/&#34;&#62;an account of publishing with Atahualpa&#60;/a&#62;.) Having tangled with and bounced off Montezuma, I can say that there's a significant learning/customization curve, but whether it's worth climbing for you is yours to answer.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;If PressForward ever gets out of vaporware stage, it too is likely to be worth looking at.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;If you want to move to Drupal, there's an &#60;a href=&#34;http://journal.code4lib.org/articles/5913&#34;&#62;excellent article in Code4lib Journal&#60;/a&#62; you should read.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Trevor Munoz on "What exists as an open platform for editorial management?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/what-exists-as-an-open-platform-for-editorial-management#post-1979</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 20:56:02 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Trevor Munoz</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1979@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;You could look into using an instance of Open Journal Systems, an open source management system for peer reviewed journals from the Public Knowledge Project. You'd want it essentially just for its backend management systems not for actually publishing the journal since that's happening through Wordpress. The OJS site and documentation can be found here: &#60;a href=&#34;http://pkp.sfu.ca/?q=ojs&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://pkp.sfu.ca/?q=ojs&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Of course, then you have two systems to manage and support.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Jason Heppler on "What exists as an open platform for editorial management?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/what-exists-as-an-open-platform-for-editorial-management#post-1978</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 20:51:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Jason Heppler</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1978@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I'm looking into platforms that can be used as an editorial management system for a project I'm providing assistance with. I'm working with a faculty member who is publishing reviews of dissertations with WordPress. The challenge he and his co-editor are having is with their system for keeping track of editors, people contacted for review, and the state reviews are in. They have a large editorial team assigned to specific historical fields, who work directly in finding reviewers and soliciting reviewees. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;What they're running up against is tracking all these people. They currently are using Google Spreadsheets to track who has been contacted, who needs contacting, if someone's been contacted and declined review, if someone's been contacted and wants to be reviewed but needs a follow-up, tracking the state of review drafts, and so on. But it's starting to be a pinch point (part of the problem is different field editors can potentially contact the same reviewee or reviewer -- they want something more unified that anyone can query and track statuses). Short of building their own database system to track everyone, are there other solutions that already exist in managing people and content for journals? I've looked at system like Annotum and Edit Flow, but I don't think they're quite what they need. It doesn't need to be built on top of WordPress, either. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Any thoughts? Would Drupal serve as a better alternative? Should we build something from the ground-up?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Joel Kalvesmaki on "How create a real (with page numbers) index of journal&#039;s entire run, from PDFs?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-create-a-real-with-page-numbers-index-of-journals-entire-run-from-pdfs#post-1913</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 14:22:39 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Joel Kalvesmaki</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1913@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;You could try indexing software such as &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.pdfindexgenerator.com/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://www.pdfindexgenerator.com/&#60;/a&#62;. But it sounds as if the level of quality and detail to which you aspire would be best handled not so much by software but by hiring a professional indexer who already uses such software and can write a strong index in a timely manner. Of course, if you have more time than money, this may not be feasible.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>olaf on "How create a real (with page numbers) index of journal&#039;s entire run, from PDFs?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-create-a-real-with-page-numbers-index-of-journals-entire-run-from-pdfs#post-1911</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2013 20:25:43 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>olaf</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1911@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;&#60;em&#62;Replying to @&#60;a href='/profile/olaf'&#62;olaf&#60;/a&#62;'s &#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-create-a-real-with-page-numbers-index-of-journals-entire-run-from-pdfs#post-1910&#34;&#62;post&#60;/a&#62;:&#60;/em&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;The OCR idea seems to be a bust, unfortunately. It's a pain to convert to a &#34;flat&#34; file without renderable text. Then, even the newest version of Acrobat is finding it difficult to understand diacritics, italics and anything else non-standard. I think I'll be better off working with mistakes that follow a regular pattern (such as a≠ always equals ā) and working on a script or something to do mass replacements.&#60;br /&#62;
Don't know why Adobe doesn't allow OCR of files with renderable text in them. What could be the harm?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>olaf on "How create a real (with page numbers) index of journal&#039;s entire run, from PDFs?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-create-a-real-with-page-numbers-index-of-journals-entire-run-from-pdfs#post-1910</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2013 19:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>olaf</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1910@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;&#60;em&#62;Replying to @Peter Organisciak's &#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-create-a-real-with-page-numbers-index-of-journals-entire-run-from-pdfs#post-1909&#34;&#62;post&#60;/a&#62;:&#60;/em&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Thanks for the tips.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Not automated. Just more convenient, and perhaps with some automated features to help with the actual index creation.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I hadn't thought of running any OCR on the older files, since I made them many years ago from the original Word or Nisus files (i.e., they were never scanned or OCRed), but that's a great idea that I'm about to try. Don't know if OCR will ignore the text that's already 'live' though, or if I'll have to flatten them first.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I'll definitely take a stroll through the research and see what I can find.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Peter Organisciak on "How create a real (with page numbers) index of journal&#039;s entire run, from PDFs?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-create-a-real-with-page-numbers-index-of-journals-entire-run-from-pdfs#post-1909</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2013 18:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Peter Organisciak</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1909@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;&#60;em&#62;Replying to @&#60;a href='/profile/olaf'&#62;olaf&#60;/a&#62;'s &#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-create-a-real-with-page-numbers-index-of-journals-entire-run-from-pdfs#post-1908&#34;&#62;post&#60;/a&#62;:&#60;/em&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I believe you're looking for an automated way to create a back-of-the-book index, correct? 'Indexing' tends to refer to building indices for information retrieval (such as Terrier and Lucene's PDF parsers), which is why you couldn't find it on Google.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Back-of-the-book indexes are tough to parse. Patrick Juola wrote about the need for such software and the technical challenges in &#60;a href=&#34;http://llc.oxfordjournals.org/content/23/1/73.full?sid=f01a5ee3-2477-4711-8fff-d42916eead6d&#34;&#62;Killer Applications for Digital Humanities&#60;/a&#62;. If I recall, he had early work in the area: I'm not sure what came of it. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I don't know if there is any software that would do what you need. However, since it's a tough problem, you can be sure that researchers have tried it. Your best bet is to look through the research literature and see if any researchers have released their code. A scholar search for 'back-of-the-book indexing' along with keywords like 'unsupervised', 'semi-supervised', or 'automated' gave me some potentially useful articles. Still, you'd probably have to split the problem into two parts — parsing PDFs to text and generating an index — as I suspect there aren't any tools mature enough t include PDF parsing.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;To be honest, your approach of going through manually and highlighting notable terms sounds more tractable to me. With the OCR problems: have you tried re-applying text recognition on the older issues with the newest version of Acrobat Professional? Their OCR improves often.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Sorry that I don't have a better answer for you. Good luck.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>olaf on "How create a real (with page numbers) index of journal&#039;s entire run, from PDFs?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-create-a-real-with-page-numbers-index-of-journals-entire-run-from-pdfs#post-1908</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2013 18:21:41 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>olaf</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1908@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;One more wish for the wishlist: a way to designate a term as fitting into more than one topic in the index. For example, al-Zahir Baybars would be indexed as himself and under &#34;sultans&#34;.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>olaf on "How create a real (with page numbers) index of journal&#039;s entire run, from PDFs?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-create-a-real-with-page-numbers-index-of-journals-entire-run-from-pdfs#post-1907</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2013 18:09:23 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>olaf</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1907@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;&#60;em&#62;Replying to @Dorothea Salo's &#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-create-a-real-with-page-numbers-index-of-journals-entire-run-from-pdfs#post-1905&#34;&#62;post&#60;/a&#62;:&#60;/em&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I mean a real index, not a concordance. The need to leave out passing mentions is one of the reasons that no software will be able to automate the process.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>olaf on "How create a real (with page numbers) index of journal&#039;s entire run, from PDFs?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-create-a-real-with-page-numbers-index-of-journals-entire-run-from-pdfs#post-1906</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2013 18:07:37 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>olaf</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1906@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;One thing I've been playing with today is going through a pdf and using the highlight tool on words/phrases, in the hope that I can then export the comments list (which has page numbers) to some format I can work with. Doesn't work very well for the older issues with the messy fonts, since you can't always tell what the word was supposed to be (Ṣubḥ becomes ˝ubh˝S and maqāmah becomes maqa≠mah or mah≠maqa, and words with lots of diacritics become almost unrecognizable as words). Those fonts were on long-dead Macs running OS7-OS9, so aren't available to me now.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Dorothea Salo on "How create a real (with page numbers) index of journal&#039;s entire run, from PDFs?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-create-a-real-with-page-numbers-index-of-journals-entire-run-from-pdfs#post-1905</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2013 17:59:59 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Dorothea Salo</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1905@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I'm confused. Are you making a concordance (list of words/phrases present in text with pointers), or an index (synthesized list of important terminology, with pointers to meaningful mentions while omitting passing ones)? They're not at all the same thing.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>olaf on "How create a real (with page numbers) index of journal&#039;s entire run, from PDFs?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-create-a-real-with-page-numbers-index-of-journals-entire-run-from-pdfs#post-1904</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2013 17:57:10 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>olaf</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1904@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I need to index all back issues of &#60;em&#62;&#60;a href=&#34;http://mamluk.uchicago.edu&#34;&#62;Mamluk Studies Review&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/em&#62; (open access, now digital only but formerly print) but have not had much luck finding ideas about how to go about it.&#60;br /&#62;
Searching the Web for info about indexing PDFs leads largely to results about indexing them on a computer for improved searches, or to indexing services.&#60;br /&#62;
I hope to find software (or scripts or something!) that can &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;ul&#62;
&#60;li&#62;read PDF files&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;understand the idea of page numbers&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;understand that each page in a pdf is a distinct entity&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;handle Unicode and diacritics (and, ideally, Arabic script)&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;see phrases or hyphenated words that break across pages as single items&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;/ul&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I don't expect anything to happen automatically: I know I (or better yet an unwary grad student) will have to actually go through and mark words and phrases to be included in the index.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Bonus points if it can be taught to ignore certain strings when alphabetizing. For example, since 'al-' is Arabic for 'the', it doesn't affect alphabetization (so al-Nasir Muhammad goes in the N section).&#60;br /&#62;
Similarly, there needs to be a way to instruct it that ā and a are the same for purposes of alphabetization, as are ṣ and s, etc.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Super bonus points if it can recognize (or learn to recognize) variations on a word or phrase in terms of spelling (often inconsistent when transliteration is involved), word order or intervening words.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;What I have: 23 issues of the journal as whole-book pdfs, as well as individual pdfs of all articles. Unfortunately, the first half dozen or so were created without Unicode, using proprietary fonts with non-standard encodings. Messy, but I can work around it somehow. I also have InDesign files (various versions) for about half the issues. This will all be done in Windows (32-bit XP and 64-bit 7). I always have the latest version of Acrobat (not reader, the full program).&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;The resulting index will be posted on the Web, probably both as a PDF and in some more dynamic and usable format(s). &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Any ideas for ways to streamline this would be appreciated. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Thanks!&#60;br /&#62;
Olaf
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Bethany Nowviskie on "Support for a multi-media poetry translation website?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/support-for-a-multi-media-poetry-translation-website#post-1577</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2012 12:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Bethany Nowviskie</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1577@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Depending on your ambitions for a project like this, many digital humanities centers would need some outside support in order to assist with a effort by someone outside their home institutions.  &#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/im-considering-a-move-to-the-chicago-area-whats-the-dh-scene-like-there&#34;&#62;Start-up funding&#60;/a&#62; from an NEH grant, for instance, would help.  And regional &#60;a href=&#34;http://thatcamp.org&#34;&#62;THATCamp&#60;/a&#62; events are often excellent places to meet up with faculty and staff from DH centers, publishers, humanities agencies, and cultural heritage institutions and find out about opportunities to collaborate.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;You may also want to register on the new &#60;a href=&#34;http://dhcommons.org/&#34;&#62;DH Commons site&#60;/a&#62;, which is designed for people seeking collaborators or offering collaborative opportunities.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;If you are looking for publishing platforms or journals that support multi-media work, you should consider &#60;a href=&#34;http://mediacommons.futureofthebook.org/&#34;&#62;MediaCommons&#60;/a&#62; and &#60;a href=&#34;http://vectors.usc.edu/journal/index.php?page=Introduction&#34;&#62;Vectors&#60;/a&#62;.  The Vectors team is also working on a new digital publishing tool, &#60;a href=&#34;http://scalar.usc.edu/anvc/?page_id=6&#34;&#62;Scalar&#60;/a&#62;.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
