<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- generator="bbPress/1.0.2" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Humanities Questions &#38; Answers &#187; Tag: long-term projects - Recent Posts</title>
		<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/tags/long-term-projects</link>
		<description>Digital Humanities Questions &amp; Answers &#187; Tag: long-term projects - Recent Posts</description>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 04:03:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<generator>http://bbpress.org/?v=1.0.2</generator>
		<textInput>
			<title><![CDATA[Search]]></title>
			<description><![CDATA[Search all topics from these forums.]]></description>
			<name>q</name>
			<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/search.php</link>
		</textInput>
		<atom:link href="/rss/tags/long-term-projects" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
			 
				<title>Dorothea Salo on "best practices for sharing TEI code and public/private data dictionaries"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/best-practices-for-sharing-tei-code-and-publicprivate-data-dictionaries#post-1307</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2011 11:13:38 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Dorothea Salo</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1307@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Why would anyone bother to do that, given that your project would already be there, dated and documented? What exactly could they hope to gain?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Paige Morgan on "best practices for sharing TEI code and public/private data dictionaries"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/best-practices-for-sharing-tei-code-and-publicprivate-data-dictionaries#post-1295</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2011 00:32:38 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Paige Morgan</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1295@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Thanks, Patrick. I've been a bit intimidated by Github, but I'll look into it further, and see whether it might serve.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Conal, that's a useful question, thank you. I realize that what I'm concerned about losing is the basic concept as much as anything, and once that's out in public, well, it's out -- someone could use it, and the metadata, to build a version of the project  -- but that doesn't automatically provide them with massive amounts of data. (Whether they could build a program that would automatically retrieve it might be another story.) But the more that I work to publicly establish the project (and the more traditional, less strictly DH critical background behind it), the more recognizable it is as my work.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;This has given me good things to think about -- thanks again, to both of you.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Conal Tuohy on "best practices for sharing TEI code and public/private data dictionaries"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/best-practices-for-sharing-tei-code-and-publicprivate-data-dictionaries#post-1294</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2011 20:16:23 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Conal Tuohy</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1294@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;&#60;em&#62;Replying to @paigecm@uw.edu's &#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/best-practices-for-sharing-tei-code-and-publicprivate-data-dictionaries#post-1292&#34;&#62;post&#60;/a&#62;:&#60;/em&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;It depends what parts of your work you consider your 'IP' and what exactly you stand to lose from describing your methods in public. In other words, what scenarios do you you envisage that you would suffer a loss, and what would you ha ve lost?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Patrick Murray-John on "best practices for sharing TEI code and public/private data dictionaries"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/best-practices-for-sharing-tei-code-and-publicprivate-data-dictionaries#post-1293</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2011 20:11:43 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Patrick Murray-John</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1293@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;One option, though it is a bit techy, might be to use github ( &#60;a href=&#34;https://github.com&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;https://github.com&#60;/a&#62; ). It's mostly thought of as a code repository and versioning system, but it's also hard to ignore what they learned from Flickr about being social and sharing (Their tag-line is &#34;Social Coding&#34;).&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;So, even though it would mean a learning curve of using git and github, it would offer ways to share code -- for a fee you can restrict access, but that'd mean others also having a github account to be able to see it, and you managing that access.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;But it would let you share some things, restrict access to others, and it has a built-in issue system where people could provide feedback.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;It'd also be really nice, I personally think, to see see more extensions of TEI up there. That's solid coding, and could live in a different git repository from the marked up text. With a paid account that'd let you put different permissions on different content.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;This idea isn't really a &#34;best practice&#34; since it isn't tested and assessed. Maybe it's a &#34;radical practice&#34;, which might be more fun.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;HTH&#60;br /&#62;
Patrick
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Paige Morgan on "best practices for sharing TEI code and public/private data dictionaries"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/best-practices-for-sharing-tei-code-and-publicprivate-data-dictionaries#post-1292</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2011 19:18:32 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Paige Morgan</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1292@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I'm working on a long-term database project involving literature and economics, in which I'm gathering price data from a wide range of 18th and 19th century English texts.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;On my project website, I have an editorial statement and FAQ designed to provide context for the project both for people who are familiar with lit./econ. studies, and less so. I don't want to give away my IP, so most of the project itself is walled off. But I'm at the stage where I'm going to be looking for interested collaborators, and so I'd like to put as much on display as possible while protecting my work. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;With that in mind, I'm trying to make a decision about whether to share a sample entry with full TEI markup. It's important, I think, that I show how my work uses the current TEI guidelines; especially because in a couple of areas, I'm extending them to meet the needs of my data. That brings me to the data dictionary, and the question of whether to make it visible, so that people can see my rationale for the choices I've made.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I could password protect some parts of the site, and maintain a certain amount of control over who can access it that way, but that doesn't provide a lot of security, and to be truthful, I'd prefer to have the site open, so that someone who found it could explore without having to contact me first.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I looked back through previous posts, and though I found acknowledgments that code is often kept out of the public eye, I didn't find any clear statements regarding the fine balance between making code public as a way of illustrating that you know what you're doing; and sharing too much.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Anyone have any recommendations? And thanks, very much, in advance.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
