<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- generator="bbPress/1.0.2" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Humanities Questions &#38; Answers &#187; Tag: Omeka - Recent Topics</title>
		<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/tags/omeka</link>
		<description>Digital Humanities Questions &amp; Answers &#187; Tag: Omeka - Recent Topics</description>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 13:07:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<generator>http://bbpress.org/?v=1.0.2</generator>
		<textInput>
			<title><![CDATA[Search]]></title>
			<description><![CDATA[Search all topics from these forums.]]></description>
			<name>q</name>
			<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/search.php</link>
		</textInput>
		<atom:link href="/rss/tags/omeka/topics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
			 
				<title>zachwhalen on "Best approaches for using DC fields to describe physical computing components?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/best-approaches-for-using-dc-fields-to-describe-physical-computing-components#post-2095</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2013 22:03:37 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>zachwhalen</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2095@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Hi,&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I've got my students working on an assignment where we take apart old media devices, learn about their key components, and then create an Omeka exhibit about our device, using Neatline to trace each component in time and space. This part works pretty well, so far.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;For example, I'm taking apart an Atari VCS. The MOS 6507 CPU bears the MOS technologies logo so was probably (I've learned) manufactured at their plant in Norristown, PA. The TIA chip, on the other hand, has a Synertek logo which (I've learned) second-sourced many of the integrated circuits used by Atari. Even though Atari's TIA chip (the famous Stella) was originally fabricated by MOS in Pennsylvania, &#60;em&#62;mine&#60;/em&#62; was produce at Synertek in California. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;My problem is, I want to capture that kind of distinction in my record, but I'm not sure how to use Omeka's Dublin Core fields to describe everything that I find interesting about these chips, including those differences in production sites. My understanding of DC is pretty basic -- for example, does it make a distinction between &#34;The TIA Chip&#34; as a class of objects exhibiting uniform properties, vs. &#34;My TIA Chip&#34; which has a specific origin in time and place? &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;In other words, is Synertek the &#34;creator&#34;, &#34;publisher&#34;, or &#34;source&#34;? And what does &#34;coverage&#34; mean?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Am I over-thinking this? Are there better ontologies for this kind of archive?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I welcome any and all suggestions. Thanks for your time.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Zach
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>mdalmau on "Who&#039;s using the Zotero-plugin for displaying bibliographic collections in Omeka?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/whos-using-the-zotero-plugin-for-displaying-bibliographic-collections-in-omeka#post-1868</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 11:06:01 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>mdalmau</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1868@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Using Omeka for discovery of bibliographic collections was discussed in a related post by Susan Hollis Merritt (&#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/most-effective-software-for-building-searchable-digital-bibliographic-database#post-1856)&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/most-effective-software-for-building-searchable-digital-bibliographic-database#post-1856)&#60;/a&#62;.  I'd like to focus on the public display aspect touched upon therein.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;A few of us here at Indiana University are exploring options for fostering image-based bibliographic collections.  Most of these to date are driven by scholars so they serve very specific research questions, but our Rare Books library could very well benefit from such a platform for documents with broader appeal.  Poking around the Omeka forums and the interwebs, I noticed a lot of interest in the Zotero plugin for Omeka, but I am curious to see some examples of Zotero-based collections using Omeka as an end-user delivery system.  &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Please share links and any other pertinent info!   I am especially curious how well importing file attachments work. Thanks!
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>calebmcd@gmail.com on "What is the easiest way to automate Omeka backups to a local machine?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/what-is-the-easiest-way-to-automate-omeka-backups-to-a-local-machine#post-1776</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2012 11:38:06 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>calebmcd@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1776@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I have no experience at all with PHP or MySQL, but I have recently put an Omeka installation on a server I have running on a virtual machine, where I have root privileges. If at all possible, I would like to be able to automatically back up my database to my local Unix-based machine at regular intervals, perhaps using something like Git or scp.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I don't necessarily have to backup all of the Omeka item files, as I have a folder on my local machine that contains all my PDFs and images in the Omeka database, with filenames that are identical to the &#34;Identifier&#34; field in my Omeka items. But I do want to get all of the metadata backed up, even just by grabbing the XML output. But I do want to be able to do this without having to think about it often or log in to Omeka to do the backup. Is there a way to do this?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>cyavorcik on "How do you display TEI documents online?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-do-you-display-tei-documents-online#post-1525</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2012 14:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>cyavorcik</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1525@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I'm working with a partner on an update to the TEIDisplay plugin for Omeka and looking for user input. Do you use TEIDisplay or another tool for displaying TEI Documents? Why did you choose that tool and how does it meet/not meet your needs? &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Additionally, what type of documents would you expect to display (e.g., poetry, correspondence, etc.) in a generalizable interface? For a general audience, what should a template for displaying these texts in an Omeka exhibit include? For instance, which teiHeader elements are most important (e.g., file description, revision history)? Would you want to display bibliographic codes and numbers such as page breaks and numbers or paragraph numbers? We assume folks would want to see additions and deletions and notes, but what other aspects of your texts should be displayed for a general audience? What would you add to this list for a general audience?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;(More context for this project is available here: &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.scholarslab.org/announcements/collaborative-mentoring-at-ut-and-uva-co-developing-an-updated-teidisplay-for-omeka/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://www.scholarslab.org/announcements/collaborative-mentoring-at-ut-and-uva-co-developing-an-updated-teidisplay-for-omeka/&#60;/a&#62; and here: &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.scholarslab.org/digital-humanities/an-update-to-teidisplay-for-omeka/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://www.scholarslab.org/digital-humanities/an-update-to-teidisplay-for-omeka/&#60;/a&#62;. More info on TEIDisplay itself is available here: &#60;a href=&#34;http://omeka.org/codex/Plugins/TeiDisplay&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://omeka.org/codex/Plugins/TeiDisplay&#60;/a&#62; ).
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Katy Meyers on "Can you migrate Omeka.net content into Omeka.org?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/can-you-migrate-omekanet-content-into-omekaorg#post-1149</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 10:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Katy Meyers</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1149@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I am going to be building an Omeka.org site and was wondering if I can transfer my Omeka.net data directly into it? Does anyone know what steps can be done to migrate data? Are there any guides?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Shawn on "Share your (digital) research workflow!"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/share-your-digital-research-workflow#post-1353</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2011 13:22:11 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Shawn</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1353@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Hi Miriam,&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I've been sketching out how I work here: &#60;a href=&#34;http://j.mp/digital-smg&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://j.mp/digital-smg&#60;/a&#62;  But for actual step-by-step workflow, take a look at Bill Turkel: &#60;a href=&#34;http://williamjturkel.net/how-to/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://williamjturkel.net/how-to/&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Shawn
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>genachattin on "Multiple Omeka sites on the same server?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/multiple-omeka-sites-on-the-same-server#post-1176</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2011 12:12:21 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>genachattin</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1176@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Hi all, &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Forgive me - I am a UNIX n00b, and I really feel like I should know this. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;In a nutshell, is it possible and/or advisable to create multiple Omeka sites on the same server? If so, in three sentences or less, what does an admin have to do to do this? &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;(Not looking for step-by-step instructions, just an general idea of where I have to go next with my own research to make this happen.)&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Thank you very much!&#60;br /&#62;
Gena
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Shane Landrum on "Best practices for historical-primary-source translations sites?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/best-practices-for-historical-primary-source-translations-sites#post-1073</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2011 15:56:53 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Shane Landrum</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1073@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;A colleague (currently in doctoral coursework in history) is working on translating historical primary sources about mid-20th-century North African anti-colonial revolutions. These are currently available only in French-language anthologies and are hard to get by interlibrary loan, but she's gotten copies and wants to translate them into English (and eventually into Arabic). I've suggested that she consider putting her translations online for pedagogical purposes.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Before I get myself in too deep on this, I'd love some guidance by people who know more about translations websites. (Once I've seen enough answers here, I'll probably just forward the URL of this discussion to her, and she can ask her own clarifying questions.)&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;ul&#62;
&#60;li&#62; I'm aware of at least one existing site, &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.einaudi.cornell.edu/europe/integrated_history/about.asp&#34;&#62;Integrated History&#60;/a&#62;, that does precisely this-- English translations of Eastern European history sources-- but I'd welcome examples of others that present scholarly translations well, particularly for historical texts. (For this purpose, it's a plus if they're small-scale/solo-scholar/DIY in nature.)&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;What are the intellectual-property/rights issues of translating portions of published texts from a published anthology, when the original sources being anthologized are &#34;historical&#34; in nature (i.e. not &#34;literary&#34; and thus subject to litigation from an author's estate)? The jurisdiction of first publication is France (or maybe Algeria, Tunisia, Morocco-- unsure on this), within the last 50 years. How copyright-risky would it be for her to put the French text online alongside her English and/or Arabic translations?&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;Is the &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.einaudi.cornell.edu/europe/integrated_history/copyright.asp&#34;&#62;Integrated History copyright statement&#60;/a&#62; a reasonable model for a copyright disclaimer? I like my sources website's &#60;a href=&#34;http://cliotropic.org/sources/copyright/&#34;&#62;copyright statement&#60;/a&#62;, but it wouldn't be a good model in this case, since all my online sources are copyright-expired and/or US government documents.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;I know that &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.tei-c.org/Guidelines/&#34;&#62;TEI&#60;/a&#62; is the Real Scholars' Tool for encoding translations, but it's got a high learning curve and (from what I can see) mostly makes sense for larger-scale projects with a literary flavor, not small, short-term proof-of-concept projects. (I'd be open to hearing good arguments to the contrary, though.) If one were encoding one's translations in a future-compatible way, what's the minimal set of formatting tags that overlap between HTML and TEI?&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;Since my colleague doesn't yet have a webserver setup of her own, I was going to suggest &#60;a href=&#34;http://omeka.net&#34;&#62;Omeka.Net&#60;/a&#62; as a way to get started quickly and without much technical overhead, with the thought that if she wants to expand or install custom plugins like &#60;a href=&#34;http://omeka.org/codex/Plugins/TeiDisplay&#34;&#62;TeiDisplay&#60;/a&#62; later, she can buy a webhosting plan then. Is there any reason I should be suggesting a tool other than Omeka for this project?&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;Scholars' Lab folks: How mature is the TeiDisplay plugin? Where can I see it running?&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;/ul&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Thanks in advance for your suggestions and comments.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Mark Sample on "How to have students create their own exhibits in Omeka?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-to-have-students-create-their-own-exhibits-in-omeka#post-908</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2011 16:24:42 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Mark Sample</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">908@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I'd like to have each student create his or her own exhibit in Omeka, using a shared collection of items. I know the MyOmeka plugin offers users to create their own 1-page &#34;poster&#34;---but I want students to be able create deeper exhibits than that.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
