<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- generator="bbPress/1.0.2" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Humanities Questions &#38; Answers &#187; Tag: translation - Recent Posts</title>
		<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/tags/translation</link>
		<description>Digital Humanities Questions &amp; Answers &#187; Tag: translation - Recent Posts</description>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 00:04:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<generator>http://bbpress.org/?v=1.0.2</generator>
		<textInput>
			<title><![CDATA[Search]]></title>
			<description><![CDATA[Search all topics from these forums.]]></description>
			<name>q</name>
			<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/search.php</link>
		</textInput>
		<atom:link href="/rss/tags/translation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
			 
				<title>Bethany Nowviskie on "Support for a multi-media poetry translation website?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/support-for-a-multi-media-poetry-translation-website#post-1577</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2012 08:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Bethany Nowviskie</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1577@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Depending on your ambitions for a project like this, many digital humanities centers would need some outside support in order to assist with a effort by someone outside their home institutions.  &#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/im-considering-a-move-to-the-chicago-area-whats-the-dh-scene-like-there&#34;&#62;Start-up funding&#60;/a&#62; from an NEH grant, for instance, would help.  And regional &#60;a href=&#34;http://thatcamp.org&#34;&#62;THATCamp&#60;/a&#62; events are often excellent places to meet up with faculty and staff from DH centers, publishers, humanities agencies, and cultural heritage institutions and find out about opportunities to collaborate.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;You may also want to register on the new &#60;a href=&#34;http://dhcommons.org/&#34;&#62;DH Commons site&#60;/a&#62;, which is designed for people seeking collaborators or offering collaborative opportunities.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;If you are looking for publishing platforms or journals that support multi-media work, you should consider &#60;a href=&#34;http://mediacommons.futureofthebook.org/&#34;&#62;MediaCommons&#60;/a&#62; and &#60;a href=&#34;http://vectors.usc.edu/journal/index.php?page=Introduction&#34;&#62;Vectors&#60;/a&#62;.  The Vectors team is also working on a new digital publishing tool, &#60;a href=&#34;http://scalar.usc.edu/anvc/?page_id=6&#34;&#62;Scalar&#60;/a&#62;.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>snehaadesai@gmail.com on "Support for a multi-media poetry translation website?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/support-for-a-multi-media-poetry-translation-website#post-1559</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2012 04:36:31 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>snehaadesai@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1559@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Hi, I am a Fulbright Scholar working on translation practice and theory. I'd like to solicit ideas for organizations that would support a multi-media presentation of the translations I am writing. Ideally, I would work with an organization that it invested in innovation in digital publishing, and the humanities.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Just throwing this out there for ideas--thanks!
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Arno Bosse on "Questions about providing translations/foreign language editions of DH projects."</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/questions-about-providing-translationsforeign-language-editions-of-dh-projects#post-1259</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2011 15:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Arno Bosse</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1259@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I've just finished reviewing the user's manual for a German text editor/annotation tool. Something I realized immediately was that it's fairly counterproductive to have non-native English speakers (say, the project's developers) create an initial &#34;literal&#34; translation and then request a native speaker to add some final &#34;polish&#34; (no, not Polish!) to the final draft. Untangling the resulting mangle of embedded idioms is extremely time consuming and fraught with compromises. You'd be much better off re-writing the manual from scratch. The better approach, I feel, is to develop a well thought out style manual and high-level concept for the translation, ask the developers to deliver a combination of terse, bullet-point style lists and longer explanations where necessary describing the functions and then have the translation written by a native speaker. And based at least on my experience it would be wise to create a variant of the style manual for each of your target languages.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>amandafrenchphd@gmail.com on "Questions about providing translations/foreign language editions of DH projects."</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/questions-about-providing-translationsforeign-language-editions-of-dh-projects#post-1246</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 18:44:25 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>amandafrenchphd@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1246@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;For what it's worth, I made thatcamp.org multilingual (though I'm sure it's inelegant) by installing a WordPress translation plugin. I think it's this one: &#60;a href=&#34;http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/global-translator/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/global-translator/&#60;/a&#62; -- I can check if you like. It makes a &#34;Translate&#34; link appear on every page. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;No, we haven't tested it, really, though a couple of our friends in Italy and France were appreciative on Twitter. And of course it only works on WordPress sites, though I'm sure there's something similar for Drupal.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Karin Dalziel on "Questions about providing translations/foreign language editions of DH projects."</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/questions-about-providing-translationsforeign-language-editions-of-dh-projects#post-1241</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 15:21:57 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Karin Dalziel</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1241@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;&#60;em&#62;Replying to @Stéfan Sinclair's &#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/questions-about-providing-translationsforeign-language-editions-of-dh-projects#post-1237&#34;&#62;post&#60;/a&#62;:&#60;/em&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Thanks for your response! I'm at the beginning part of implementing these translations, but am already starting to see problems:&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;- People don't by default give me new text in foreign languages.&#60;br /&#62;
- When changes are sent for a page, I have to ask for corresponding changes for the foreign language pages. Sometimes I can make an educated guess, but that way lies madness (and laughably bad translations.)&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;My usability alarms go off when I am asked to make a &#34;foreign language&#34; edition of a site where only the intro text is in a foreign language, but I can't find any articles that have actually tested this scenario or done informational interviews with users of a site outside the primary language. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I would love to hear if any foreign language users find this kind of limited translation useful, or, if not, what would be useful.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;My co-worker proposed an alternative for sites that only have limited content in a foreign language: make a section of the site that explicitly details what resources *are* available in each language. There are questions of how to direct users to that area of the site, but that approach seems much more usable and sustainable.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Stéfan Sinclair on "Questions about providing translations/foreign language editions of DH projects."</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/questions-about-providing-translationsforeign-language-editions-of-dh-projects#post-1237</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2011 16:05:42 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Stéfan Sinclair</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1237@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;This topic seems a bit like walking on eggshells, especially since their are some very adamant opinions out there. My experience is that translation is somewhat of a losing battle, but may still be well worth the trouble, especially when trying to reach certain communities. In an ideal scenario translation responsibilities fall back on people within the community (rather than assuming responsibility centrally in a project).&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Way back when the digitalhumanities.org site was launched we created translations in French and Italian – both were done with modest stipends. The site then was powered by a wiki and there was a mechanism to notify editors when a change was made to a translation page, but over time the translated content fell out of sync. That was using TWiki – I'd be curious to see if MediaWiki has more sophisticated support, but I suspect not (several Wikipedia pages are not translations at all, but entirely autonomous articles).&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;For other projects I've built custom localization modules, partly because I find it easier to keep all translations together in a common resource (as opposed to one file per set of language strings). But that approach doesn't scale and only works in a small development team.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I guess for most of the multilingual projects I've been involved in the translations seem like a gesture more than a necessity, and frankly I'm not entirely convinced that the gesture has been worth the trouble. It's like the DH conference call for proposals that exists in several languages, which is a worthy nod to multiculturalism, but ultimately it's unlikely that someone would propose something without having functional reading competencies in English.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;It may not be a choice in your case, but a generic piece of advice would be to do translation on a concrete need basis only, not on an anticipated need basis (this might be akin to agile programming where a client expresses a need rather than the developer anticipating a use). If translation is in the cards, then hopefully there's an engaged group of people who can sustain it and avoid linguistic atrophy over time.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;&#60;em&#62;&#38;lt;annotation&#38;gt;hope I'm not sounding cynical&#38;lt;/annotation&#38;gt;&#60;/em&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;&#60;em&#62;&#38;lt;annotation&#38;gt;this probably didn't even answer your question&#38;lt;/annotation&#38;gt;&#60;/em&#62;
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Karin Dalziel on "Questions about providing translations/foreign language editions of DH projects."</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/questions-about-providing-translationsforeign-language-editions-of-dh-projects#post-1235</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2011 14:21:22 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Karin Dalziel</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1235@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;This is mostly just a request for anyone with experience providing translations of DH projects to share what they learned. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Some general questions: &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;-How do the translations affect the workflow? i.e. if a change comes in for page (usually in English, in our case), what's the process to roll those changes out to the translated pages, especially if the original translator is no longer available?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;-How do you choose the languages to translate into?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;-What content do you translate? For instance, it is pretty easy to provide translations for the introductory pages, but if there is a lot of content it may be harder to provide translations for all of the content immediately. Is it worth rolling out translations for introductory pages before the translations for the content are complete?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I'm just starting research on this topic (beginning with the W3C's &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.w3.org/TR/i18n-html-tech-lang/#ri20040808.100519373&#34;&#62;Internationalization Best Practices: Specifying Language in XHTML &#38;amp; HTML Content&#60;/a&#62;) but would love to hear other's experiences.  This isn't a question as much about the technical implementation, though I'd love to hear about that too if you want to share. :)
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Wayne Graham on "Best practices for historical-primary-source translations sites?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/best-practices-for-historical-primary-source-translations-sites#post-1080</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2011 10:05:33 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Wayne Graham</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1080@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I'm not familiar with the Integrated History project, but I can speak to the TEI questions (and side step copyright issues)...&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;My first question is what is the proposed end product for this? Are there uses of the text (other than a straight translation) that they're wanting to use the texts for?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Depending on how you're envisioning the long-term use of the information, I would encourage you to investigate TEI. Especially if you're looking for more encoding of the content (e.g. names, dates, etc.) of the texts, and not just the structure and words. Truthfully TEI is no more scary than HTML, and with a decent editor like oXygen, you can get up and running pretty quickly with it (there are also supportive &#60;a href=&#34;http://listserv.brown.edu/archives/cgi-bin/wa?SUBED1=TEI-L&#38;amp;A=1&#34;&#62;listservs&#60;/a&#62; and &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.tei-c.org/Support/Learn/tutorials.xml&#34;&#62;tutorials&#60;/a&#62; at the TEI-C).&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;The TEI display plugin for Omeka was really a &#34;wonder if we can get this to work&#34; experiment. It's quite limited in what it does (mainly due to the limitations of PHP's implementation of XSLT). The plugin is one way to quickly display some TEI on an Omeka site, but it really depends on what the end state you're going for is, and we've not had a good use case yet to integrate this in to project, so the code is still pretty young.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;HTH,&#60;br /&#62;
Wayne
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Shane Landrum on "Best practices for historical-primary-source translations sites?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/best-practices-for-historical-primary-source-translations-sites#post-1073</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2011 15:56:53 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Shane Landrum</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1073@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;A colleague (currently in doctoral coursework in history) is working on translating historical primary sources about mid-20th-century North African anti-colonial revolutions. These are currently available only in French-language anthologies and are hard to get by interlibrary loan, but she's gotten copies and wants to translate them into English (and eventually into Arabic). I've suggested that she consider putting her translations online for pedagogical purposes.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Before I get myself in too deep on this, I'd love some guidance by people who know more about translations websites. (Once I've seen enough answers here, I'll probably just forward the URL of this discussion to her, and she can ask her own clarifying questions.)&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;ul&#62;
&#60;li&#62; I'm aware of at least one existing site, &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.einaudi.cornell.edu/europe/integrated_history/about.asp&#34;&#62;Integrated History&#60;/a&#62;, that does precisely this-- English translations of Eastern European history sources-- but I'd welcome examples of others that present scholarly translations well, particularly for historical texts. (For this purpose, it's a plus if they're small-scale/solo-scholar/DIY in nature.)&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;What are the intellectual-property/rights issues of translating portions of published texts from a published anthology, when the original sources being anthologized are &#34;historical&#34; in nature (i.e. not &#34;literary&#34; and thus subject to litigation from an author's estate)? The jurisdiction of first publication is France (or maybe Algeria, Tunisia, Morocco-- unsure on this), within the last 50 years. How copyright-risky would it be for her to put the French text online alongside her English and/or Arabic translations?&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;Is the &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.einaudi.cornell.edu/europe/integrated_history/copyright.asp&#34;&#62;Integrated History copyright statement&#60;/a&#62; a reasonable model for a copyright disclaimer? I like my sources website's &#60;a href=&#34;http://cliotropic.org/sources/copyright/&#34;&#62;copyright statement&#60;/a&#62;, but it wouldn't be a good model in this case, since all my online sources are copyright-expired and/or US government documents.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;I know that &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.tei-c.org/Guidelines/&#34;&#62;TEI&#60;/a&#62; is the Real Scholars' Tool for encoding translations, but it's got a high learning curve and (from what I can see) mostly makes sense for larger-scale projects with a literary flavor, not small, short-term proof-of-concept projects. (I'd be open to hearing good arguments to the contrary, though.) If one were encoding one's translations in a future-compatible way, what's the minimal set of formatting tags that overlap between HTML and TEI?&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;Since my colleague doesn't yet have a webserver setup of her own, I was going to suggest &#60;a href=&#34;http://omeka.net&#34;&#62;Omeka.Net&#60;/a&#62; as a way to get started quickly and without much technical overhead, with the thought that if she wants to expand or install custom plugins like &#60;a href=&#34;http://omeka.org/codex/Plugins/TeiDisplay&#34;&#62;TeiDisplay&#60;/a&#62; later, she can buy a webhosting plan then. Is there any reason I should be suggesting a tool other than Omeka for this project?&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;Scholars' Lab folks: How mature is the TeiDisplay plugin? Where can I see it running?&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;/ul&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Thanks in advance for your suggestions and comments.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Stéfan Sinclair on "Applications for aligning multiple translations?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/applications-for-aligning-multiple-translations#post-860</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2011 10:27:12 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Stéfan Sinclair</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">860@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;&#60;em&#62;A colleague has asked me&#60;/em&#62;™ for suggestions of applications that are designed to help with aligning multiple translations of a text (as I'm writing this, I'm wondering if aligning multiple editions of a text wouldn't be similar, at least in some ways). Some things can be done with spreadsheets or tables in editors, of course, but we're wondering if anyone can recommend some specialized software. I'd already suggested &#60;a href=&#34;http://translate.google.com/toolkit&#34;&#62;Google Translator Toolkit&#60;/a&#62;.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
