<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- generator="bbPress/1.0.2" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Humanities Questions &#38; Answers &#187; Topic: Recommended course of study for New Media/DH teaching career?</title>
		<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/recommended-course-of-study-for-new-mediadh-teaching-career</link>
		<description>Digital Humanities Questions &amp; Answers &#187; Topic: Recommended course of study for New Media/DH teaching career?</description>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2013 22:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<generator>http://bbpress.org/?v=1.0.2</generator>
		<textInput>
			<title><![CDATA[Search]]></title>
			<description><![CDATA[Search all topics from these forums.]]></description>
			<name>q</name>
			<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/search.php</link>
		</textInput>
		<atom:link href="/rss/topic/recommended-course-of-study-for-new-mediadh-teaching-career/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
			 
				<title>Miriam Posner on "Recommended course of study for New Media/DH teaching career?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/recommended-course-of-study-for-new-mediadh-teaching-career#post-1555</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2012 00:36:16 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Miriam Posner</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1555@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Hi mariazoey,&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I think you may have a few questions packed in here! First, you're absolutely right that finding a job as a faculty member in an English department is really tough. Unfortunately, the academic job market is pretty bad all around, not just in English. And it's a big investment of your time. As you might know, a Ph.D. is pretty much required to teach at a university. Getting one usually takes about six or seven years after your B.A.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Some people will &#60;a href=&#34;http://chronicle.com/article/Graduate-School-in-the/44846/&#34;&#62;tell you&#60;/a&#62; that job prospects for faculty are so bad that it's not worth your time to get a Ph.D. in the humanities, period. Others &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.dispositio.net/archives/586&#34;&#62;will say&#60;/a&#62; that you should go if it's really what you love more than anything else, but you should be aware that there may not be a job waiting for you at the other end.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;The other question I see in your post is about &#34;new media&#34; versus &#34;digital humanities.&#34; Confusingly enough, these are actually two separate fields. To make some really broad generalizations: People who study new media write and think about the effect of new media on people's lives. In digital humanities, the emphasis tends to be on making things — designing software, analyzing data, creating online archives, things like that. &#60;a href=&#34;http://projectroomseattle.org/2012/03/making-things/&#34;&#62;Here's&#60;/a&#62; a good article that does a nice job summarizing the &#34;making&#34; part of digital humanities.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;So I guess I have more questions for you than answers: Is teaching at a university what you really, really want to do? How important is secure employment to you? Do you want to be a university professor because you love studying and writing, or because you're seeking a secure career? If it's the latter, there may be better routes for you.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;This is not meant to dissuade you from studying new media or digital humanities! I think these are both wonderful things to study, and the University of Kansas even has a &#60;a href=&#34;http://cds.lib.ku.edu/tag/digital-humanities/&#34;&#62;digital humanities center&#60;/a&#62; that you could take advantage of. But it does sound as though sitting down with a career counselor, either at your current institution or at the one where you end up, might be a good idea.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Very best of luck to you!
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>mariazoey on "Recommended course of study for New Media/DH teaching career?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/recommended-course-of-study-for-new-mediadh-teaching-career#post-1554</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2012 21:44:46 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>mariazoey</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1554@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I have been completing hours for an AA to transfer for an English undergrad degree. Recently it has come to my attention that teaching university English is a field mostly closed to new blood, due to the number of highly-qualified individuals already there. I'm considering switching to a career path in teaching Digital Humanities or New Media instead, but feel a little lost as to knowing what would be a fruitful undergrad degree versus one that's actually worthless in the face of a teaching career. What degrees are useful? Which schools are good? Are there any in the Kansas City area?? Thanks a bunch.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
