<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- generator="bbPress/1.0.2" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Humanities Questions &#38; Answers &#187; Tag: metadata - Recent Topics</title>
		<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/tags/metadata</link>
		<description>Digital Humanities Questions &amp; Answers &#187; Tag: metadata - Recent Topics</description>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 02:29:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<generator>http://bbpress.org/?v=1.0.2</generator>
		<textInput>
			<title><![CDATA[Search]]></title>
			<description><![CDATA[Search all topics from these forums.]]></description>
			<name>q</name>
			<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/search.php</link>
		</textInput>
		<atom:link href="/rss/tags/metadata/topics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
			 
				<title>Miriam Posner on "What are people using to manage large collections of images?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/what-are-people-using-to-manage-large-collections-of-images#post-2307</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 19:05:22 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Miriam Posner</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2307@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I'm curious to know what software humanities scholars are using to wrangle large collections of images. I often encounter scholars who struggle to manage large image collections — it's not at all unusual to find people managing collections of historical images with iPhoto — and wondered if there are databases that make sense for visual collections. I'm especially interested in programs that:&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;ul&#62;
&#60;li&#62;work out of the box and have a GUI (sorry)&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;are designed for individuals, not enterprises&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;allow a scholar to quickly apprehend many images at once&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;allow one to add metadata (like place and date) — something beyond tags would be nice — and construct queries&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;make sense for people who have a lot of digital surrogates of primary sources (which is to say, systems that are optimized to retrieve the EXIF data from a photo of an archival document won't make a whole lot of sense)&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;/ul&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I know about Picasa, LightRoom, and ImagePlot. I don't think an enterprise-level system like ContenDM or the like makes sense for individual scholars. Omeka, of course, is nice, but it's a bit unwieldy if you're just trying to manage a collection. What am I missing?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>dot.porter on "Seeking a generalizable metadata mapping tool"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/seeking-a-generalizable-metadata-mapping-tool#post-1916</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 12:32:12 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>dot.porter</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1916@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I'm looking for what is probably the holy grail of metadata: a generalizable mapping tool. I could specify the final output (in XML), perhaps based on a schema or I could just indicate somehow the output tags and attributes. This tool would enable a user to put in their metadata in whatever format it's in (any XML, csv, excel), map fields/tags/attributes from their metadata document into the tags and attributes I've specified, and would spit out a document that follows my format.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;An example of how this would function is the Sheet Music Consortium Metadata Mapping Tool, which is unfortunately not generalizable and doesn't accept XML (&#60;a href=&#34;http://www.dlib.indiana.edu/smcmigrator/upload.php&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://www.dlib.indiana.edu/smcmigrator/upload.php&#60;/a&#62;)&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Does such a thing exist?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>IanRobertson on "TEI Basic Tags"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/tei-basic-tags#post-667</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2010 13:12:49 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>IanRobertson</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">667@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Hello,&#60;br /&#62;
I'm working on an ongoing research project at my school where I will be encoding in TEI.  I was just curious if anyone had a list of standard TEI tags, and specifically tags for SmallCaps, Hyphens, and M-lines.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Thanks!
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Karin Dalziel on "Best way to create COinS or other metadata from TEI using XSLT?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/best-way-to-create-coins-or-other-metadata-from-tei-using-xslt#post-134</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2010 12:31:50 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Karin Dalziel</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">134@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I feel way behind in this area. I have successfully used XSLT to insert in Dublin Core metadata into the header of an HTML page, but I would like to support multiple resources, etc. From looking around, it seems the best format to use is COinS, but the format is a bit more, er, obtuse than dublin core. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Has anyone done this? care to share some sample XSLT? Am I going about this all wrong?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;(Also, I debated whether this should go in metadata or programming. Feel free to chime in on that as well)
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Stéfan Sinclair on "Bibliographies with Geolocation Metadata"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/bibliographies-with-geolocation-metadata#post-1410</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2011 09:41:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Stéfan Sinclair</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1410@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Can anyone suggest good sources for &#60;strong&#62;bulk&#60;/strong&#62; bibliographic records with geolocation metadata? I'm mostly interested in literary and historical texts, though other collections might serve as good examples. Typical publication location as words would be a fine start, but ideally there would be location of writing (where possible) and latitude/longitude values.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Paige Morgan on "best practices for sharing TEI code and public/private data dictionaries"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/best-practices-for-sharing-tei-code-and-publicprivate-data-dictionaries#post-1292</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2011 19:18:32 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Paige Morgan</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1292@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I'm working on a long-term database project involving literature and economics, in which I'm gathering price data from a wide range of 18th and 19th century English texts.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;On my project website, I have an editorial statement and FAQ designed to provide context for the project both for people who are familiar with lit./econ. studies, and less so. I don't want to give away my IP, so most of the project itself is walled off. But I'm at the stage where I'm going to be looking for interested collaborators, and so I'd like to put as much on display as possible while protecting my work. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;With that in mind, I'm trying to make a decision about whether to share a sample entry with full TEI markup. It's important, I think, that I show how my work uses the current TEI guidelines; especially because in a couple of areas, I'm extending them to meet the needs of my data. That brings me to the data dictionary, and the question of whether to make it visible, so that people can see my rationale for the choices I've made.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I could password protect some parts of the site, and maintain a certain amount of control over who can access it that way, but that doesn't provide a lot of security, and to be truthful, I'd prefer to have the site open, so that someone who found it could explore without having to contact me first.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I looked back through previous posts, and though I found acknowledgments that code is often kept out of the public eye, I didn't find any clear statements regarding the fine balance between making code public as a way of illustrating that you know what you're doing; and sharing too much.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Anyone have any recommendations? And thanks, very much, in advance.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>cforster on "What have you discovered using the TEI and what programs did you use/create?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/what-have-you-discovered-using-the-tei-and-what-programs-did-you-usecreate#post-1169</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2011 10:49:59 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>cforster</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1169@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;This question is really fascinating (especially since I suspect I have inkling of &#60;a href=&#34;http://dl.lib.brown.edu/mjp/&#34;&#62;the sort of texts&#60;/a&#62; you're interested in). Let me just dump a handful of links which I think might be helpful from my recent delicious/pinboard (hmm... delicious pinboard).&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;While I can't point to specific results/papers. Aditi Muralidharan (@silverasm)'s WordSeer project is promising interesting results about slave narratives, though it does not rely on TEI. In &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.eecs.berkeley.edu/~aditi/projects/wordseer.html&#34;&#62;this talk&#60;/a&#62;, though, she does a good job of answering Sean's question directly--how can metadata improve on generic full-text search. WordSeer (as I understand it) works mostly by supplementing raw text with part of speech tagging and other grammatical metadata.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;With respect to TEI specifically one obvious place to start, I think, is &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.monkproject.org/&#34;&#62;MONK&#60;/a&#62;; as Dorothea notes, Martin Mueller is involved with the MONK project. You can find him summarizing MONK &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.cch.kcl.ac.uk/cocoon/tei2008/programme/abstracts/abstract-169.html&#34;&#62;here&#60;/a&#62; and at greater length &#60;a href=&#34;https://apps.lis.illinois.edu/wiki/display/MONK/Notes+towards+a+user+manual+of+Monk&#34;&#62;here&#60;/a&#62;. Unlike WordSeer, the Monk Workbench gives you metadata about author (including gender) and publication date. Matt Kirschenbaum mentions MONK in &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.umbc.edu/~hillol/NGDM07/abstracts/talks/MKirschenbaum.pdf&#34;&#62;this article&#60;/a&#62; [PDF].&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;(How relevant it will be to you, I don't know, but when I heard John Unsworth speak recently, he talked about the work flow and complications of large text collections with different encoding standards--with reference to MONK in particular. You can hear him &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.scholarslab.org/podcasts/unsworth-idiosyncrasy-at-scale/&#34;&#62;here&#60;/a&#62;.)&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;There was a &#60;a href=&#34;http://listserv.brown.edu/archives/cgi-bin/wa?A1=ind1104&#38;amp;L=TEI-L&#38;amp;F=&#38;amp;S=&#38;amp;O=T&#38;amp;H=0&#38;amp;D=0&#38;amp;T=1#34&#34;&#62;recent discussion&#60;/a&#62; on the TEI list about eXist from which I learned a lot--again, about what's possible rather than specific results/reports.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Finally--this one is also not TEI specific--if you haven't seen Ben Schmidt's blog, he is doing some pretty impressive stuff. This post, on &#60;a href=&#34;http://sappingattention.blogspot.com/2011/04/age-cohort-and-vocabulary-use.html&#34;&#62;vocabulary use and age cohort&#60;/a&#62; gives some idea.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Ryan Cordell on "Custom tags in TEI"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/custom-tags-in-tei#post-1185</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2011 11:31:55 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Ryan Cordell</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1185@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Hi all,&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;So I'm tinkering with the TEI in my first batch of &#34;Celestial Railroad&#34; editions (&#60;a href=&#34;http://celestialrailroad.org/)&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://celestialrailroad.org/)&#60;/a&#62;, and I'm looking for the best way to indicate, in the metadata, a few features of each text. I want to be able to indicate the denomination and/or political affiliations of each newspaper/magazine that reprinted the story. I thought I could add some fields in the &#38;lt;sourceDesc&#38;gt;: e.g. &#38;lt;sourceDenomination&#38;gt; or &#38;lt;sourcePolitics&#38;gt;, but that seems to raise red flags when I attempt to post or use the TEI file. Any suggestions for how I can encode this information? The religious and/or political backgrounds of the newspapers are central to the questions I'm asking about these texts.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Thanks,&#60;br /&#62;
Ryan
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Jennifer Sano-Franchini on "Suggestions for open source frameworks for web development?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/suggestions-for-open-source-protocols-for-web-development#post-981</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2011 14:54:34 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Jennifer Sano-Franchini</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">981@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I'm looking for a fairly user-friendly open source protocol for developing a web-based project that basically combines organized, user-contributed links (kind of like an online bibliography) with tagging capabilities and discussion boards. It would be great if I could develop something easy for users to navigate, as the site would be geared toward college-level writing students and instructors.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Right now I'm looking at Drupal and BuddyPress, and I'm also thinking to use APIs, possibly from delicious, Mendeley, and I'm interested in looking into OpenCalais for pulling metadata from the linked sources. But, I'm really new to all of this and I'm wondering if anyone else has any other suggestions of tools that I might look into using--?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>dana on "Libraries offering OAI-PMH metadata for digitized objects?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/libraries-offering-oai-pmh-metadata-for-digitized-objects#post-834</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2010 14:33:06 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>dana</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">834@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Recently, the University of Florida set up a free download link to the metadata of their digital objects. Does anyone know of other schools/institutions following suit? Please let me know, as I'd like to learn more about the implementation of this feature.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Dorothea Salo on "Controlled-vocabulary management software"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/controlled-vocabulary-management-software#post-885</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 09:55:59 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Dorothea Salo</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">885@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Any DHers have homegrown controlled vocabularies for metadata? Or CVs that they didn't invent, but manage in-house? Do you have software for that? What is it?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>tanyaclement on "Which text editor is best for Hebrew and TEI?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/which-text-editor-is-best-for-hebrew-and-tei#post-739</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2010 10:41:48 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>tanyaclement</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">739@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;From a colleague:&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I have, for my sins, begun to develop a project of a direct-to-digital edition of the Mishnah . . . Our basic problem right now is text/XML editors. At least for the Mac, even if the editor claims to be fully compliant with Unicode, any time you add tags to the text the word order on the line gets fouled up, which deeply complicates the problem of proof reading and error checking. So my question is,can you recommend a text editor that works with right to left fonts?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Erin Bell on "Oral History Metadata Standards and Schemes"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/oral-history-metadata-standards-and-schemes#post-302</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 13:14:45 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Erin Bell</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">302@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I'm wondering if anyone knows of an ideal metadata scheme for digital oral history projects and collections.  I've seen many different approaches, most often DublinCore-based, but none seem to follow any identifiable standard specific to the oral history medium or field as a whole.  In addition to the use of DublinCore et al, have there been any attempts to create or use something like PBCore (NPR/PBS multimedia metadata scheme &#60;a href=&#34;http://pbcore.org/2.0/)&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://pbcore.org/2.0/)&#60;/a&#62; that answers specifically to some of the unique characteristics of oral history media?  Are there any agreed upon standards, exemplary use cases, important articles, etc.?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;EDIT: I've created a public open Zotero Group that explores this issue as well.  Join/Add if interested: &#60;a href=&#34;https://www.zotero.org/groups/digital_oral_history_and_metadata&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;https://www.zotero.org/groups/digital_oral_history_and_metadata&#60;/a&#62;
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Shane Landrum on "Good, fast metadata management for digital photos of archival items?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/good-fast-metadata-management-for-digital-photos-of-archival-items#post-138</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2010 01:01:32 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Shane Landrum</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">138@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;As a historian working on a dissertation, I'm looking for a good, open-source, Mac-friendly metadata tool for managing the gigabytes of digital photos I've taken of archival materials. Adobe Lightroom's features are close, but it's an expensive piece of software and doesn't solve my problems well. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Mostly, I want a way to add arbitrary metadata to an individual image or batch of images. It might be citation-related (&#34;Every JPG in this folder or its subfolders is from the Jane Texas Papers, and this subfolder is from Box 1...&#34;), subject-related, author-related, or idiosyncratically related to my own research questions. (Think of a sociologist or anthropologist coding interview data.) In an ideal world, it would be able to support a &#34;transcription&#34; field. JPEG/EXIF metadata fields seem unwieldy, not to mention that they're easy to clobber accidentally. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I've looked into DSpace as a repository system (and even installed it on my laptop), but it's overkill for single-researcher use at the dissertation level, not to mention a huge amount of work to set up. I don't have access to an institutional DSpace for building my own collections, or else that might be a good answer (from what I know of it).&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Really, what I want is a research workflow system for digital reference images. I want to be able to easily, quickly mark and categorize the items in my (very large) collections according to arbitrary categories; find the items I'm looking for using a faceted search; transcribe them in some cases, but not all; know what I haven't looked at yet, but need to; cite the item I'm looking at; etc. Zotero isn't really suited for this, nor is Bookends (my preferred desktop citation manager).&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;If such a tool doesn't exist for making this process easier, are there established best practices for setting up a home-hacked metadata and workflow system of my own? I've been hacking around with Ruby scripts that store this metadata in nearby text or YAML files, but those haven't worked as well as I'd like.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>PhDeviate on "What do undergraduates need to know about metadata?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/what-do-undergraduates-need-to-know-about-metadata#post-104</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2010 18:11:54 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>PhDeviate</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">104@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I wish for a guideline, akin to what elementary school teachers study about age appropriate behaviors and skills, about scholar-age appropriate digital skills. What should first-years know about metadata? I teach keywords and controlled vocab subjects by default, but I'm considering adding the concept of the tag. What else should they know? What should college graduates know? What should MA students know? PhD?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
