<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- generator="bbPress/1.0.2" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Humanities Questions &#38; Answers &#187; Topic: Readings on or models of collaboration in DH projects?</title>
		<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/models-of-collaboration-in-digital-humanities-project</link>
		<description>Digital Humanities Questions &amp; Answers &#187; Topic: Readings on or models of collaboration in DH projects?</description>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 04:21:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<generator>http://bbpress.org/?v=1.0.2</generator>
		<textInput>
			<title><![CDATA[Search]]></title>
			<description><![CDATA[Search all topics from these forums.]]></description>
			<name>q</name>
			<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/search.php</link>
		</textInput>
		<atom:link href="/rss/topic/models-of-collaboration-in-digital-humanities-project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
			 
				<title>Brian Rosenblum on "Readings on or models of collaboration in DH projects?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/models-of-collaboration-in-digital-humanities-project#post-656</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2010 11:50:20 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Brian Rosenblum</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">656@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Everyone, may thanks for all these suggestions!  It's very helpful. Still getting my thoughts together for Monday's session--if anything interesting happens to come out of the discussion I will follow up here with more info.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Jason Boyd on "Readings on or models of collaboration in DH projects?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/models-of-collaboration-in-digital-humanities-project#post-630</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 14:17:09 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Jason Boyd</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">630@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;You may find some of Lynne Siemens' work useful, particularly the following:&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;&#34;&#34;It’s a team if you use ‘reply all'&#34;: An Exploration of Research Teams in Digital Humanities Environments&#34; Literary &#38;amp; Linguistic Computing 24.2(June 2009), 225-233.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;&#34;&#34;It Challenges Members to Think of Their Work Through Another Kind of Specialist's Eyes&#34;: Exploration of the Benefits and Challenges of Diversity in Digital Project Teams&#34; (with Wendy Duff, R. Cunningham and C. Warwick) Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the American Society for Information Science and Technology, 2009, November 2009 (Vancouver, British Columbia) &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.asis.org/Conferences/AM09/open-proceedings/openpage.html&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://www.asis.org/Conferences/AM09/open-proceedings/openpage.html&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Lynne Siemens' webpage:&#60;br /&#62;
(&#60;a href=&#34;http://publicadmin.uvic.ca/aboutUs/staffPersonal/siemens.php&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://publicadmin.uvic.ca/aboutUs/staffPersonal/siemens.php&#60;/a&#62;)
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Bethany Nowviskie on "Readings on or models of collaboration in DH projects?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/models-of-collaboration-in-digital-humanities-project#post-625</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2010 16:20:54 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Bethany Nowviskie</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">625@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Hi, Brian -- I think and speak about these issues pretty frequently, and write about them lately, too: &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;&#60;a href=&#34;http://nowviskie.org/tag/collaboration/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://nowviskie.org/tag/collaboration/&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Of the posts in that category, I might highlight these two, which touch on some issues raised by your question, &#34;What kinds of collaborations are needed to enable &#60;strong&#62;faculty&#60;/strong&#62; &#60;em&#62;(my emphasis)&#60;/em&#62; to participate in or create digital humanities projects?&#34;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;&#60;a href=&#34;http://nowviskie.org/2009/monopolies-of-invention/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://nowviskie.org/2009/monopolies-of-invention/&#60;/a&#62;&#60;br /&#62;
&#60;a href=&#34;http://nowviskie.org/2010/on-compensation/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://nowviskie.org/2010/on-compensation/&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Collaboration is just about the last activity for which a typical graduate education in the humanities, or experience on the tenure track, might prepare you -- and our inherited institutional structures, policies, and assumptions often work against faculty as they first enter into very rich and (frankly) essential collaborations in the digital humanities.  These folks need to be prepared to think carefully and make good decisions about the way they frame collaborations.  Many times, they'll be PIs on their own first grants, and will suddenly -- with only past teaching experience to draw on -- have a small staff to manage, or large institutional partners to wrangle, often from differently-organized divisions of the university.  &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;If I had your opportunity in being invited to give this talk, I'm sure I'd use it to raise awareness about some of the problematic divisions between faculty and staff -- research and &#34;service&#34; -- that really do, in an academic setting, require much more than a trite call for everyone to collaborate as equals (even if it's absolutely true that the most exciting DH projects I've worked on or encountered were crafted by faculty, staff, and students working as peers).  Nope -- these problems actually require us to address institutional policies, such as those (generally different for faculty and &#34;work-for-hire&#34; staff) around authors' rights and intellectual property, or local practices that shape differently the notion of &#34;compensated time&#34; for different kinds of collaborators.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I'll be very interested in following this thread! I'm giving a talk in Melbourne next month in which I'll re-use my &#34;Monopolies of Invention&#34; title (the quotation is from a famous Thomas Jefferson letter against the use of copyright and patent to lock down the free circulation of ideas) for a different presentation -- this time adding a subtitle: &#34;Collaboration Across Class Lines in the Digital Humanities.&#34;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;So I'm hoping to see some great discussion and resource sharing in this thread!
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Patrick Murray-John on "Readings on or models of collaboration in DH projects?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/models-of-collaboration-in-digital-humanities-project#post-624</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2010 15:29:30 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Patrick Murray-John</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">624@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;These questions sometimes hint at the question of what DH itself is, and some perspective on that tends to be implicit in a lot of replies (certainly is in mine!), but here's my $.02.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;What collaborations are needed? My experience has been with collaborations between tech.-oriented people with a humanities background/interest and humanities-oriented people with a tech. background/interest. Knowing a little about the other's focus helps keep everyone on the same page, and having different sets of expertise fosters productive conversations.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;New kinds of collaborations? My favorite is the micro-collaboration -- something that springs up, often spontaneously, and exists in a time from a day or two, max, and often just a couple of hours. Twitter is great at that. A blog and/or a public code repo for longer contributions also helps.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Introducing it? I think that an effective example, if you are on Twitter, is to prime people you follow that you'll be doing a quick Twitter demo at a particular time during your talk. Then just ask for a shoutout during the talk -- maybe ask a quick, easy question. Instant collaboration!&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Hope that helps,&#60;br /&#62;
Patrick
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Brian Rosenblum on "Readings on or models of collaboration in DH projects?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/models-of-collaboration-in-digital-humanities-project#post-620</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2010 23:53:51 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Brian Rosenblum</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">620@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I have been asked to give a talk to our faculty on &#34;Models of Collaboration in Digital Humanities Projects&#34; focusing on &#34;the possibilities and challenges of collaboration.&#34; It will probably be a general audience of humanities scholars, whose experience with digital projects may range from a lot to none.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;This topic could be approached at so many levels that I'm not quite sure where to begin. I'm finding the following pages very helpful&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;&#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalscholarship.wordpress.com/category/collaboration/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://digitalscholarship.wordpress.com/category/collaboration/&#60;/a&#62;&#60;br /&#62;
&#60;a href=&#34;http://www.dancohen.org/category/collaboration/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://www.dancohen.org/category/collaboration/&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;but would also be interested in pointers to other readings, or seeing a discussion here at DHanswers on how &#34;collaboration&#34; relates to &#34;digital humanities.&#34;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;For the immediate purposes of my upcoming talk, I am most interested in discussing this at a practical level: What kinds of collaborations are needed to enable faculty to participate in or create digital humanities projects. And, conversely, what kinds of new collaborations does digital technology enable? And what is an effective way to introduce this topic to a general scholarly audience?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
