<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- generator="bbPress/1.0.2" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Humanities Questions &#38; Answers &#187; User Favorites: galarza.alex@gmail.com</title>
		<link><a href='/profile/galarzaalexgmailcom'>galarzaalexgmailcom</a></link>
		<description>Digital Humanities Questions &amp; Answers &#187; User Favorites: galarza.alex@gmail.com</description>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 14:13:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<generator>http://bbpress.org/?v=1.0.2</generator>
		<textInput>
			<title><![CDATA[Search]]></title>
			<description><![CDATA[Search all topics from these forums.]]></description>
			<name>q</name>
			<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/search.php</link>
		</textInput>
		<atom:link href="/rss/profile/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
			 
				<title>digitalmom on "What are some useful tools for creating timelines?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/what-are-some-useful-tools-for-creating-timelines#post-2347</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 05:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>digitalmom</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2347@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I really like a more photo based timeline and to see them larger, so I have been working with a timeline creator called liniaa.&#60;br /&#62;
I have a nice wall of images I can see at a glance. This is great for documenting children growing up, I added my son's first words, his toys, his drawings and family vacations.&#60;br /&#62;
&#60;a href=&#34;http://liniaa.com&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://liniaa.com&#60;/a&#62;
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Bethany Nowviskie on "What are some useful tools for creating timelines?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/what-are-some-useful-tools-for-creating-timelines#post-1737</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2012 06:30:48 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Bethany Nowviskie</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1737@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Readers may also be interested in Neatline, a newly-released tool for creating timelines and geo-temporal visualizations from the content of Omeka collections: &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;&#60;a href=&#34;http://neatline.org/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://neatline.org/&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;The timeline feature in Neatline may be used alongside its map-annotation features, or separately (as &#34;Neatline Time&#34;). Users of the larger Neatline plug-in have to ability to indicate ambiguity or uncertainty in events plotted on the timeline, making it a more attractive option for humanities interpretation than most existing timeline systems.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>mauropasi on "What are some useful tools for creating timelines?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/what-are-some-useful-tools-for-creating-timelines#post-1736</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2012 06:18:21 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>mauropasi</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1736@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Sorry for going around exhuming old questions but there is a new tool that I think is way better than all the others (and I am not just saying that because I work for it).&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;It's called myHistro and it focuses on the geographical visualization of the events which is something that all other tools lack.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I wrote a short article about its use in the classroom here: &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.myhistro.com/blog/interactive-timelines-for-teachers-and-students&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://www.myhistro.com/blog/interactive-timelines-for-teachers-and-students&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Mauro Pasi&#60;br /&#62;
&#60;a href=&#34;http://www.myhistro.com&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://www.myhistro.com&#60;/a&#62;
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Ethan Gruber on "What would your dream DH apprenticeship opportunity involve?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/what-would-your-dream-dh-apprenticeship-opportunity-involve#post-1211</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2011 09:28:36 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Ethan Gruber</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1211@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;My dream apprenticeship would involve little or no web development.  Programming is useful in the digital humanities, but it is important to keep in mind that code isn't restricted to publishing on the web.  I know computer scientists who have made extraordinary contributions to the humanities without writing a single line of HTML or CSS.  If the Scholars' Lab seeks to bring computer science students into the fold, they need to be attracted by challenging problems (i.e., not web design).  This could include optical recognition of 3D geometry, quantitative analysis of massive volumes of humanities or social sciences data (not just text, but that could be a start), or augmented reality.  &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Looking back on my own career development, I wish I had learned information architecture a lot sooner: semantically correct ways of representing information and learning how information systems interact with one another.  And linked data.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>sselisker on "What would your dream DH apprenticeship opportunity involve?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/what-would-your-dream-dh-apprenticeship-opportunity-involve#post-1210</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2011 14:02:59 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>sselisker</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1210@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;This sounds like a wonderful program.  I'd like to draw on a wonderful experience as a graduate student involved in a digital project (redschoolhouse.org, with the UVA Writing Program and with some contact with the Scholar's Lab) in responding to the question.  &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I think, and I imagine you'd agree, that a &#34;bad&#34; version of such an internship would be to stick a grad student in a room to do some XML or whatever kind of markup for a whole summer, with no &#34;big picture&#34; benefits from participating in the program.  I think what I gained in &#34;big picture&#34; terms from working on a project for a year was: 1) learning how programmers think and 2) learning how project managers think.  Learning how project managers work is fairly easy to do, since one just needs to sit in on a lot of meetings to get the idea—but the benefit is that organizing a project from scratch at another institution would be much easier to do.  &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Thinking like a programmer has a steeper learning curve for most humanities grad students.  I know a lot of DHers who generally &#34;hack&#34;—figuring out through trial and error some rudiments of CSS or PHP—and that's fine for limited and local problems, but it in no way amounts to expertise.  But it seems like graduate students would be in a good position to learn some basic principles of programming (where to write subroutines, stacks, loops, etc.) and best practices, like documenting code and version control.  These skills, while, granted, still well below the BS level in computer science, would aid these graduate students in doing better-informed &#34;hacking&#34; and explaining computer concepts to others, as well as in the future when they'll be working with full-on programmers to put their own projects into motion.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I'd be excited to see an internship that involved some workshops or independent learning about programming, such that new knowledge might be put to use while participating hands-on in ongoing projects.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Alex Galarza on "What would your dream DH apprenticeship opportunity involve?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/what-would-your-dream-dh-apprenticeship-opportunity-involve#post-1205</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2011 13:16:11 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Alex Galarza</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1205@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;&#60;em&#62;Replying to @Bethany Nowviskie's &#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/what-would-your-dream-dh-apprenticeship-opportunity-involve#post-1204&#34;&#62;post&#60;/a&#62;:&#60;/em&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I would be interested in an apprenticeship that allow me to walk away with some tangible new skill and a completed project. For grads, it is important that we walk away from these apprenticeships with something beyond the CV line. I would love to gain experience coding and designing with people who do it for a living. With my own project in mind, my DH apprenticeship would enable me to create a very polished Omeka site for my primary sources and skills in HTML and Php to build my own digital dissertation.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Bethany Nowviskie on "What would your dream DH apprenticeship opportunity involve?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/what-would-your-dream-dh-apprenticeship-opportunity-involve#post-1204</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2011 11:23:21 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Bethany Nowviskie</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1204@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;The &#60;a href=&#34;http://lib.virginia.edu/scholarslab&#34;&#62;Scholars' Lab&#60;/a&#62; is about to get even  more intentional about the contribution it's making to the grad community and to graduate methodological training in DH at UVa.  As we bring on a bunch of new grad student journeymen (and women!) &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.scholarslab.org/announcements/student-jobs/&#34;&#62;all at once&#60;/a&#62;, we're wondering: &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;What would the specific elements of &#60;strong&#62;your&#60;/strong&#62; dream DH apprenticeship include?  What skills and experiences would you want gain?  What do you need most desperately?  What would you &#60;em&#62;not&#60;/em&#62; find useful or interesting?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;We'd love to hear from current grad students (either those gaining real-world DH skills somewhere or wishing they could) and from people past the apprenticeship phase who can share their top experiences and memories of learning on-the-job.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;MANY thanks for your help! This could become a pretty useful DH Answers thread for lots of projects and institutions...
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>mkirschenbaum on "How does one &#039;sell&#039; the Digital Humanities to a grad committee?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-does-one-sell-the-digital-humanities-to-a-grad-committee#post-1191</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2011 16:28:35 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>mkirschenbaum</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1191@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;John Unsworth pointed me to this thread and asked me to offer a reply.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I was in the enviable position of not having to work to &#34;sell&#34; DH to a committee at Virginia that included John and J. McGann, among others, but I can speak directly to the consequences of &#34;doing&#34; DH as an integral element of my dissertation work.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;The dissertation itself was conceived as a critical intervention in the emerging discourse around hypertext and electronic text more generally. The DH component of it was primarily in the realm of scholarly communication and information design, by means of writing the dissertation openly, in public, on the Web (1.0), in straight HTML. In essence, I was working toward the kind of open access scholarship we now see with resources like MediaCommons, CommentPress, Twitter, and so forth without any of that social media apparatus being in place (the dates here are roughly 1996-9). Nonetheless, even in this early rendition, the network turned out to be an excellent place to, well . . . network. Readers found my work online, including some of the more prominent critics and commentators in the field, which in turn led to my work getting linked to and cited, invitations to conferences, and so forth--that kind of recognition turned into the kind of near-term gratification that is so rare when one is embedded within the longue duree of scholarly dissertation writing.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I think the key take-away here is that whatever the specific form your digital humanities work takes, the salient argument to your committee has to be about scholarly communication and professionalization. On these terms the significance of DH is  unassailable. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;And may I offer one other piece of advice? Think of DH less as a &#34;thing,&#34; that is a bill of goods to be sold, and more as a kind of ethos, or commitment to the way your want to do your work, long-term, in whatever venue or circumstances you find yourself. Otherwise the risk is one of the &#34;digital&#34; becoming a kind of add-on, something that you can reward yourself with once you've done the &#34;foundational&#34; work of the dissertation. But tools, platforms, and networks are pretty foundational in and of themselves, or ought to be, or so it seems to me.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Good luck!
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Dorothea Salo on "How does one &#039;sell&#039; the Digital Humanities to a grad committee?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-does-one-sell-the-digital-humanities-to-a-grad-committee#post-1184</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 14:22:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Dorothea Salo</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1184@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Steve Hitchcock maintains &#60;a href=&#34;http://opcit.eprints.org/oacitation-biblio.html&#34;&#62;an entire webliography&#60;/a&#62; on the open-access citation-advantage question. It is as comprehensive as anything I know -- which means that not all the listed articles confirm an advantage!&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;A digital dissertation I have used as an intriguing example of same is &#60;a href=&#34;http://exploringthehyper.net/&#34;&#62;Exploring the Hype(r)&#60;/a&#62;. You might also like &#60;a href=&#34;http://digital.library.wisc.edu/1793/32316&#34;&#62;this music master's thesis&#60;/a&#62; (bias disclaimer: I archived that one).&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Hope this helps.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Alex Galarza on "How does one &#039;sell&#039; the Digital Humanities to a grad committee?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-does-one-sell-the-digital-humanities-to-a-grad-committee#post-1183</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 14:09:31 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Alex Galarza</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1183@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;At the Digivangelism session at Great Lakes Thatcamp last month, many people brought up some great points regarding converting our colleagues to the digital humanities. As a graduate student I pointed to the importance of 'selling' the digital humanities to a committee. By 'selling', I mean justifying the time we spend building Omeka archives, Zotero libraries, using TEI, and making our work openly accessible. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Some campers brought up excellent points, such as how open-access scholarship is cited more frequently than material behind paywalls. Many advisers and committee members ask tough questions about our time commitments and it would be beneficial for grads to these sorts of stories, statistics, and examples at their fingertips. This way, we can answer concerns by saying &#34;Incorporating DH methods into my project will make me a better scholar and teacher because... x/y/z, and check out these links that say so!&#34;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;So, I am asking for articles, studies, concrete examples, and any other sorts of evidence to compile into a post titled &#34;Having the DH conversation with your committee&#34; for gradhacker.org, a Profhacker-like site that will be launching this June. Do you have the article that proves open-access scholarship is more frequently cited? Do you have an excellent example of a digital dissertation? Do you have a blog post about using Zotero to collaborate with other grads in a writing group? A how-to on building an online presence and how it helps your work? I am looking for ammunition to answer not only tech-hostile committee members, but mentors who are concerned about their students' time commitments, project feasibility, and the rewards of embracing DH tools. Thanks in advance for the links to articles, posts, stories, etc...&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;For an idea of how the digivangelism session panned out, Amanda French's notes can be found here: &#60;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/jH0Ha0&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://bit.ly/jH0Ha0&#60;/a&#62;
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Bethany Nowviskie on "Reading recommendations for a GIS newbie?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/reading-recommendations-for-a-gis-newbie#post-1127</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2011 19:44:52 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Bethany Nowviskie</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1127@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;And a GIS newbie in the digital humanities might want to start here:&#60;br /&#62;
&#60;a href=&#34;http://spatial.scholarslab.org/&#34;&#62;http://spatial.scholarslab.org/&#60;/a&#62;&#60;br /&#62;
-- an NEH-funded, community-driven &#34;Spatial Humanities&#34; site from the Scholar's Lab, just launched today!&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;It includes some great essays by Jo Guldi framing the &#34;spatial turn&#34; across the disciplines, and a nascent, peer-reviewed set of step-by-step tutorials -- as well as a variety of crowdsourced resources drawn from Zotero groups, hashtags, and sites like... DH Answers! :)
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>saschmidt8 on "Reading recommendations for a GIS newbie?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/reading-recommendations-for-a-gis-newbie#post-948</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2011 18:46:41 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>saschmidt8</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">948@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Hi Eric&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I'd recommend the following books and taking a look at the bibliography and resources pages on the HGIS website&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;&#60;a href=&#34;http://www.hgis.org.uk/bibliography.htm&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://www.hgis.org.uk/bibliography.htm&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;&#60;a href=&#34;http://www.hgis.org.uk/resources.htm&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://www.hgis.org.uk/resources.htm&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Gregory, Ian N. and Paul S. Ell. Historical GIS: Technologies, Methodologies, and Scholarship. Cambridge Studies in Historical Geography. 2007&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Sinton, Diana Stuart and Jennifer J. Lund Understanding Place: GIS and Mapping Across the Curriculm  ESRI Press, 2006.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Also though I haven't had a chance to read it yet, I think the following book may also be of interest&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Bodenhamer, David J. et al  The Spatial Humanities: GIS and the Future of Humanities Scholarship Indiana U. Press, 2010&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Sara Schmidt
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Kelly Johnston on "Reading recommendations for a GIS newbie?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/reading-recommendations-for-a-gis-newbie#post-917</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2011 22:25:21 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Kelly Johnston</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">917@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;&#60;em&#62;Replying to @Alex Galarza's &#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/reading-recommendations-for-a-gis-newbie#post-907&#34;&#62;post&#60;/a&#62;:&#60;/em&#62;&#60;br /&#62;
ArcGIS is the most widely-used GIS software, but qGIS is an ever-improving alternative.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Alex Galarza on "Reading recommendations for a GIS newbie?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/reading-recommendations-for-a-gis-newbie#post-907</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2011 13:52:09 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Alex Galarza</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">907@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;&#60;em&#62;Replying to @Kelly Johnston's &#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/reading-recommendations-for-a-gis-newbie#post-852&#34;&#62;post&#60;/a&#62;:&#60;/em&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I found this post very helpful to wet my beak with some reading. After reading from a few of your links, I was wondering if you might be able to answer a follow-up question: My adviser asked if I was familiar enough with GIS to produce maps for his manuscript, to which I replied no. Is there a standard for historians and anthropologists using GIS to produce maps for their books? Is it qGIS? Should I start with qGIS and move onto something else if I want to do my own maps for my own dissertation in the years to come? Thanks!
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Kelly Johnston on "Reading recommendations for a GIS newbie?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/reading-recommendations-for-a-gis-newbie#post-852</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2010 17:45:30 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Kelly Johnston</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">852@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Hi Eric,&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;A few suggestions:&#60;br /&#62;
An engaging mappy introduction to GIS and its application: &#60;a HREF=&#34;http://maptogether.org/nonprofit-mapping&#34;&#62;Maptogether&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;David Rumsey’s take on historical maps in GIS: &#60;a HREF=&#34;http://www.davidrumsey.com/gis/ch01.pdf &#34;&#62;Rumsey&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;A gentle (and excellent) introduction to GIS with examples using qGIS, one of the best free open source GIS packages: &#60;a HREF=&#34;http://download.osgeo.org/qgis/doc/manual/qgis-1.0.0_a-gentle-gis-introduction_en.pdf&#34;&#62;qGIS&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Real world issues of cartography and presentation: &#60;a HREF=&#34;http://www.shadedrelief.com/bubble/patterson_cp65.pdf&#34;&#62;Cartographic Perspectives&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Librarians' lists of best GIS resources: &#60;a HREF=&#34;http://presentations.ala.org/images/e/e8/GIS_Program_Top_5_Resources.pdf&#34;&#62;Top 5 GIS Resources&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;The Bigger Picture: Maps are not the world, they are propositions: &#60;a HREF=&#34;http://makingmaps.owu.edu/this_is_not_krygier_wood.pdf&#34;&#62;This Is Not The World&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Kelly Johnston
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
