<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- generator="bbPress/1.0.2" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Humanities Questions &#38; Answers &#187; Forum: About DHAnswers - Recent Posts</title>
		<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/forum/about-dhanswers</link>
		<description>Digital Humanities Questions &amp; Answers &#187; Forum: About DHAnswers - Recent Posts</description>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2018 16:27:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<generator>http://bbpress.org/?v=1.0.2</generator>
		<textInput>
			<title><![CDATA[Search]]></title>
			<description><![CDATA[Search all topics from these forums.]]></description>
			<name>q</name>
			<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/search.php</link>
		</textInput>
		<atom:link href="/rss/forum/about-dhanswers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
			 
				<title>Amanda Visconti on "DH Q&#38;A is closed to new questions and answers (read more)"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/dh-qa-is-closed-to-new-questions-and-answers-read-more#post-2409</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 12:59:25 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Amanda Visconti</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2409@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;The Digital Humanities Questions &#38;amp; Answers website is currently being migrated to a read-only, archived version of the site. Follow @ach_org for news about the migration.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>aelang on "Good 3D scanners to use alongside a 3D printer?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/best-3d-scanner#post-2397</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 16:22:56 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>aelang</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2397@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I have the chance to get a 3D scanner alongside a 3D printer for a DH-lab-to-be, and although there's lots of useful posts here about 3D printers, there doesn't seem to be much about 3D scanners. If anyone has any recommendations or tips, I'd be glad to hear them. It's not going to be state-of-the-art stuff (yet), but there's a lot of scope for interesting work with colleagues at my institution working on digital cultural heritage so I'd like to get something that will at least provide the opportunity for people to pilot ideas or create a proof of concept.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Arno Bosse on "Tech Foundation for a DH Center Lab"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/tech-foundation-for-a-dh-center-lab#post-2284</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2015 21:46:35 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Arno Bosse</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2284@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Something else occurred to me. It's just a small thing but might have a impact down the road depending on your needs. Let's say you're also interested in machine learning, particularly image recognition, where training a model can be computationally taxing. I've noticed that while many toolkits (e.g. Caffe) offer (or even depend) on GPU based optimizations they invariably only support CUDA, which means in effect an nVidia graphics card. However most current Macs and also many older models and of course regular PCs too are sold with video cards from AMD/ATI. So then you'd be stuck or at minimum would need to pony up for another card(s). Consequently, probably a good case could be made for getting one reasonably fast, headless, vanilla PC with lots of RAM and dual video cards to use as a computation server. For example, as mentioned, for machine learning experiments, but also as a place to run MATLAB or Mathematica etc.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Update: A few days later I came across this very useful report on exactly this topic: &#60;a href=&#34;https://timdettmers.wordpress.com/2014/08/14/which-gpu-for-deep-learning/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;https://timdettmers.wordpress.com/2014/08/14/which-gpu-for-deep-learning/&#60;/a&#62;
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Patrick Murray-John on "Tech Foundation for a DH Center Lab"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/tech-foundation-for-a-dh-center-lab#post-2283</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 16:15:45 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Patrick Murray-John</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2283@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;+ several million for Arno's idea of leaving 25% for experiments and risks. Not only does that reflect the reality of doing DH, and being able to respond to student and faculty needs as they emerge quickly. If the administration is willing to build that in, that's a great signal of their real understanding of and commitment to what a DH lab should be. If you can get that, you'll have a great DH lab!
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Arno Bosse on "Tech Foundation for a DH Center Lab"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/tech-foundation-for-a-dh-center-lab#post-2282</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 13:27:38 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Arno Bosse</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2282@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;If the lab is to focus on DH as text analysis then you might want to reconsider buying 6-10 &#34;workstations&#34; (in the sense of high-end PCs) at all. Instead, purchase much cheaper Mini PCs. These will be more than up to the task. Then again, you may not want to deal with creating individual user accounts on these machines or else, cleaning-up the user-directories or working with your IT group to mount shared home directories. I certainly wouldn't.. So If you're really going to be focusing on text anyway, why not do something more radical and purchase a series of ultra cheap Raspberry Pi2s instead., attach these to some big, cheap monitors and give each student a fast 16GB SD card at the start of the class. A learning moment, if you will. The new Raspberry Pi 2 has quad-core CPU, 1GB RAM, runs Ubuntu and even comes bundled with Mathematica v10. It'll be more than capable enough for R, MALLET and the like. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Then, since DH is obviously not just about texts, take some of all the money you've saved and buy just one or two well-equipped PCs or iMacs. Two should be more than enough since you've already got 10 or more MiniPCs or Raspberry Pi computers making up the bulk of the lab. And perhaps, I would not even buy these two workstations, I would lease them on a 3 year replacement cycle. Otherwise, come 3-4-5 years from now, someone is going to have to go back to the Dean or whomever and ask for another one-off capital investment. Instead, if your institution is also kicking in some funding, return (!) some of this capital funding you have now and ask for a raise in your operating budget instead (something most grants will not be able to provide). Alternatively, hold onto some of the money you saved by not purchasing workstations and plan/collaborate with other departments on purchasing various kinds of input devices for use in an experimental setting, such as a portable audio recorder, a basic scanner, a cheap video camera, maybe a portable (GoPro-like) camera or a cheap (even &#34;toy&#34;) 3D scanner. The general idea being that students should not be exposed just to the (comparatively) clean world of texts but also to noisier, dirtier, computationally less tractable &#34;real-world&#34; A/D sources. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Elsewhere on DHAnswers someone made a comment that a lot of time was spent in their DH lab thinking about furniture (tables, table layouts etc). I think this is very good advice. A place in your lab (e.g. a long, tall table) where students can plug-in devices, place their books or tools, carry over a Raspberry Pi, store artifacts, and build and hack at things together in a group would be great, don't you think? Heck, I'd even put it in the center of the room. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Patrick made a very good point in his comment above, &#34;No matter what choices you make, though, you'll be implicitly guiding what kinds of DH work you are able to facilitate.&#34; He's right. Perhaps, as a practical response to that, plan and spend 75% (?) of your budget on what you know you want to do with the students. And leave 25% for cheap HW investments in experiments, risks and whatever might conceivably stick to the wall.. and mitigate the risk &#38;amp; difficulty of deciding what this might be by drawing in other units such as special collections, theatre, media studies, art history, studio art, linguistics, local/campus museums/archives etc.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Patrick Murray-John on "Tech Foundation for a DH Center Lab"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/tech-foundation-for-a-dh-center-lab#post-2280</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 16:55:39 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Patrick Murray-John</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2280@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Without a greater sense of the types of projects, it'll be a little hard to make decisions. If there's an emphasis on media production, &#60;a href='http://convergence.umw.edu/multimedia-editing-lab-soundbooth/'&#62;this media lab at UMW&#60;/a&#62; might be a good model, or at least give some example ideas.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Other software that might be fairly common for DH work:&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;* &#38;lt;oXygen/&#38;gt; XML editor&#60;br /&#62;
* R statistics package&#60;br /&#62;
* MALLET topic modeling&#60;br /&#62;
* Some kind of code editor&#60;br /&#62;
* Some FTP application&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Which of those would actually be used depends a lot on specific types of projects. No matter what choices you make, though, you'll be implicitly guiding what kinds of DH work you are able to facilitate. Those would probably cover a good range of interests, though.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>kwsherwood on "Tech Foundation for a DH Center Lab"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/tech-foundation-for-a-dh-center-lab#post-2279</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 02:33:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>kwsherwood</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2279@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Looking at the opportunity to write a quick proposal for equipment to be used in a new DH lab (space for 6, max 10 workstations) and thinking about generic needs of future colleagues and graduate student researchers.  The quandry -- we lack information about specific project needs which might emerge.  Any recommendations on the foundation or baseline for such a lab?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>ripunbarik99@gmail.com on "what is correctional socialwork?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/what-is-correctional-socialwork#post-2245</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2014 14:17:47 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>ripunbarik99@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2245@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;plz tel me sir that how can a social worker do oe practice his proffesion with prisoners??
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Bethany Nowviskie on "OK, I just joined and saw the highlighted question about what this q and a is"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/ok-i-just-joined-and-saw-the-highlighted-question-about-what-this-q-and-a-is#post-2115</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2013 12:48:16 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Bethany Nowviskie</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2115@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;PS: my view is that if you are a librarian seeking to get an initial grounding in digital scholarship and to be most generally helpful to the faculty and students in your area, probably the worst thing you could do is devote a lot of time up front to learning to &#34;code.&#34; Librarianship has likely already provided you with all the skills you need to get rolling! I'd suggest moving outward from specific cases. Conduct a solid reference interview to figure out what the scholar who has come to you is really trying to do, and then use your research skills to help him or her review the literature and locate past projects in that particular area. Once you find some models, research the technologies behind them and seek ways to learn together! In my experience, you'll build more generalized &#34;digital humanities&#34; capacity at your library by working on a real project (even if it's rather specialized) than if you spent that time either on overviews or on learning a programming language without a specific reason to.  Good luck!
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Bethany Nowviskie on "OK, I just joined and saw the highlighted question about what this q and a is"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/ok-i-just-joined-and-saw-the-highlighted-question-about-what-this-q-and-a-is#post-2114</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2013 12:33:42 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Bethany Nowviskie</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2114@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Ted has shared two great links. You might also find it interesting to read through the &#60;a href=&#34;http://dhsi.org/courses.php&#34;&#62;variety of courses&#60;/a&#62; on offer at this year's Digital Humanities Summer institute, to get a sense of the methods and skills appropriate to answering different kinds of research questions or assisting with different sorts of projects. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Some other resources that may be of particular interest to you (and me! I'm a librarian, too) are &#60;a href=&#34;http://devdh.org&#34;&#62;DevDH&#60;/a&#62; (still under development) and &#60;a href=&#34;http://acrl.ala.org/dh/&#34;&#62;dh+lib&#60;/a&#62;.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>tedunderwood on "OK, I just joined and saw the highlighted question about what this q and a is"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/ok-i-just-joined-and-saw-the-highlighted-question-about-what-this-q-and-a-is#post-2113</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2013 12:21:16 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>tedunderwood</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2113@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Oh, and a piece that answers your question perhaps even more directly is Miriam Posner's fabulous, incomparable blog post &#60;a href=&#34;http://miriamposner.com/blog/how-did-they-make-that/&#34;&#62;&#34;How Did They Make That?&#34;&#60;/a&#62;
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>tedunderwood on "OK, I just joined and saw the highlighted question about what this q and a is"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/ok-i-just-joined-and-saw-the-highlighted-question-about-what-this-q-and-a-is#post-2112</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2013 12:15:22 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>tedunderwood</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2112@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Lisa Spiro's piece on &#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalscholarship.wordpress.com/2011/10/14/getting-started-in-the-digital-humanities/&#34;&#62;&#34;getting started in the digital humanities&#34;&#60;/a&#62; is very good.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;There are &#34;off the shelf&#34; systems that can address particular &#60;em&#62;aspects&#60;/em&#62; of projects. E.g. Omeka, MALLET, Gephi, Voyant. But my experience has been that you often need to be able to code if you want to bind pieces together in new ways. (In my own subfield of text mining, I would change &#34;often&#34; to &#34;always&#34;; this might be less true in other subfields.) However, I'm not a librarian, and people also disagree very strongly about the necessity of coding, so in the end you'll need to make your own decision.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>raischmj on "OK, I just joined and saw the highlighted question about what this q and a is"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/ok-i-just-joined-and-saw-the-highlighted-question-about-what-this-q-and-a-is#post-2110</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2013 11:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>raischmj</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2110@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;...that is, what it is for. Not to ask about schools, but sorry, I am a librarian seeking to transition to working with digital humanities. Could I please just ask what training I really need for this? writing code only? Are there off the shelf systems for digital projects that require less technical training? if I could get some answers to these queries, I promise I won't bother you with FINDING the training. I need a better handle on what to look for myself. thanks.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>mdalmau on "Are any libraries using Neatline?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/are-any-libraries-using-neatline#post-2109</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 17:52:36 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>mdalmau</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2109@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;So the non-UVa and -IU folks understand the context ... the IU Libraries basically wants to use Neatline as a standalone tool.  For the faculty projects in question, all will be using Omeka, but at least two are not relying on the Neatline mapping features at the item level (the monographs, maps, pamphlets) but rather discrete data sets compiled from various sources including those we would feature in an Omeka exhibit. To get around this, which is what's causing the heartache, we need to set up an Omeka collection for essentially data that we would then like to render in Neatline (and not in Omeka proper).  Once we have these initial points plotted, the researchers can then layer the maps with annotations, cross-references, etc.  &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;We were exploring ways that we could streamline the process for batching chunks of geo and temporal data into Neatline with little to no technical wizardry or workarounds to make it happen (i.e., use of existing plugins).  Mostly because we are hoping to establish Map-Based Discovery (digital library) &#34;Services&#34; for which Neatline would feature significantly (at least that's my hope). Obviously, to establish a service model, we need to be able to use existing tools and workflows as much as possible.  However, we don't necessarily expect SLab folks to go and do the work to make this happen!  I do think that in trying to wrangle Neatline in the way we have, we encountered more obstacles than expected, and soon began to realize that we didn't perhaps understand the architecture as well as we thought.  It just so happened that in talking with David McClure, the Neatline crew has already encountered requests for supporting a use case similar to our, and we may have a more elegant solution yet!  &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;As Brianna and I mentioned to David, we would like to contribute what we can toward this endeavor.  It won't be code-based, but we have compiled lots of parallel documentation (workflows, scenarios, etc.) that I probably too narrowly label &#34;from the library's perspective&#34; that we'd like to share with the broader community and can work with SLab to integrate the relevant bits into Neatline's existing documentation. The community would also benefit greatly by seeing accompanying implementation documentation along with the Neatline &#34;demo&#34;/featured projects.  Perhaps IU could help wrangle existing documentation for a few exemplars?  (I know -- I said that, right?  crazy!).
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>rondauva on "Are any libraries using Neatline?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/are-any-libraries-using-neatline#post-2108</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 17:23:20 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>rondauva</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2108@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;&#60;em&#62;Replying to @&#60;a href='/profile/bhmarsha'&#62;bhmarsha&#60;/a&#62;'s &#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/are-any-libraries-using-neatline#post-2107&#34;&#62;post&#60;/a&#62;:&#60;/em&#62;&#60;br /&#62;
Hi Brianna, I'm the project manager here in the Scholars' Lab, and I support our faculty Neatline installations. As Bethany said above, we've installed Neatline for about a dozen faculty members for use in their own research and in the classroom, and we're not getting reports of the kinds of issues that you've experienced, but our local use cases are a more in line with the uses originally envisioned for Neatline.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Your use case has created lots of discussion here in the SLab offices, and we've scheduled a formal meeting for next week to sit down together and hash out the next phase of Neatline development here at UVa.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I'd love to chat further with you about this, and especially to understand where you hit blocks as you started to work with Neatline to figure out how we might mitigate those for other users. You can reach me at rag9b (at) virginia.edu.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
