<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- generator="bbPress/1.0.2" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Humanities Questions &#38; Answers &#187; Tag: network analysis - Recent Topics</title>
		<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/tags/network-analysis</link>
		<description>Digital Humanities Questions &amp; Answers &#187; Tag: network analysis - Recent Topics</description>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2016 03:44:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<generator>http://bbpress.org/?v=1.0.2</generator>
		<textInput>
			<title><![CDATA[Search]]></title>
			<description><![CDATA[Search all topics from these forums.]]></description>
			<name>q</name>
			<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/search.php</link>
		</textInput>
		<atom:link href="/rss/tags/network-analysis/topics" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
			 
				<title>Josh on "How does one prepare and use data for network analysis with Gephi?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-does-one-prepare-and-use-data-for-network-analysis-with-gephi#post-1880</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 12:09:22 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Josh</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1880@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;There are plenty of tutorials on the web that are useful for learning Gephi, but I've encountered a much steeper learning curve for the steps prior—such as extracting and preparing data from literary texts to be used with Gephi. In my example, I am interested in performing a network analysis of the social networks (both real and imaginary) in the works of Enrique Vila-Matas (I'd eventually like to expand this corpus to other authors). Acquiring the digital text and working with Gephi I can do (or the latter learn), but it's the very important intermediary steps of preparing the data (extraction of names and places to getting those in a form—database? spreadsheet?—analyzable by Gephi) that I need help with. Any good reading, tutorials, or other resources out there? Other recommendations? I'm working on a Mac and have a limited knowledge of Python, so any Mac-friendly software would be a big help. Thanks!
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Lisa Rhody on "Does anyone have experience using the newest 3.5 Leximancer software?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/does-anyone-have-experience-using-the-newest-35-leximancer-software#post-1397</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2011 08:12:52 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Lisa Rhody</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1397@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Leximancer (&#60;a href=&#34;https://www.leximancer.com)&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;https://www.leximancer.com)&#60;/a&#62;, an Australian, pay for use, text analysis software package seems intriguing.  It claims to be able to create topic and concept based network visualizations and includes among its filters a sentiment analyzer.  It's not cheap.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;If you do have experience with it?  Which type did you use?  The pay-per-use? The monthly portal? or the stand alone? Why?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
