<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- generator="bbPress/1.0.2" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Humanities Questions &#38; Answers &#187; Tag: nook - Recent Posts</title>
		<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/tags/nook</link>
		<description>Digital Humanities Questions &amp; Answers &#187; Tag: nook - Recent Posts</description>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2016 06:21:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<generator>http://bbpress.org/?v=1.0.2</generator>
		<textInput>
			<title><![CDATA[Search]]></title>
			<description><![CDATA[Search all topics from these forums.]]></description>
			<name>q</name>
			<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/search.php</link>
		</textInput>
		<atom:link href="/rss/tags/nook/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
			 
				<title>Sharon K. Goetz on "Alternatives to InDesign for creating multimedia ebooks?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/alternatives-to-indesign-for-creating-multimedia-ebooks/page/2#post-2034</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2013 13:19:30 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Sharon K. Goetz</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2034@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;An update to my own earlier comment and a partial reply to Wally Grotophorst's: I have since had cause to use Sigil to &#60;em&#62;correct&#60;/em&#62; the imperfect epub export produced by current Calibre. I would very much recommend Sigil over Calibre for epub2 at this point. (The document in question was a &#34;reprint&#34; collection of stories, poems, and review essays for a webzine, and thus with some visual complications--indented lines of verse--as well as structural requirements analogous to a chaptered book's.)
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Kevin Hawkins on "Alternatives to InDesign for creating multimedia ebooks?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/alternatives-to-indesign-for-creating-multimedia-ebooks/page/2#post-2033</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2013 19:30:13 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Kevin Hawkins</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2033@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Amazon sells books in print and in formats that can be read by Amazon Kindle devices.  Sound and film obviously cannot be in a print book, and I believe that the Kindle formats do not yet support these either.  (On the other hand, iBooks Author allows you to create ebooks with these types of media, but then they can be used on Apple, not Amazon, devices.)&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;So you will need to determine whether you are willing to omit some of your content in the version sold on Amazon in order to reach the audience found there.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Pedram on "Alternatives to InDesign for creating multimedia ebooks?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/alternatives-to-indesign-for-creating-multimedia-ebooks/page/2#post-2031</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2013 09:22:07 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Pedram</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2031@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Dear kevin,&#60;br /&#62;
Thanks for your kind reply. My project cover both cases, yes I want to provide it on amazon and also have some part of that (not all pages) as project online. But have it as a book on amazon is the main aim.&#60;br /&#62;
Thanks again for your helps.&#60;br /&#62;
Best&#60;br /&#62;
Pedram
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Kevin Hawkins on "Alternatives to InDesign for creating multimedia ebooks?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/alternatives-to-indesign-for-creating-multimedia-ebooks/page/2#post-2018</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2013 23:43:36 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Kevin Hawkins</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2018@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;On Miriam's original question on this thread, if you aren't in a position to start with webpages or TEI and want to be able to work with things more visually, see &#60;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Category:Free_desktop_publishing_software&#34;&#62;Wikipedia's list of free desktop publishing software&#60;/a&#62;.  Some of these may be able to produce EPUB files as InDesign can, and they may let you embed multimedia content.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;The easy-to-use tool for creating multimedia ebooks is iBooks Author, but your content is then locked into Apple's proprietary flavor of EPUB or in PDF and can only be read on an iPad.  See &#60;a href=&#34;http://wiki.publishing.umich.edu/IBooksAuthor&#34;&#62;our guide to iBooks Author&#60;/a&#62;.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;As for Pedram's recent question on this thread, there is no simple answer here.  Answers to a few questions will help guide you in the right direction:&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;a) Do you need for this book to be sold as an e-book on Amazon, in the iBook Store, or in another retail outlet?  Or are you content to put files on your own website and let people download from there?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;b) Do you need for a user to be able to read the book on an e-reader, or is it okay to require them to have a web browser?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Pedram on "Alternatives to InDesign for creating multimedia ebooks?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/alternatives-to-indesign-for-creating-multimedia-ebooks/page/2#post-2016</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2013 13:21:47 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Pedram</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2016@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Hi everyone,&#60;br /&#62;
I am a visual anthropologist and want to know if you can advise me which way is better for me to publish one of my research projects electronically.&#60;br /&#62;
My work is about material culture and their technics of production. Therefore in my book I will have texts, photos, maps, sounds, films and because of the nature of my research I need to create links between all of this. But please don’t forget my target are mostly social scientists: anthropologists, archaeologists, sociologists,…&#60;br /&#62;
So can you kindly let me know what is your feedback? Shall I use one of the ready programs which we can find on the net or I should find someone to write such program for my publication project.&#60;br /&#62;
Thanks in advance for your kind supports.&#60;br /&#62;
Dr. Pedram Khosronejad&#60;br /&#62;
Department of Social Anthropology&#60;br /&#62;
71 North Street&#60;br /&#62;
University of St. Andrews&#60;br /&#62;
St. Andrews, Fife, Scotland KY16 9AL&#60;br /&#62;
Tel: +44 (1334) 461968&#60;br /&#62;
Fax: +44 (1334) 462985&#60;br /&#62;
Email: &#60;a href=&#34;mailto:pedram.khosronejad@st-andrews.ac.uk&#34;&#62;pedram.khosronejad@st-andrews.ac.uk&#60;/a&#62;&#60;br /&#62;
&#60;a href=&#34;http://www.st-andrews.ac.uk/anthropology/files/staff/142/CV.pdf&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://www.st-andrews.ac.uk/anthropology/files/staff/142/CV.pdf&#60;/a&#62;
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Arno Bosse on "Alternatives to InDesign for creating multimedia ebooks?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/alternatives-to-indesign-for-creating-multimedia-ebooks/page/2#post-1248</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 10:31:55 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Arno Bosse</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1248@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I just discovered that Apple's Pages can export documents into .epub (in that sense it's a similar suggestion to Scrivener, which I'll have to try out next). I've tested the Pages epub export feature with text documents that included images, tables and footnotes - all were converted into epub without issues (i.e. I confirmed that it looked and worked as expected on an iPhone, with the Adobe Digital Editions app and that the files could be opened with Calbre and Sigil). &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;[Update] I see that there is an excellent discussion of the pros and cons of exporting epub from &#60;a href=&#34;http://blog.threepress.org/2011/06/01/can-an-author-create-an-epub-file-using-normal-tools-part-1-pages/&#34;&#62;Pages&#60;/a&#62; and &#60;a href=&#34;http://blog.threepress.org/2011/06/02/can-an-author-create-an-epub-using-normal-tools-part-2-scrivener/&#34;&#62;Scrivener&#60;/a&#62; on the &#60;a href=&#34;http://blog.threepress.org&#34;&#62;ThreePress Blog&#60;/a&#62;.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;On a related note, if you're specifically targeting the iphone/ipad I know that there was a session at WWDC 2011 that described best practices for how to create both flowing text and fixed layout (epub based) ebooks (including features like embedded HTML5 video and audio) for these devices. Unfortunately the content of the video &#38;amp; the slides for the session are still under non-disclosure. Check back in a few weeks if you're not a registered Apple developer.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Wally Grotophorst on "Alternatives to InDesign for creating multimedia ebooks?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/alternatives-to-indesign-for-creating-multimedia-ebooks#post-659</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2010 17:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Wally Grotophorst</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">659@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;One more suggestion (Mac only)&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Over the past week or so I've been using &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.literatureandlatte.com/scrivener.php&#34;&#62;Scrivener&#60;/a&#62; 2.0 for Mac.  It has the ability to export .epub as well as .mobi (for Kindle) files.    I haven't tried epub as I'm a Kindle user but I can tell you Scrivener does a very nice job producing multimedia (e.g., text and images) documents for Kindle.  You have to go to &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/kindlepublishing&#34;&#62;Amazon&#60;/a&#62; and download their free kindlegen utility (Scrivener walks you through that one-time process) and then it's really as simple as click and publish to any number of formats.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;RTF, PDF, Word (doc,docx), Open Office (.odt), ePub, Kindle (.mobi), html, plain text and few others (e.g., multimarkdown)
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Wally Grotophorst on "Alternatives to InDesign for creating multimedia ebooks?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/alternatives-to-indesign-for-creating-multimedia-ebooks#post-632</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2010 15:27:09 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Wally Grotophorst</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">632@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;You might think about giving Calibre a try (Windows, Mac or Linux)&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;&#60;a href=&#34;http://calibre-ebook.com/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://calibre-ebook.com/&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Can create epub format but also does MOBI (for you Kindle)&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Converts between many formats.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Oh yeah, it does have just about the ugliest, counter-intuitive interface I've ever seen (and I've been around a pretty long time).
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Dorothea Salo on "Alternatives to InDesign for creating multimedia ebooks?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/alternatives-to-indesign-for-creating-multimedia-ebooks#post-608</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2010 09:18:22 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Dorothea Salo</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">608@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Slight caution with Sophie: its developers (mighty and brilliant though they are) have a history of abandoning projects. Also, you will be cutting off a lot of your potential audience if you require a software download, no matter how cross-platform (and no iOS or Android support would give me pause as well).
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Miriam Posner on "Alternatives to InDesign for creating multimedia ebooks?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/alternatives-to-indesign-for-creating-multimedia-ebooks#post-606</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2010 09:12:38 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Miriam Posner</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">606@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;&#60;em&#62;Replying to @Mark Sample's &#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/alternatives-to-indesign-for-creating-multimedia-ebooks#post-602&#34;&#62;post&#60;/a&#62;:&#60;/em&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Sophie! Wow, never heard of it, but it looks terrific. I'll definitely check it out.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Mark Sample on "Alternatives to InDesign for creating multimedia ebooks?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/alternatives-to-indesign-for-creating-multimedia-ebooks#post-602</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2010 07:51:32 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Mark Sample</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">602@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I'm surprised nobody has mentioned &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.sophieproject.org/&#34;&#62;Sophie&#60;/a&#62;, an open source project from the Institute for the Future of the Book. Sophie is especially designed as a platform to create media-rich, interactive books.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;The chief drawback of Sophie is that Sophie ebooks require the Sophie Reader. But that's not so much of a drawback when you consider that the Sophie Reader runs on Windows, Mac, and Linux.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Miriam Posner on "Alternatives to InDesign for creating multimedia ebooks?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/alternatives-to-indesign-for-creating-multimedia-ebooks#post-599</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2010 21:46:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Miriam Posner</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">599@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;&#60;em&#62;Replying to @Patrick Murray-John's &#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/alternatives-to-indesign-for-creating-multimedia-ebooks#post-593&#34;&#62;post&#60;/a&#62;:&#60;/em&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Patrick, I love Anthologize and would personally love to see multimedia support. I'll file a ticket! I don't know how common multimedia ebooks are -- as you can tell, I'm still figuring this whole ebook thing out -- but what I'm hearing from grad students is something along the lines of, &#34;I have this awesome [public domain] work that I know better than anyone else in the world, and I'd really like to create an ebook that's enriched with multimedia annotation.&#34; I'm wondering how I can help support this. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I really like the idea of going from WordPress, which a number of grad students are already familiar with, to a multimedia-enhanced Anthologize ebook.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;And thanks again, all. This has really helped me figure out which questions I need to be asking about which technologies. Googling was leading me down too many garden paths.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>sebastian.rahtz@gmail.com on "Alternatives to InDesign for creating multimedia ebooks?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/alternatives-to-indesign-for-creating-multimedia-ebooks#post-595</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2010 15:44:46 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>sebastian.rahtz@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">595@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;What I meant by target audience is that if you are producing content for eg iPad and iPhone, you can safely use video and audio in epub, confident that your readers will enjoy them. If you are targetting any ebook reader in the world (eg inc. Kindle) then you'd better be very conservative indeed in the facilities you use.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Another route is Apple's iWork Pages, by the way, supposedly has ePub export (never tried it).&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;BTW I know InDesign is not cheap, and is complex, but actually it probably only costs a day's salary or less. So the investment is not that great. Personally, I'd always prefer to edit XML and go from there but I realize I am in a minority :-}
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Patrick Murray-John on "Alternatives to InDesign for creating multimedia ebooks?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/alternatives-to-indesign-for-creating-multimedia-ebooks#post-593</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2010 13:17:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Patrick Murray-John</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">593@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;If it isn't too rude to plug a project I'm a developer for, the &#60;a href=&#34;http://anthologize.org&#34;&#62;Anthologize&#60;/a&#62; wordpress plugin is designed to take content from a WP site and publish it as ePub (among other formats). It's still early on (latest release was 0.5-alpha. read: still bugs and issues), but might be something to look at.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;The multimedia aspect is interesting. . . is support for that getting common in ebook readers? If so, there might be some tickets to file in Anthologize! :)
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Miriam Posner on "Alternatives to InDesign for creating multimedia ebooks?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/alternatives-to-indesign-for-creating-multimedia-ebooks#post-587</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2010 18:59:39 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Miriam Posner</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">587@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;First of all, thanks a million -- this is terrifically helpful.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Sharon, would you be willing to say a bit more about the complexity of moving from XML to ePub? Or if it's too complicated to go into, can you recommend a resource on the subject?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Sebastian, can you explain what you mean about a target audience? Do you mean that audio and video components might be less stable over time because they're not formally supported by the ePub?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;And if anyone cares to weigh in on the relative merits of ePub versus other ebook formats, I'd be very grateful for that response as well.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
