<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- generator="bbPress/1.0.2" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Humanities Questions &#38; Answers &#187; Forum: Project Management &#38; DH Professions - Recent Posts</title>
		<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/forum/project-management</link>
		<description>Digital Humanities Questions &amp; Answers &#187; Forum: Project Management &amp; DH Professions - Recent Posts</description>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 21:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<generator>http://bbpress.org/?v=1.0.2</generator>
		<textInput>
			<title><![CDATA[Search]]></title>
			<description><![CDATA[Search all topics from these forums.]]></description>
			<name>q</name>
			<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/search.php</link>
		</textInput>
		<atom:link href="/rss/forum/project-management" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
			 
				<title>Patrick Murray-John on "Why should DH coursework count towards a literature grad program?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/why-should-dh-coursework-count-towards-a-literature-grad-program#post-2403</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 16:15:11 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Patrick Murray-John</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2403@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;There's also the MLA's &#60;a href='https://www.mla.org/About-Us/Governance/Committees/Committee-Listings/Professional-Issues/Committee-on-Information-Technology/Guidelines-for-Evaluating-Work-in-Digital-Humanities-and-Digital-Media'&#62;Guide for evaluating DH work&#60;/a&#62;. It's (sadly) less about grad students than tenure and promotion, but seems to still apply. If nothing else, the fact that MLA (and AHA, for that matter) have produced guides for DH evaluation says clearly that the professional organization says that DH does, in fact, correlate with language, literature, and teaching.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Amanda Visconti on "Why should DH coursework count towards a literature grad program?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/why-should-dh-coursework-count-towards-a-literature-grad-program#post-2401</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 13:44:59 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Amanda Visconti</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2401@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;(We tweeted a bit, but for anyone else happening on this question...)&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;DH dissertations in general&#60;br /&#62;
-----&#60;br /&#62;
1. The CUNY Graduate Center fellows and staff do amazing work making more kinds of dissertation possible, and in particular I'd suggest looking for blog posts and video from their #remixthediss event/project (e.g. &#60;a href=&#34;http://mediacommons.futureofthebook.org/alt-ac/pieces/what-dissertation-new-models-methods-media)&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://mediacommons.futureofthebook.org/alt-ac/pieces/what-dissertation-new-models-methods-media)&#60;/a&#62;. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;2. They maintain a collaborative GoogleDoc where people doing current or past non-monograph dissertations (humanities and not, digital and not) describe and link to their projects: &#60;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/remixthediss-models&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://bit.ly/remixthediss-models&#60;/a&#62;. I don't think these are included there, but two additional completed DH+textual literature dissertations to check out or use as examples are:&#60;br /&#62;
* Lisa Rhody's literature dissertation using topic modeling and visualization to explore ekphrastic poetry: &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.lisarhody.com/project/revising-ekphrasis/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://www.lisarhody.com/project/revising-ekphrasis/&#60;/a&#62;&#60;br /&#62;
* Tanya Clement's literature dissertation included the creation of an experimental scholarly digital edition: &#60;a href=&#34;http://digital.lib.umd.edu/transition/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://digital.lib.umd.edu/transition/&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;3. Here's a Zotero library of articles and guidelines for doing DH dissertations and applying for DH promotion/tenure (the latter often being applicable to arguing for the former): &#60;a href=&#34;https://www.zotero.org/amandavisconti/items/collectionKey/V9DA47T7&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;https://www.zotero.org/amandavisconti/items/collectionKey/V9DA47T7&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;My DH+textual studies dissertation&#60;br /&#62;
-----&#60;br /&#62;
I defended a DH dissertation about public digital humanities and digital textual scholarship for the University of Maryland's literature Ph.D. To show the department chair what a completed DH+textual studies dissertation can look like, or reuse some of the DH and literature precedents I used in my arguments:&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;The dissertation did not include any chapters; I used design, code, usertesting, blogging, and an analytical report written during last month before defense.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;The completed dissertation is this website: &#60;a href=&#34;http://dr.amandavisconti.com&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://dr.amandavisconti.com&#60;/a&#62;. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;The dissertation produced a participatory digital edition of Ulysses (&#60;a href=&#34;http://www.infiniteulysses.com)&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://www.infiniteulysses.com)&#60;/a&#62;.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;My doctoral exams areas were DH and textual scholarship (list and introductory essay explaining choices here: &#60;a href=&#34;http://literaturegeek.com/assets/ExamsSharingCopy.pdf)&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://literaturegeek.com/assets/ExamsSharingCopy.pdf)&#60;/a&#62;.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I blogged about twice a month through exams and the dissertation, both about my research and the larger meta aspects of doing a digital/DH dissertation: &#60;a href=&#34;http://literaturegeek.com/tag/dissertation/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://literaturegeek.com/tag/dissertation/&#60;/a&#62;. In particular, this post has some practical advice on getting started (&#60;a href=&#34;http://literaturegeek.com/2012/10/21/startingadhdissertation&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://literaturegeek.com/2012/10/21/startingadhdissertation&#60;/a&#62;) and this post has info on choosing your dissertation's format (&#60;a href=&#34;http://literaturegeek.com/2014/04/02/digitaldissformat)&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://literaturegeek.com/2014/04/02/digitaldissformat)&#60;/a&#62;.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;The slides and text of my successful dissertation defense talk are here: &#60;a href=&#34;http://literaturegeek.com/2016/06/20/digital-humanities-dissertation-defense-talk&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://literaturegeek.com/2016/06/20/digital-humanities-dissertation-defense-talk&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I am happy to email with this student (or anyone curious about DH/digital dissertations!) via &#60;a href=&#34;mailto:amandavisconti@gmail.com&#34;&#62;amandavisconti@gmail.com&#60;/a&#62;.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>pfyfe on "Why should DH coursework count towards a literature grad program?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/why-should-dh-coursework-count-towards-a-literature-grad-program#post-2400</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 15:51:42 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>pfyfe</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2400@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Hi everyone: I have a former grad student who wrote to me in a panic. Apparently, her current department chair has decided that her previous coursework in DH, book history will not count towards her current graduate program, because it does not &#34;correlate&#34; to literature, composition, or teaching. (Wow. I can barely even.) The chair is apparently reacting to an accreditation review and has asked for justification in language accessible to non-specialist peers. Does anyone have go-to resources for helping us make this case? Thank you --
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Amanda Visconti on "Reviving stalled or neglected DH projects"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/reviving-stalled-or-neglected-dh-projects#post-2399</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 13:48:01 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Amanda Visconti</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2399@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;&#60;em&#62;Replying to @&#60;a href='/profile/althealogan'&#62;althealogan&#60;/a&#62;'s &#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/reviving-stalled-or-neglected-dh-projects#post-2398&#34;&#62;post&#60;/a&#62;:&#60;/em&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Hi, Althea! This brings to mind a 2009 Digital Humanities Quarterly cluster of articles, &#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalhumanities.org/dhq/vol/3/2/index.html&#34;&#62;&#34;Done: Finishing Projects in the Digital Humanities&#34;&#60;/a&#62;. Looking forward to hearing more about your project and survey results!
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>althealogan on "Reviving stalled or neglected DH projects"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/reviving-stalled-or-neglected-dh-projects#post-2398</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 14:52:47 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>althealogan</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2398@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Hello!&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I am a student at the School of Information at the University of Texas at Austin.  I’m working with Jennifer Hecker (&#60;a href=&#34;http://jenniferlasupremahecker.info)&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://jenniferlasupremahecker.info)&#60;/a&#62;, who works with Technology Innovation &#38;amp; Strategy here at UT, on a project exploring how best to breathe new life into stalled or neglected DH projects.  &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;If you have experience working on a DH project, and a few minutes to spare, I’d be grateful if you would complete my survey on this topic.  You can find the survey here: &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62; &#60;a href=&#34;http://tinyurl.com/revivingdh&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://tinyurl.com/revivingdh&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I also welcome any resource recommendations, feedback or questions you may have. Also, please feel free to forward this survey to other interested parties. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Thanks for your time!&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Althea N. Logan&#60;br /&#62;
MSIS Candidate - School of Information, The University of Texas at Austin&#60;br /&#62;
&#60;a href=&#34;https://loganmsis.wordpress.com&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;https://loganmsis.wordpress.com&#60;/a&#62;&#60;br /&#62;
&#60;a href=&#34;mailto:thealogan@utexas.edu&#34;&#62;thealogan@utexas.edu&#60;/a&#62;
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>katherineharris on "Map or Directory of Digital Humanists?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/map-or-directory-of-digital-humanists#post-2383</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 17:25:41 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>katherineharris</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2383@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;&#60;em&#62;Replying to @Patrick Murray-John's &#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/map-or-directory-of-digital-humanists#post-2382&#34;&#62;post&#60;/a&#62;:&#60;/em&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;All of this began because I heard through live tweeting about an NEH-funded effort in San Diego to create a local consortium regarding digital pedagogy and DH. It's been in play for almost a year at a CSU (my university's system). I was incredibly overjoyed to see this happened at a CSU where DH Centers are rare due to funding and space limitations. Even in the CSUs there's no way to contact faculty at the other 22 campuses to see who's playing with DH. And, admittedly, I've expended lots and lots and lots of time trying to organize locally over the years. But, it's a time suck and my department doesn't give me professional credit for doing this kind of work. Glenn Worthey created a meet-up group for DH in the Bay Area, but it's fragmented (and again takes lots of time). Stanford has its LitLab and CESTA. There's a few faculty at other local institutions (and there are many in the Bay Area!) but I have no idea who unless I cold call departments. And then that doesn't necessarily inspire anything other than a &#34;hey, how's it going?&#34; We need a better way to make contact. If for anything, so we can collaborate locally and host events and avoid reinventing the wheel on projects. (I was just part of a California gathering of DHers; if I'd known about the San Diego lot, I would have strongly recommended them to be invited to the gathering as well!) &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;So, if there's data already out there from Day of DH, can we go through it to create even an ugly listing of DHer locales?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Patrick Murray-John on "Map or Directory of Digital Humanists?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/map-or-directory-of-digital-humanists#post-2382</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 17:13:20 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Patrick Murray-John</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2382@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Yeah, that is a challenge that lots of different places have been trying to tackle in different ways, especially at a more local level. Examples of that are the &#60;a href='http://nycdh.org/'&#62;NYCDH site&#60;/a&#62;, &#60;a href='https://phillydh.org/'&#62;DH Philly&#60;/a&#62;, and &#60;a href='http://vadhconsortium.org/'&#62;Virgina DH Consortium&#60;/a&#62;. Those are basically attempts in other places to tackle the same problem, with varying degrees of success. Difficulty for all is finding the people who should join up in the first place, which is more at the heart of your question.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;That said, I'm more confident about the regional efforts to build a DH community than I am with an effort at a national or international listing by location. I suspect that there will be more word-of-mouth growth at that local scale to build up membership in such sites (both NYCDH and VA are using Commons In A Box, I think, so setup is pretty easy).&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;If you're in the Santa Cruz neighborhood, I think some folks at UCSC have at least started talking about how to build up a group for that area.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I haven't been especially active on it, so I don't know how helpful it might be, but there's also the &#60;a href='https://digitalhumanities.slack.com'&#62;DH Slack&#60;/a&#62;, where you might be able to ask and spot people in your neighborhood.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>katherineharris on "Map or Directory of Digital Humanists?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/map-or-directory-of-digital-humanists#post-2381</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 15:19:45 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>katherineharris</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2381@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;&#60;em&#62;Replying to @Patrick Murray-John's &#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/map-or-directory-of-digital-humanists#post-2380&#34;&#62;post&#60;/a&#62;:&#60;/em&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Good solutions and ones that I've used over the last decade, but California is a very, very big state. And waiting for planned events or infrastructure to be instituted isn't quite what I'm looking for. I've been at this DH thing for a few years, and I'm  interested in expanding my network of DHers beyond the seredipity meet n'greet or the pub phenomenon (discovering each other by accident). &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;It would be terrific if we had a directory of some sort so we don't miss each other (and don't have to wait for yearly events such as Day of DH). Even DHCommons doesn't have a geographical sort to its list of collaborators. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Anyone want to take this up or propose it to Day of DH organizers?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Patrick Murray-John on "Map or Directory of Digital Humanists?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/map-or-directory-of-digital-humanists#post-2380</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 13:12:36 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Patrick Murray-John</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2380@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Day of DH is a good bet for finding others. Also, keep an eye out for local THATCamps. They are a great way to make those face-to-face meetings.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>katherineharris on "Map or Directory of Digital Humanists?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/map-or-directory-of-digital-humanists#post-2379</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2016 01:15:57 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>katherineharris</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2379@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Has anyone ever created a directory or map of Digital Humanists? I ask because there are so many doing DH in California but I don't know where or how to find them. I follow lists on Twitter, keep updated on recent scholarship and writings, talk to many people, but still I hear about California DH events after the fact. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Would really like to know if someone has taken this up based on the directory from DHNow or DHCommons or Day of DH. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I bet if we knew there was someone down the street that we could get up to some interesting shenanigans in DH
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Bethany Nowviskie on "DH Grad Fellowships?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/dh-grad-fellowships#post-2375</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 18:39:36 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Bethany Nowviskie</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2375@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Just a couple of newer ones to add to your list: alongside the &#34;Original Sources&#34; Mellon program you mention above, CLIR and the Library of Congress are offering a &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.clir.org/fellowships/mellon/preservation.html&#34;&#62;fellowship placement&#60;/a&#62; in the Library's Preservation Research &#38;amp; Testing Division, for PhD students whose work would benefit from techniques like hyperspectral imaging, x-ray fluorescence, spectroscopy, high-resolution microscopy, etc. -- and METRO has announced a &#60;a href=&#34;http://fellowship.metro.org/?q=node/4&#34;&#62;new program&#60;/a&#62; that will match fellows with projects in its network of New York-based libraries. This program isn't specifically designed for PhD students, as I understand it, but open to them.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Miriam Posner on "DH Grad Fellowships?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/dh-grad-fellowships#post-2349</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2015 03:53:12 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Miriam Posner</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2349@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Update: People on Twitter suggested a lot of university-specific grad fellowships (at &#60;a href=&#34;http://humanities.lib.rochester.edu/mellondh/&#34;&#62;the University of Rochester&#60;/a&#62;, &#60;a href=&#34;http://mith.umd.edu/community/fellowships/winnemore-fellows/&#34;&#62;the University of Maryland&#60;/a&#62;, &#60;a href=&#34;https://simpsoncenter.org/programs/initiatives/digital-humanities/digital-humanities-commons&#34;&#62;the University of Washington&#60;/a&#62;, &#60;a href=&#34;http://scholarslab.org/uncategorized/call-for-applications-graduate-fellowship-in-the-digital-humanities/&#34;&#62;the University of Virginia&#60;/a&#62;,and Carnegie Mellon).&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;The &#60;a href=&#34;http://editingmodernism.ca/funding/phd-stipends/&#34;&#62;Editing Modernism in Canada fellowship&#60;/a&#62; is open to grad students at &#60;a href=&#34;http://editingmodernism.ca/about-us/partners/&#34;&#62;EMIC partner universities&#60;/a&#62;. The University of Pennsylvania's Schoenberg Research Center's &#60;a href=&#34;http://schoenberginstitute.org/graduate-student-research-fellowship/&#34;&#62;Graduate Student Fellowship&#60;/a&#62; encourages digital projects.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Alex Gil et al.'s &#60;a href=&#34;https://github.com/achorg/dhfunding/blob/gh-pages/index.md&#34;&#62;list of DH funding opportunities&#60;/a&#62; might be useful.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Miriam Posner on "DH Grad Fellowships?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/dh-grad-fellowships#post-2348</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 21:56:02 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Miriam Posner</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2348@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I feel like this question gets asked periodically in various fora, but perhaps there are new developments I'm not aware of:&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Are there any options out there for graduate students looking for fellowships to do specifically DH work? ACH micro-grants and the like are helpful, of course, but I'm thinking of fellowships along the lines of the &#60;a href=&#34;https://www.acls.org/programs/dcf/&#34;&#62;Mellon dissertation completion fellowship&#60;/a&#62; or the &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.clir.org/fellowships/mellon&#34;&#62;CLIR Original Sources&#60;/a&#62; fellowships. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I'm asking specifically for American grad students, but I'm sure future readers will appreciate links to other fellowships as well.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Thanks!
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Arno Bosse on "Best DH project-management system?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/best-dh-project-management-system#post-2336</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 09:04:20 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Arno Bosse</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2336@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Returning to this since there are now a lot (and when I say &#34;a lot&#34;... &#60;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Comparison_of_project_management_software)&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Comparison_of_project_management_software)&#60;/a&#62; of web-based options for project management out there.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I've started testing Active Collab (&#60;a href=&#34;https://www.activecollab.com/features.html&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;https://www.activecollab.com/features.html&#60;/a&#62;) and would be grateful for feedback from anyone else who has used this. I'd also love to hear about first hand experience with other alternatives now that 4 years have passed since the question was first posted.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>ebuhe on "Feedback on Digital Humanities Best Practices document"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/feedback-on-digital-humanities-best-practices-document#post-2306</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2015 00:51:16 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>ebuhe</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2306@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I'm working on a Digital Humanities Best Practices document that would serve as a list of questions humanities scholars could ask themselves as they get started on a collaborative project--something that is widely applicable, accessible, and quick and easy to read (meaning: not written in prose, not one person's reflections about their DH experience, not behind a paywall). The scope is specifically geared toward setting expectations and the issues to consider including in a charter / contract.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;It currently exists as an editable document on Google Drive -- and I'd love feedback!! What's missing, what's too broad/specific? Other great links to share? I'd especially like thoughts on integrating language re: open source, creative commons, code.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Here's the link:&#60;br /&#62;
&#60;a href=&#34;http://www.nyu.edu/gsas/dept/fineart/research/digital-humanities-best-practices.htm&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://www.nyu.edu/gsas/dept/fineart/research/digital-humanities-best-practices.htm&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Thanks!
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
