<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- generator="bbPress/1.0.2" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Humanities Questions &#38; Answers &#187; Topic: Design a digital history curriculum: what would you include?</title>
		<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/design-a-digital-history-curriculum-what-would-you-include</link>
		<description>Digital Humanities Questions &amp; Answers &#187; Topic: Design a digital history curriculum: what would you include?</description>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 10:21:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<generator>http://bbpress.org/?v=1.0.2</generator>
		<textInput>
			<title><![CDATA[Search]]></title>
			<description><![CDATA[Search all topics from these forums.]]></description>
			<name>q</name>
			<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/search.php</link>
		</textInput>
		<atom:link href="/rss/topic/design-a-digital-history-curriculum-what-would-you-include/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
			 
				<title>jean_bauer on "Design a digital history curriculum: what would you include?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/design-a-digital-history-curriculum-what-would-you-include#post-1008</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 16:11:57 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>jean_bauer</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1008@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I also concur with everything said by William Turkel.  You'll find almost all of that in my syllabus, although since we only had 1 semester and a research paper requirement I didn't have time to teach my students to program, just recognize what XML --&#38;gt; XSLT --&#38;gt; HTML looks like.  It kind of blew their minds.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>jean_bauer on "Design a digital history curriculum: what would you include?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/design-a-digital-history-curriculum-what-would-you-include#post-1007</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 16:08:13 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>jean_bauer</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1007@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I don't know if this will help (or just be yet another conflicting syllabus) but I taught a course at the University of Virginia for Spring 2010 which might give you some new ideas.  It was a senior seminar and more of a &#34;philosophy of digital history&#34; class.  Basically, I wanted my students to think hard about the sources they encountered whether digital or analog and recognize how the ways in which information is recorded effects the kind of analysis historians can perform later.  The course was called &#34;From Vellum to Very Large Databases: Historical Sources Past, Present, and Future&#34; and we had hands-on experience with all the sources (holding medieval manuscripts, setting type by hand, georeferencing a historical map, etc).  The course website is &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.jeanbauer.com/vellum_to_vldb.html&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://www.jeanbauer.com/vellum_to_vldb.html&#60;/a&#62; and includes a detailed syllabus with possible research paper topics.  Hope that helps.  If you have any questions, feel free to contact me.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>william.j.turkel@gmail.com on "Design a digital history curriculum: what would you include?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/design-a-digital-history-curriculum-what-would-you-include#post-1006</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 16:06:02 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>william.j.turkel@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1006@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;In the introductory course, I think it is important to find a balance between presenting history on the web and using digital sources to do research.  At the least, such a course should also cover&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;ul&#62;
&#60;li&#62;How search engines work and how to get the most out of them&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;Where digital sources come from&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;How digital information differs from more familiar analog media&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;How information can be measured and manipulated with computational tools&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;Reading and writing markup like HTML and XML&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;The separation of form from content&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;Open content, open access and open source; Creative Commons&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;/ul&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I like to mix seminar discussion with active learning.  I've found that students work harder and learn more on individual or small group projects than large-group ones.  Programming is best taught and learned by working closely with someone who already knows how to program.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>hopegreenberg on "Design a digital history curriculum: what would you include?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/design-a-digital-history-curriculum-what-would-you-include#post-814</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2010 15:04:59 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>hopegreenberg</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">814@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;There are now a number of universities offering courses in digital history. When you look at individual syllabi, however, there is quite a variety in approaches or topics covered. If you were given the task of designing a curriculum or a series of courses to be taught alongside more traditional history courses, what would you include? &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Let's say it's a series of 4 courses, one per semester over 2 years, that begins with first year students (undergraduate freshmen) with a goal of producing digitally &#34;nimble&#34; history students or even digital historians (feel free to define both of those!). How would you balance theory, general information literacy skills, projects, programming, etc? What would be the &#34;must include&#34; pieces and which would be the ideal? What mix of lecture-based, active learning/project based, discussion/seminar, online/face-to-face/hybrid or other configuration would you build?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
