<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- generator="bbPress/1.0.2" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Humanities Questions &#38; Answers &#187; Topic: Faircite: Who should we cite in collaborative DH Projects?</title>
		<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/faircite-who-should-we-cite-in-collaborative-dh-projects</link>
		<description>Digital Humanities Questions &amp; Answers &#187; Topic: Faircite: Who should we cite in collaborative DH Projects?</description>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2016 23:12:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<generator>http://bbpress.org/?v=1.0.2</generator>
		<textInput>
			<title><![CDATA[Search]]></title>
			<description><![CDATA[Search all topics from these forums.]]></description>
			<name>q</name>
			<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/search.php</link>
		</textInput>
		<atom:link href="/rss/topic/faircite-who-should-we-cite-in-collaborative-dh-projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
			 
				<title>Trevor Owens on "Faircite: Who should we cite in collaborative DH Projects?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/faircite-who-should-we-cite-in-collaborative-dh-projects#post-1654</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2012 19:59:56 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Trevor Owens</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1654@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Neat project Adam. I tend to have mixed feelings about metrics writ large. Personally, I think there are two different questions here. One is about how to cite something and one is about how people get credit for their work. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I don't really care that much about the citation question. I think it falls into the CMS response to &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.chicagomanualofstyle.org/CMS_FAQ/Documentation/Documentation12.html&#34;&#62;this question&#60;/a&#62;. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;blockquote&#62;&#60;p&#62;Cite it the same way you would “cite” your sandwich or your miniblinds or the fluff under your bathroom rug—not by trying to pretend it is a bibliographic source, but simply by telling what it is.”&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;/blockquote&#62;
&#60;p&#62;If someone wants to cite Zotero it doesn't matter to me if I am in any way mentioned in that citation. I'm fine with not being listed in any way on the project. I didn't design it, I didn't build it, I didn't conceive of it. I did do a lot of work as part of it, but I wouldn't think of myself as an author. With that said, if someone want's to talk about some of the things I designed and developed for outreach on the project, or about it's documentation, I likely warrant some kind of mention.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;In terms of the question of credit, I think our best bet is to treat our work more as a artists portfolio than as a stack of things that someone counts. In general, I think the whole idea of citation metrics do more harm than good. In my experience, the moment when credit matters is when you are applying for a job, or being considered for some kind of work. It is essential that anyone is able to offer up a portfolio with a list of projects and a description of what you did on those projects and what you can offer up as the indicators of your success in that project. Being mentioned on about pages for projects I've been in is nice, but in practice largely irrelevant to me. With that said, those experiences gave me everything I need to describe demonstrable skills, knowledge and abilities when I applied for a federal job.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>DavidBeavan on "Faircite: Who should we cite in collaborative DH Projects?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/faircite-who-should-we-cite-in-collaborative-dh-projects#post-1651</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2012 11:21:47 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>DavidBeavan</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1651@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Adam, In my experience it varies from institution to institution. I don't think it's ever a direct policy to preclude individuals from credit, rather it's indirect and is due to naivety. If those responsible for maintaining the repository only allow certain classes of staff (e.g. academic/research) to be featured, then this cuts out those on other contracts. So, if somebody is employed as a database/web designer; then as they don't exist in the repository brain, they don't get credited there.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Of course, some repositories only list publications, and fall short of capturing resources too, which is even worse. The traditional model of who is credited for contributions to research outputs needs to be more flexible, certainly when it comes to DH.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>acrymble on "Faircite: Who should we cite in collaborative DH Projects?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/faircite-who-should-we-cite-in-collaborative-dh-projects#post-1643</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2012 02:49:59 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>acrymble</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1643@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Jason, thanks for your thoughts. I like your practical approach to extending the guidelines of the Medical Journal Editors. And thanks also for that twitter exchange; I had missed that.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;David, thanks for the correction on the REF. I'm curious about your comment that non-academic staff cannot be named alongside their work in institutional repositories. Is this a policy in UK universities? This obviously isn't an issue in the wider world. Illustrators on children's books for example are often listed in libraries despite their &#34;alternative&#34; role in the creative process.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>DavidBeavan on "Faircite: Who should we cite in collaborative DH Projects?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/faircite-who-should-we-cite-in-collaborative-dh-projects#post-1642</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2012 09:31:51 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>DavidBeavan</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1642@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I can only speak from my experience in the UK (BTW the REF is UK wide, not just England). DH projects have included an About page, which lists those involved and their responsibilities. While that is a help, it does not necessarily constitute a citation.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;This is where we bump into cultural role traditions: academics do research, non academics (alt-ac) do not. This model may hold true in traditional humanities scholarship (if there is such a thing), where the research and the writing of an article is performed solely by academics. With DH project work, a diverse team is assembled, often including those who are not academics. This sadly leads to situations where non-academic staff cannot be named alongside their work in institutional repositories etc, simply because their job title or job family excludes them from that possibility. This completely ignores the collaborative processes involved in the creation of DH resources and projects.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Personally, I would welcome a citation system that includes all those who have made a major contribution to the project, listing their roles or responsibilities. That seems a fair approach to me.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Jason Heppler on "Faircite: Who should we cite in collaborative DH Projects?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/faircite-who-should-we-cite-in-collaborative-dh-projects#post-1638</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2012 12:33:45 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Jason Heppler</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1638@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;&#60;em&#62;Replying to @&#60;a href='/profile/acrymble'&#62;acrymble&#60;/a&#62;'s &#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/faircite-who-should-we-cite-in-collaborative-dh-projects#post-1536&#34;&#62;post&#60;/a&#62;:&#60;/em&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Hi Adam,&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Here's a discussion that occurred on Twitter this morning that might have some relevance. I'm placing it here for reference:&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;blockquote&#62;&#60;p&#62;
@karikraus Curious if DH tweeps are starting to adopt &#34;order of authorship&#34; conventions from the sciences or listing collaborators alphabetically. [+] &#60;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/karikraus/status/198049750166142976&#34;&#62;[link]&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;@karikraus With a joint appt. that crosses the sciences &#38;amp; humanities, I have a mix of both on my CV. [-] &#60;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/karikraus/status/198049823902007297&#34;&#62;[link]&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;@&#60;a href='/profile/melissaterras'&#62;melissaterras&#60;/a&#62; @karikraus good question. I have known wars to erupt over it. &#60;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/melissaterras/status/198051517566169089&#34;&#62;[link]&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;@karikraus @&#60;a href='/profile/melissaterras'&#62;melissaterras&#60;/a&#62; What's your practice, Melissa? Also a mix, depending on venue and collaborators? &#60;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/karikraus/status/198051655311302656&#34;&#62;[link]&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;@geoffrockwell @karikraus We tend to use a hybrid - first couple of authors are those that led and the rest in alpha order &#60;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/geoffrockwell/status/198051678979756033&#34;&#62;[link]&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;@&#60;a href='/profile/melissaterras'&#62;melissaterras&#60;/a&#62; @karikraus in general, person who does most writing is first author. Then list everyone  (alphabetically?) &#38;amp; see if anyone starts shouting. &#60;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/melissaterras/status/198052407626829826&#34;&#62;[link]&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;@karikraus @&#60;a href='/profile/melissaterras'&#62;melissaterras&#60;/a&#62; Otherwise, rinse &#38;amp; repeat? ;-) &#60;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/karikraus/status/198052764893450240&#34;&#62;[link]&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;@&#60;a href='/profile/melissaterras'&#62;melissaterras&#60;/a&#62; @karikraus yeah. We've found @sruecker's project charter really helpful; get people to agree in advance. &#60;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/melissaterras/status/198053340037394433&#34;&#62;[link]&#60;/a&#62;
&#60;/p&#62;&#60;/blockquote&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Jason Heppler on "Faircite: Who should we cite in collaborative DH Projects?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/faircite-who-should-we-cite-in-collaborative-dh-projects#post-1637</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2012 12:23:09 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Jason Heppler</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1637@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;&#60;em&#62;Replying to @&#60;a href='/profile/acrymble'&#62;acrymble&#60;/a&#62;'s &#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/faircite-who-should-we-cite-in-collaborative-dh-projects#post-1536&#34;&#62;post&#60;/a&#62;:&#60;/em&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Adam,&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I think this is a really great topic for us to be considering. I'm involved in two different ways of citing contributors to a project, so I'll add this as fuel for thought--&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;At projects at the Center for Digital Research in the Humanities, we use our project About pages to list the roles that everyone in a project contributes to. This includes roles that change over time (for example, I'm listed twice on the &#60;a href=&#34;http://codyarchive.org/staff/&#34;&#62;Cody Archive staff page&#60;/a&#62;, first as a research editor and then as project manager). This sort of credit page, I believe, is similar across various CDRH projects.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;The second area where I'm having to think through these issues is with an article I'm co-authoring with some collaborators. During the fall 2011 semester, I was enrolled in the digital humanities seminar with Prof. William G. Thomas, and one of the projects we had in the class was to build an iOS application. Towards the end of the course we decided as a group that we wanted to author an article about our experience (which is currently in progress). However, not everyone in the seminar had an interest or the time to contribute to a written piece -- so, I'm working with three others to draft the essay. However, we also did not want to leave out our fellow seminar colleagues -- they obviously contributed to the iOS app and, thus, deserve credit for their contributions (even if they are not part of the essay side). So, what we have done is to list the four of us as authors alphabetically, and we cite our colleagues (alphabetically) in the footnotes as contributors to the project. We have made it clear to them that they can cite this on their C.V.'s even though their names may not appear on the byline. In this case, it's more about acknowledgements rather than authorship.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;My other thought on this (which I think follows other conventions) is to take a &#34;science-y&#34; approach and list everybody. What I would envision here is listing the author(s) that do the most writing first then follow with the rest of the contributors alphabetically. But that's for published projects. I think it's slightly more complicated with digital projects that have continual evolution and, by extension, revolving collaborators (people come and go, collaborators take on new roles, etc). Listing everyone on the Cody About page, for example, would become unwieldy to place on a C.V.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I do like the general themes of the International Committee of Medical Journal Editors you cite above. So, authorship for digital projects could follow similar themes and lay these out clearly in a project narrative (as Bethany notes above). Using their model, we might think about:&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;ul&#62;
&#60;li&#62;Defining authorship around 1) substantial quality intellectual content; 2) the contribution of data, analysis, or interpretation; 3) public responsibility for the quality of the project. The acquisition of funding is a contribution, but perhaps not authorship credit.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;Authorship and credit should be clearly established at the beginning of a project. The principals of a project should be generous in their shared credit and inclusion.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;Contributors not listed as authors have to claim their own stake and responsibility in a project. They perhaps cannot speak about the project as a whole (say, to the public or to a hiring committee) but can discuss their role(s) within the project.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;There should be a sense of shared knowledge production that should be conveyed in credit, no matter the rank, status, or contribution of an individual.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;/ul&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Anyways, these are some quick and dirty thoughts. There are a lot of other issues to think about (should digital centers represent large, multi-group projects?) but hopefully I've added a little food for thought. This is a topic I think about often, so I'll be closely watching FairCite and the discussions that continue around it.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>acrymble on "Faircite: Who should we cite in collaborative DH Projects?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/faircite-who-should-we-cite-in-collaborative-dh-projects#post-1617</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2012 02:55:51 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>acrymble</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1617@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;&#60;em&#62;Replying to @Bethany Nowviskie's &#60;a href=&#34;http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/faircite-who-should-we-cite-in-collaborative-dh-projects#post-1549&#34;&#62;post&#60;/a&#62;:&#60;/em&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Thanks Bethany,&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I have been keeping an eye on Twitter. I appreciate the discussion you've been having at the Scholar's Lab and I look forward to hearing more about what you'll come up with. I think leading by example is a great way to test what works and what doesn't.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Bethany Nowviskie on "Faircite: Who should we cite in collaborative DH Projects?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/faircite-who-should-we-cite-in-collaborative-dh-projects#post-1549</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2012 11:34:50 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Bethany Nowviskie</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1549@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Adam, I've seen so much good stuff in response to this query on Twitter. Are you trying to collect it all, or would it be helpful for us to try to encourage folks to post here as well?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;For example, this morning's excellent contribution from Sheila Brennan and Sharon Leon at CHNM -- where great thinking and fair dealing has clearly been happening for a long time:&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;blockquote&#62;&#60;p&#62;@&#60;a href='/profile/sharonmleon'&#62;sharonmleon&#60;/a&#62;: Faircite material. MT @&#60;a href='/profile/sherah1918'&#62;sherah1918&#60;/a&#62;: Do you look at a DH project About pages?&#60;br /&#62;
Here is a @chnm NEH proj ('03-'05). &#60;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/yUp5Nu&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://bit.ly/yUp5Nu&#60;/a&#62;&#60;br /&#62;
&#60;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/Aqq8c2&#34;&#62;tweet link&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;/blockquote&#62;
&#60;p&#62;At the Scholars' Lab, we're taking the FairCite initiative and the great work you've done on this so far as inspiration for the credits page of our Neatline project, which will have its official launch this spring.  The plan is to include a project narrative alongside a full listing of roles and their evolution -- to get not only at the diversity of perspectives and skillsets work like this takes, but also at how a project evolves collaboratively over time.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Anyway, thanks for your leadership!
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>acrymble on "Faircite: Who should we cite in collaborative DH Projects?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/faircite-who-should-we-cite-in-collaborative-dh-projects#post-1548</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2012 11:20:53 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>acrymble</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1548@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;If you'd like to submit ideas in a less public forum, please feel free to email me directly at &#60;a href=&#34;mailto:adam.crymble@gmail.com&#34;&#62;adam.crymble@gmail.com&#60;/a&#62;.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>acrymble on "Faircite: Who should we cite in collaborative DH Projects?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/faircite-who-should-we-cite-in-collaborative-dh-projects#post-1536</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2012 11:38:29 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>acrymble</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1536@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;How does one cite a digital humanities project? The &#60;a href=&#34;http://faircite.wordpress.com&#34;&#62;Fair Cite&#60;/a&#62; initiative is looking for your feedback on citation in collaborative projects. How should we incorporate the efforts of people such as project managers, students, community participants, programmers, designers, etc? What type of contribution is &#34;enough&#34; for someone to appear in the project citation? And why?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;For more background information on the issue please see &#60;a href=&#34;http://faircite.wordpress.com/2012/02/15/citation-practices-in-academia/&#34;&#62;Current Citation Practices&#60;/a&#62;. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;We invite members of the community to contribute your opinions on what those guidelines should look like. Who should be cited? What criteria should someone meet before being included as an &#34;author&#34; or &#34;editor&#34;? How do we best emphasize the different types of contributions people make? Your help will be instrumental in fostering a fairer model of citation for those whose contributions are all too often invisible.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;The guidelines of the International Committee of Medical Journal Editors is perhaps a good place to start the discussion:&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;ol&#62;
&#60;li&#62;the conception and design of the study, or acquisition of data, or analysis and interpretation of data&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;drafting the article or revising it critically for important intellectual content&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;final approval of the version to be submitted&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;/ol&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Can these be adapted to meet the needs of the DH community? Is there a better starting point elsewhere?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Please distribute this to anyone you think may be interested including those outside of the digital humanities and Alt-ac communities.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
