<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- generator="bbPress/1.0.2" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Humanities Questions &#38; Answers &#187; Tag: translation - Recent Topics</title>
		<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/tags/translation</link>
		<description>Digital Humanities Questions &amp; Answers &#187; Tag: translation - Recent Topics</description>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 01:48:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<generator>http://bbpress.org/?v=1.0.2</generator>
		<textInput>
			<title><![CDATA[Search]]></title>
			<description><![CDATA[Search all topics from these forums.]]></description>
			<name>q</name>
			<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/search.php</link>
		</textInput>
		<atom:link href="/rss/tags/translation/topics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
			 
				<title>snehaadesai@gmail.com on "Support for a multi-media poetry translation website?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/support-for-a-multi-media-poetry-translation-website#post-1559</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2012 04:36:31 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>snehaadesai@gmail.com</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1559@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Hi, I am a Fulbright Scholar working on translation practice and theory. I'd like to solicit ideas for organizations that would support a multi-media presentation of the translations I am writing. Ideally, I would work with an organization that it invested in innovation in digital publishing, and the humanities.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Just throwing this out there for ideas--thanks!
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Karin Dalziel on "Questions about providing translations/foreign language editions of DH projects."</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/questions-about-providing-translationsforeign-language-editions-of-dh-projects#post-1235</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2011 14:21:22 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Karin Dalziel</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1235@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;This is mostly just a request for anyone with experience providing translations of DH projects to share what they learned. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Some general questions: &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;-How do the translations affect the workflow? i.e. if a change comes in for page (usually in English, in our case), what's the process to roll those changes out to the translated pages, especially if the original translator is no longer available?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;-How do you choose the languages to translate into?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;-What content do you translate? For instance, it is pretty easy to provide translations for the introductory pages, but if there is a lot of content it may be harder to provide translations for all of the content immediately. Is it worth rolling out translations for introductory pages before the translations for the content are complete?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I'm just starting research on this topic (beginning with the W3C's &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.w3.org/TR/i18n-html-tech-lang/#ri20040808.100519373&#34;&#62;Internationalization Best Practices: Specifying Language in XHTML &#38;amp; HTML Content&#60;/a&#62;) but would love to hear other's experiences.  This isn't a question as much about the technical implementation, though I'd love to hear about that too if you want to share. :)
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Shane Landrum on "Best practices for historical-primary-source translations sites?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/best-practices-for-historical-primary-source-translations-sites#post-1073</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2011 15:56:53 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Shane Landrum</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1073@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;A colleague (currently in doctoral coursework in history) is working on translating historical primary sources about mid-20th-century North African anti-colonial revolutions. These are currently available only in French-language anthologies and are hard to get by interlibrary loan, but she's gotten copies and wants to translate them into English (and eventually into Arabic). I've suggested that she consider putting her translations online for pedagogical purposes.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Before I get myself in too deep on this, I'd love some guidance by people who know more about translations websites. (Once I've seen enough answers here, I'll probably just forward the URL of this discussion to her, and she can ask her own clarifying questions.)&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;ul&#62;
&#60;li&#62; I'm aware of at least one existing site, &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.einaudi.cornell.edu/europe/integrated_history/about.asp&#34;&#62;Integrated History&#60;/a&#62;, that does precisely this-- English translations of Eastern European history sources-- but I'd welcome examples of others that present scholarly translations well, particularly for historical texts. (For this purpose, it's a plus if they're small-scale/solo-scholar/DIY in nature.)&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;What are the intellectual-property/rights issues of translating portions of published texts from a published anthology, when the original sources being anthologized are &#34;historical&#34; in nature (i.e. not &#34;literary&#34; and thus subject to litigation from an author's estate)? The jurisdiction of first publication is France (or maybe Algeria, Tunisia, Morocco-- unsure on this), within the last 50 years. How copyright-risky would it be for her to put the French text online alongside her English and/or Arabic translations?&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;Is the &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.einaudi.cornell.edu/europe/integrated_history/copyright.asp&#34;&#62;Integrated History copyright statement&#60;/a&#62; a reasonable model for a copyright disclaimer? I like my sources website's &#60;a href=&#34;http://cliotropic.org/sources/copyright/&#34;&#62;copyright statement&#60;/a&#62;, but it wouldn't be a good model in this case, since all my online sources are copyright-expired and/or US government documents.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;I know that &#60;a href=&#34;http://www.tei-c.org/Guidelines/&#34;&#62;TEI&#60;/a&#62; is the Real Scholars' Tool for encoding translations, but it's got a high learning curve and (from what I can see) mostly makes sense for larger-scale projects with a literary flavor, not small, short-term proof-of-concept projects. (I'd be open to hearing good arguments to the contrary, though.) If one were encoding one's translations in a future-compatible way, what's the minimal set of formatting tags that overlap between HTML and TEI?&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;Since my colleague doesn't yet have a webserver setup of her own, I was going to suggest &#60;a href=&#34;http://omeka.net&#34;&#62;Omeka.Net&#60;/a&#62; as a way to get started quickly and without much technical overhead, with the thought that if she wants to expand or install custom plugins like &#60;a href=&#34;http://omeka.org/codex/Plugins/TeiDisplay&#34;&#62;TeiDisplay&#60;/a&#62; later, she can buy a webhosting plan then. Is there any reason I should be suggesting a tool other than Omeka for this project?&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;Scholars' Lab folks: How mature is the TeiDisplay plugin? Where can I see it running?&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;/ul&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Thanks in advance for your suggestions and comments.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Stéfan Sinclair on "Applications for aligning multiple translations?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/applications-for-aligning-multiple-translations#post-860</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2011 10:27:12 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Stéfan Sinclair</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">860@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;&#60;em&#62;A colleague has asked me&#60;/em&#62;™ for suggestions of applications that are designed to help with aligning multiple translations of a text (as I'm writing this, I'm wondering if aligning multiple editions of a text wouldn't be similar, at least in some ways). Some things can be done with spreadsheets or tables in editors, of course, but we're wondering if anyone can recommend some specialized software. I'd already suggested &#60;a href=&#34;http://translate.google.com/toolkit&#34;&#62;Google Translator Toolkit&#60;/a&#62;.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
