<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- generator="bbPress/1.0.2" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Humanities Questions &#38; Answers &#187; Topic: Writing Grants for DH Projects</title>
		<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/writing-grants-for-dh-projects</link>
		<description>Digital Humanities Questions &amp; Answers &#187; Topic: Writing Grants for DH Projects</description>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2013 22:17:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<generator>http://bbpress.org/?v=1.0.2</generator>
		<textInput>
			<title><![CDATA[Search]]></title>
			<description><![CDATA[Search all topics from these forums.]]></description>
			<name>q</name>
			<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/search.php</link>
		</textInput>
		<atom:link href="/rss/topic/writing-grants-for-dh-projects" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
			 
				<title>laurie taylor on "Writing Grants for DH Projects"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/writing-grants-for-dh-projects#post-1863</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 21:45:31 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>laurie taylor</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1863@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;The budget preparation requirements vary by funding agency and by institutional requirements. One of the big recommendations for all grants is to contact your institutional grant office (often called sponsored research or with those words in the title) because they can help a great deal in navigating the specifics and with the proposal preparation and submission and so on. The other big recommendation is to call the program officer for the grant. The program officers are there to help orient investigators to resources to help ensure that the projects are successful. They can often share older grant narratives and sometime example budgets. The UF Libraries share our grant proposals (most successful, and some not; not all proposals, but many and with budgets to IMLS, NEH, NHPRC, and other agencies) online for others to use in developing a culture of grantsmanship and for support in training in grantsmanship. The available proposals are available from here: &#60;a href=&#34;http://ufdc.ufl.edu/ufirgrants&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://ufdc.ufl.edu/ufirgrants&#60;/a&#62;&#60;br /&#62;
The grant information can be difficult to read even in finished proposals because the underlying calculations include %FTE (percentage of full time employment, so 10% is 4 hours a week), salary+benefit costs (often a standard institutional rate, and UF has different rates for hourly and salary folks with several types and rates, but 30% tends to be a good initial ballpark rate for benefits), and IDC (indirect costs, which are fascinating and tie back to Vannevar Bush's work, but also vary by funding agency and often by entity within an organization). Your local grant folks can explain all of this more helpfully in line with helping develop the budget.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Roger Whitson on "Writing Grants for DH Projects"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/writing-grants-for-dh-projects#post-1862</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 20:22:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Roger Whitson</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1862@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Are there any resources online that give insight about writing grants for DH projects? I'm preparing a grant for an augmented reality application, and would like some guidance - specifically - about preparing a budget. Any insight or suggestions would be appreciated. Thanks!
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
