<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- generator="bbPress/1.0.2" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Humanities Questions &#38; Answers &#187; Tag: study - Recent Topics</title>
		<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/tags/study</link>
		<description>Digital Humanities Questions &amp; Answers &#187; Tag: study - Recent Topics</description>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2013 19:29:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<generator>http://bbpress.org/?v=1.0.2</generator>
		<textInput>
			<title><![CDATA[Search]]></title>
			<description><![CDATA[Search all topics from these forums.]]></description>
			<name>q</name>
			<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/search.php</link>
		</textInput>
		<atom:link href="/rss/tags/study/topics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
			 
				<title>b4ssm4st3r on "Undergraduate wishing to know more about options for Digital Humanities"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/undergraduate-wishing-to-know-more-about-options-for-digital-humanities#post-809</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2010 22:03:43 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>b4ssm4st3r</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">809@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I am a Senior at the University of Mary Washington and have taken a couple of courses that look more into the field of Digital Humanities. Two of them being Digital History and Digital Storytelling. Unfortunately I am coming to that time where I have to start thinking about my future. I was wondering what kind of options are out there for those interested in the field of Digital Humanities. Would I need to go to graduate school to have a chance at finding a job within the field? Or do I have the basic skills I already need/ Are there internships or other programs that also support the field of Digital Humanities? I am actually more so interested in History because that is where I will get my bachelors. However I am open to any kind of advice. Thank you!
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Marius on "Is there a list anywhere of all the graduate programs that study DH?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/is-there-a-list-anywhere-of-all-the-graduate-programs-that-study-dh#post-506</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2010 23:45:45 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Marius</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">506@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Hello,&#60;br /&#62;
This is my first post, I will try to be concise. I was very glad to find this page.&#60;br /&#62;
I am looking for a good master's program to study digital humanities in the US. I am currently residing in Romania.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I have found it far more difficult than I had thought, to find these master's online. The only ones I've been able to locate are one at MIT and at the University of Maryland. I imagine there must be more...&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I would very much appreciate your help in finding some.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Thank you!&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Marius Lobontiu
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
