<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- generator="bbPress/1.0.2" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Humanities Questions &#38; Answers &#187; Forum: Applications, Tools, Formats - Recent Topics</title>
		<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/forum/applications-tools-formats</link>
		<description>Digital Humanities Questions &amp; Answers &#187; Forum: Applications, Tools, Formats - Recent Topics</description>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 01:42:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<generator>http://bbpress.org/?v=1.0.2</generator>
		<textInput>
			<title><![CDATA[Search]]></title>
			<description><![CDATA[Search all topics from these forums.]]></description>
			<name>q</name>
			<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/search.php</link>
		</textInput>
		<atom:link href="/rss/forum/applications-tools-formats/topics" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
			 
				<title>gscottrobinson on "Reasonable goals for a first DH project?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/reasonable-goals-for-a-first-dh-project#post-2387</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 13:56:35 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>gscottrobinson</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2387@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Hi!&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I'm interested in learning more about computer-based textual analysis, so I developed a project using the journal Literature/Film Quarterly (LFQ). I haven't done this sort of research before, so I'm trying to determine the best questions to ask and the tools that will help me answer them. I'm hoping someone might be able to tell me if these are reasonable questions to ask. I'd also appreciate any suggestions. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;LFQ began in 1973 and continues now. As the oldest journal in the field, looking at the text should be able to provide some insights about how adaptation studies developed.  At about 50 articles a year for 43 years, I'm looking at 2150 articles.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Questions: &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Can an examination of the entire text of LFQ reveal anything substantial about the way adaptation studies has changed from 1973-present?&#60;br /&#62;
What are the most frequently cited texts in each year? WebofScience doesn't support this journal.&#60;br /&#62;
What names (other scholars) appear most frequently each year?&#60;br /&#62;
What kinds of terms are used in earlier years (e.g. “fidelity,” &#34;intertextuality&#34;) and do they continue throughout the journal’s history?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;If there are other questions that I could explore, I'd appreciate any suggestions.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>LeahPowell on "How did you learn to code?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-did-you-learn-to-code#post-2368</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 10:52:28 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>LeahPowell</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2368@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I'm a PhD in English student, and I'm interested in (but very new to) DH. I will start working with TEI soon through a digital archive project I'm working on, so there's that. What other avenues should I explore in my quest to learn coding for the sake of DH research?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>oosa on "where do I change my password to one I easily remember?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/where-do-i-change-my-password-to-one-i-easily-remember#post-2367</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 02:40:33 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>oosa</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2367@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;the password sent to me is quite complex and I want to change it.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Welblaud on "TEI in Oxygen Author (problem with tables’ labels in XSL-FO)"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/tei-in-oxygen-author-problem-with-tables%e2%80%99-labels-in-xsl-fo-1#post-2359</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 04:30:49 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Welblaud</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2359@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Dear community,&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I am intensively testing exports to PDF from TEI documents and can’t figure where could be the problem. The document is always fully valid, CSS rendition (default) work properly. However, in the result there is always missing the label, which is always coded as table’s head.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;&#60;code&#62;&#60;br /&#62;
  &#38;lt;table rendition=&#34;simple:frame&#34;&#38;gt;&#60;br /&#62;
    &#38;lt;head&#38;gt;The head!&#38;lt;/head&#38;gt;&#60;br /&#62;
&#60;/code&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I have noticed it is really important to test several types of notation when testing outputs via XSLT (e.g. footnotes’ rendition is rather an adventure!) but here I tried almost everything and nothing helps. It seems the &#60;code&#62;tei:head&#60;/code&#62; part from XSL templates is not passed into the final output. In XeLaTeX it worked well.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Is there something I am omitting in the code and what Oxygen needs for proper rendition? (like rend=&#34;header&#34; or so?)&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Any help more than welcome!&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Honza Hejzl
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>inactinique on "Which Named Entity Recognition Tool?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/which-named-entity-recognition-tool#post-2346</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2015 11:43:13 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>inactinique</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2346@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Dear all,&#60;br /&#62;
I have a database with more than one million tweets (about WW1). What I'd like to do now is to recognize dates and traces of time.&#60;br /&#62;
Has anyone an idea of how to do this? (In French and English).&#60;br /&#62;
Best
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>hopegreenberg on "Advice on tools for side by side pages of Latin and English translations"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/advice-on-tools-for-side-by-side-pages-of-latin-and-english-translations#post-2353</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2015 15:31:19 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>hopegreenberg</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2353@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I'm working with a faculty member who has translated 2 16th century books from Latin to English and has extensively annotated them. Both are lightly TEI encoded and could be more heavily encoded as needed. He would like to display the original and the translation side by side. A page-by-page display, as opposed to a line-by-line display, would be sufficient. When he originally asked for advice a couple years ago I looked at Juxta and the Versioning Machine. Anything new since then that I should look at? He is not looking for witness comparisons, heat maps, or anything too sophisticated. A flip-book view (one page of Latin next to one page of English) would be ideal in terms of what he is visualizing.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;- Hope
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>robbin_g on "How do I write a good research question for a Digital Humanities PhD proposal?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-do-i-write-a-good-research-question-for-a-digital-humanities-phd-proposal#post-2335</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 13:20:28 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>robbin_g</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2335@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Hello to all and I am very thankful to find this forum!&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I am wanting to attend a PhD program in Digital Humanities. (Eyes on King's College) I am struggling to write a proper research proposal to find an advisor there. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I am a technologist (not a programmer!) interested in how DH can be used in Food Studies. When I proposed this as an introduction I was told, that's really just a project, not a research question. Turns out, as a technologist, I am great at coming up with digital projects that involve food studies but they all seem to lack a research 'hook' to get me any further. &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;My current favorite idea, of a few scribbled down, is related to the study of wine (I am a certified sommelier):&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;What can a digital humanities approach to wine reveal about the definition of terroir in the region of Barolo, Italy?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Can anyone point me in a good direction? Thank you!
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Sean O&#039;Brien on "What are some useful tools for creating timelines?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/what-are-some-useful-tools-for-creating-timelines#post-261</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2010 10:52:09 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Sean O&#039;Brien</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">261@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I want to give my students a range of options for tools that will help construct detailed timelines online and/or in printable documents.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>bender on "Has anybody used Office ACCESS or FilemakerPro for artworks?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/has-anybody-used-office-access-or-filemakerpro-for-artworks#post-2342</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2015 11:22:50 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>bender</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2342@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Neither Office ACCESS nor FilemakerPro have templates for collection management of artworks, though there are many products available on the WEB for commercial art galleries. I have been using such a commercial product for my digital collection of 30,000 works. However, it is no longer supported and I look out for an appropriate replacement for off-line desktop use.&#60;br /&#62;
I assume many research art historians have spent lots of time and energy to design and build up relational database management systems, never made available to others.&#60;br /&#62;
I would like to hear about their experiences or failures with ACCESS, FileMakerPro or other similar readily available software.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>John Handel on "How to Convert PDF&#039;s to Plain Text"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/how-to-convert-pdfs-to-plain-text#post-2211</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2014 15:22:25 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>John Handel</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2211@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I'm trying to create a corpus of texts to use for various data mining ends but can only access the texts in pdf form. I have 21  pdfs that range from 250-600 pages, most are within the 400-500 page range. I've tried online converters and they are not able to handle the process. Does anyone have a way of doing this?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>alyson.musser on "DH Thesaurus - Participate in an Evaluation Survey"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/dh-thesaurus-participate-in-an-evaluation-survey#post-2322</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 14:09:09 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>alyson.musser</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2322@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Hi all, I'm looking for researchers/enthusiasts of the digital humanities to participate in a survey evaluating a digital humanities thesaurus.  &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;The survey is here: &#60;a href=&#34;http://goo.gl/forms/DyKllxSLMC&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://goo.gl/forms/DyKllxSLMC&#60;/a&#62;  and the thesaurus is here: &#60;a href=&#34;http://dhthesaurus.com/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&#62;http://dhthesaurus.com/&#60;/a&#62; &#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;The survey should only take about 15-20 minutes and I would greatly value your input and feedback. If you leave your email at the end of the survey, you'll be entered in a drawing to win a $5 Starbuck gift card. Thanks!
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Hayim on "Experience with CollateX as restful service?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/experience-with-collatex-as-restful-service#post-2321</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 13:58:47 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Hayim</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2321@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;Does anyone have experience setting up the collation software CollateX (collatex.net) as a restful service? I am a total novice, with little support right now and would like to set it up as a restful service running in Apache Tomcat. (I am familiar with Eclipse and the basics of mounting a java application in Apache Tomcat,and I can work at the command line.) Could someone point out basic guidance or a setup or war that can be cloned?&#60;br /&#62;
Many thanks, HL
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>Miriam Posner on "What are people using to manage large collections of images?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/what-are-people-using-to-manage-large-collections-of-images#post-2307</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 19:05:22 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Miriam Posner</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2307@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I'm curious to know what software humanities scholars are using to wrangle large collections of images. I often encounter scholars who struggle to manage large image collections — it's not at all unusual to find people managing collections of historical images with iPhoto — and wondered if there are databases that make sense for visual collections. I'm especially interested in programs that:&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;ul&#62;
&#60;li&#62;work out of the box and have a GUI (sorry)&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;are designed for individuals, not enterprises&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;allow a scholar to quickly apprehend many images at once&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;allow one to add metadata (like place and date) — something beyond tags would be nice — and construct queries&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;make sense for people who have a lot of digital surrogates of primary sources (which is to say, systems that are optimized to retrieve the EXIF data from a photo of an archival document won't make a whole lot of sense)&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;/ul&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I know about Picasa, LightRoom, and ImagePlot. I don't think an enterprise-level system like ContenDM or the like makes sense for individual scholars. Omeka, of course, is nice, but it's a bit unwieldy if you're just trying to manage a collection. What am I missing?
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>hopegreenberg on "Recommend a web hosting service"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/recommend-a-web-hosting-service#post-2300</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2015 11:06:17 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>hopegreenberg</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2300@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I've always used University resources for web hosting (web site, Wordpress blog, Omeka, dSpace, etc.) but now I have some personal research to post so I would like to start building my own space outside the University. So, here is the usual,frequently asked, difficultly broad question: can anyone recommend a web hosting service? I see BlueHost, DreamHost and HostGator talked about but would like pros and cons of those and others. Any new hosts making a splash? Any you have dealt with in the past that were disappointing?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;My requirements are decent service, cheap (under $10/month if possible), domain name, lots of space (currently have about 3,000 images using 57 GB of space. About half of that is in tifs that I can store elsewhere but this will continue to be a growing image database), and I'll want to install the programs listed above along with whatever may come along. I've installed and run MAMP locally but, as I said, this will be the first time doing this out in the big world so I'm not even sure which questions to ask about what to look for.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			 
				<title>DigHum Student on "Can someone point me to a list of web services that I could deploy on a service?"</title>
						<link>http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/topic/can-someone-point-me-to-a-list-of-web-services-that-i-could-deploy-on-a-service#post-2295</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 15:48:05 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>DigHum Student</dc:creator>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">2295@http://digitalhumanities.org/answers/</guid>
			<description>&#60;p&#62;I need to deploy a web service for an assignment but I am finding it hard to find examples which are relevant to Digital Humanities. If anyone could give me some examples or point me to a list if such exists that would be great. Thanks.
&#60;/p&#62;</description>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
